<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41403180</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6971</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in pulmonary medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of e-cigarettes and flavoured vapes on respiratory health: where are we now?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCP.0000000000001241</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The use of electronic cigarettes (e-cigarettes) for delivering nicotine has increased markedly in recent years, raising concerns regarding their long-term safety and their potential to sustain nicotine dependence, particularly among adolescents and young adults. Marketed as safer alternatives to conventional cigarettes, e-cigarettes warrant careful evaluation of both their short-term and long-term health risks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Evidence from systematic reviews suggests that e-cigarettes may serve as a tool for smoking reduction or cessation; however, available data indicate that usage often represents product switching rather than complete cessation. Given that e-cigarettes are not harmless, the advisability of recommending them as a smoking cessation aid remains controversial. Although long-term outcomes are not fully established, current research suggests that e-cigarettes could be responsible for acute lung injury, exacerbations of respiratory symptoms, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease progression, and various pathophysiological changes associated with cytotoxicity and airway dysfunction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Considering the accumulating evidence of harm, e-cigarettes should be regulated similarly to conventional tobacco products, with strict restrictions on access for children and adolescents. Further longitudinal studies are needed to clarify their long-term health effects and to guide evidence-based public health policies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Omcikus</LastName><ForeName>Maja</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic for Pulmonary Diseases, University Clinical Center of Serbia, Medical School, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tashkin</LastName><ForeName>Donald P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, David Geffen School of Medicine at UCLA, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dimic-Janjic</LastName><ForeName>Sanja</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic for Pulmonary Diseases, University Clinical Center of Serbia, Medical School, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barjaktarevic</LastName><ForeName>Igor</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, David Geffen School of Medicine at UCLA, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pulm Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9503765</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1070-5287</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">e-cigarettes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smoking cessation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41403180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCP.0000000000001241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00063198-990000000-00296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Doll R, Peto R, Boreham J, et al. Mortality in relation to smoking: 50 years&#x2019; observations on male British doctors. BMJ 2004; 328:1519&#x2013;1528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO global report on trends in prevalence of tobacco use 2000&#x2013;2024 and projections 2025&#x2013;2030. Sixth edition. October 6th 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai X, Gakidou E, Lopez AD. Evolution of the global smoking epidemic over the past half century: strengthening the evidence base for policy action. Tobacco Control 2022; 31:129&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birdsey J, Cornelius M, Jamal A, et al. Tobacco product use among U.S middle and high school students - National Youth Tobacco Survey. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2023; 72:1173&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine; Health and Medicine Division; Board on Population Health and Public Health Practice; Committee on the Review of the Health Effects of Electronic Nicotine Delivery Systems. Public Health Consequences of E-Cigarettes. Eaton DL, Kwan LY, Stratton K, editors. Washington, DC: National Academies Press (US); 2018. PMID: 29894118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alteri R, Baptiste D, Butler Bell E, et al. Cancer prevention and early detection facts and figures. American Cancer Society Practice Guidelines 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins BNFL, Normando AGC, Rodrigues-Fernandes CI, et al. Global frequency and epidemiological profile of electronic cigarette users: a systematic review. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol 2022; 134:548&#x2013;561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapru S, Vardhan M, Li Q, et al. E-cigarettes use in the United States: reasons for use, perceptions, and effects on health. BMC Public Health 2020; 20:1518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindson N, Butler AR, McRobbie H, et al. Electronic cigarettes for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2025; 1:CD010216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtney RJ, Howard BC, Barker D, et al. Vaporized nicotine products for smoking cessation among people experiencing social disadvantage: a randomized clinical trial. Ann Intern Med 2025; 178:1085&#x2013;1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes JR, Peters EN, Naud S. Relapse to smoking after 1&#x200a;year of abstinence: a meta-analysis. Addict Behav 2008; 33:1516&#x2013;1520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajek P, Phillips-Waller A, Przulj D, et al. A randomized trial of e-cigarettes versus nicotine-replacement therapy. N Engl J Med 2019; 380:629&#x2013;637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auer R, H&#xe9;ritier F, Bovet P, et al. Electronic nicotine-delivery systems for smoking cessation. N Engl J Med 2024; 390:1201&#x2013;1213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam S, Patel PN. Varenicline: a selective alpha4beta2 nicotinic acetylcholine receptor partial agonist approved for smoking cessation. Cardiol Rev 2007; 15:154&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuisku A, Rahkola M, Nieminen P, Toljamo T. Electronic cigarettes vs. varenicline for smoking cessation in adults: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med 2024; 184:915&#x2013;921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashkin DP, Amin AN, Kerwin EM. Comparing randomized controlled trials and real-world studies in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Int J COPD 2020; 15:1225&#x2013;1243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson SE, Kock L, Kotz D, et al. Real-world effectiveness of smoking cessation aids: a population survey in England with 12-month follow-up. Addict Behav 2022; 135:107442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins SL, Thrul J, Max W, et al. Real-world effectiveness of smoking cessation strategies for young and older adults: findings from a nationally representative cohort. Nicotine Tob Res 2020; 22:1560&#x2013;1568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson SE, Brown J, Shahab L, et al. Use, perceptions, and effectiveness of e-cigarettes for smoking cessation among older adults in England: a population study, 2014-2024. BMC Med 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalkhoran S. E-cigarettes and smoking cessation in real-world and clinical settings: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Respir Med 2016; 4:116&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leone FT, Zhang Y, Evers-Casey S, et al. Initiating pharmacologic treatment in tobacco-dependent adults: an official American Thoracic Society clinical practice guideline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2020; 202:e5&#x2013;e31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DTH, Grigg J, Filippidis FT. Tobacco Control Committee of the European Respiratory Society. European Respiratory Society statement on novel nicotine and tobacco products, their role in tobacco control and &#x201c;harm reduction&#x201d;. Eur Respir J 2024; 63:2301808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Thoracic Society. Position statement: tobacco and vaping. London: BTS; 2024. https://www.brit-thoracic.org.uk/document-library/governance-and-policy-documents/position-statements/position-statement-tobacco-and-vaping-2024/. [Accessed 11 November 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Thoracic Society. Position statement: tobacco and smoking. London: BTS; 2021. https://www.brit-thoracic.org.uk/document-library/governance-and-policy-documents/position-statements/tobacco-and-smoking-march-2020/. [Accessed 11 November 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Effects of tobacco on health. https://www.who.int/europe/news-room/fact-sheets/item/effects-of-tobacco-on-health. [Accessed 6 November 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Cancer Society. Carcinogens found in tobacco products. https://www.cancer.org/cancer/risk-prevention/tobacco/carcinogens-found-in-tobacco-products.html [Accessed 6 November 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster JA. Consideration of vaping products as an alternative to adult smoking: a narrative review. Subst Abuse Treat Prev Policy 2023; 18:67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis N, Knoll M, Cook S, et al. Chemical profiles and toxicity of electronic cigarettes: an umbrella review and methodological considerations. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2023; 20:1908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heywood J, Abele G, Langenbach B, et al. Composition of e-cigarette aerosols: a review and risk assessment of selected compounds. J Appl Toxicol 2025; 45:364&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghuman A, Choudhary P, Kasana J, et al. A systematic literature review on the composition, health impacts, and regulatory dynamics of vaping. Cureus 2024; 16:e66068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercier C, Pourchez J, Leclerc L, et al. In vitro toxicological evaluation of aerosols generated by a 4th generation vaping device using nicotine salts in an air-liquid interface system. Respir Res 2024; 25:75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benowitz NL. Nicotine addiction. N Engl J Med 2010; 362:2295&#x2013;2303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benowitz NL, Burbank AD. Cardiovascular toxicity of nicotine: implications for electronic cigarette use. Trends Cardiovasc Med 2016; 26:515&#x2013;523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price LR, Martinez J. Cardiovascular, carcinogenic and reproductive effects of nicotine exposure: a narrative review of the scientific literature. Regul Toxicol Pharmacol 2020; 113:104636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD): fact sheet. Geneva: WHO; November 6, 2024. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/chronic-obstructive-pulmonary-disease-copd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Health effects of cigarettes: chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). Atlanta (GA): CDC; 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/tobacco/about/cigarettes-and-copd.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and Prevention. Health effects of cigarettes: cancer. Atlanta (GA): CDC; 2023. https://www.cdc.gov/tobacco/about/cigarettes-and-cancer.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Cancer Society. Health risks of smoking tobacco. Atlanta (GA): ACS; 2024. https://www.cancer.org/cancer/risk-prevention/tobacco/health-risks-of-smoking-tobacco.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toledo EFV, Sim&#xf5;es IF, Farias MTd, et al. A comprehensive review of the harmful compounds in electronic cigarettes. Toxics 2025; 13:268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goniewicz ML, Knysak J, Gawron M, et al. Levels of selected carcinogens and toxicants in vapour from electronic cigarettes. Tob Control 2014; 23:133&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil C, Chahine JB, Haykal T, et al. E-Cigarette aerosol induced cytotoxicity, DNA damages and late apoptosis in dynamically exposed A549 cells. Chemosphere 2021; 263:127874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapiamba KF, Chuang HY, Hao W, et al. Evaluating the toxicity of electronic cigarette aerosols for firsthand and secondhand exposure under different device operating conditions. Chem Res Toxicol 2025; 38:1344&#x2013;1356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go YY, Mun JY, Chae SW, et al. Comparison between in vitro toxicities of tobacco- and menthol-flavored electronic cigarette liquids on human middle ear epithelial cells. Sci Rep 2020; 10:2544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guraka A, Mierlea S, Drake SJ, et al. A comprehensive toxicological analysis of panel of unregulated e-cigarettes to human health. Toxicol 2024; 509:153964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose JJ, Krishnan-Sarin S, Exil VJ, et al. Cardiopulmonary impact of electronic cigarettes and vaping products: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation 2023; 148:703&#x2013;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platel A, Dusautoir R, Kervoaze G, et al. Comparison of the in vivo genotoxicity of electronic and conventional cigarette aerosols after subacute, subchronic and chronic exposures. J Hazard Mater 2022; 423:127246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhor M, Tulpar E, Nguyen T, et al. E-cigarette aerosol condensate leads to impaired coronary endothelial cell health and restricted angiogenesis. Int J Mol Sci 2023; 24:6378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wold LE, Tarran R, Crotty Alexander LE, et al. Cardiopulmonary consequences of vaping in adolescents: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circ Res 2022; 131:e70&#x2013;e82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tattersall MC, Hughey CM, Piasecki TM, et al. Cardiovascular and pulmonary responses to acute use of electronic nicotine delivery systems and combustible cigarettes in long-term users. Chest 2023; 164:757&#x2013;769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agusti A, Celli BR, Criner G, et al. Global strategy for prevention, diagnosis and management of COPD: 2025 report. Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung S, Baumlin N, Dennis JS, et al. Electronic cigarette vapor with nicotine causes airway mucociliary dysfunction preferentially via TRPA1 receptors. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2019; 200:1134&#x2013;1145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez DH, Kang EM, Nguyen EN, et al. Inhalation of electrophilic and redox active electronic cigarette aerosol increases oxidative potential in the lung in an acute manner. Free Radic Biol Med 2025; 241:707&#x2013;716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allbright K, Villandre J, Crotty Alexander LE, et al. The paradox of the safer cigarette: understanding the pulmonary effects of electronic cigarettes. Eur Respir J 2024; 63:2301494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maspero J, Adir Y, Al-Ahmad M, et al. Type 2 inflammation in asthma and other airway diseases. ERJ Open Res 2022; 8:00576&#x2013;2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaborators GCRD. Global burden of chronic respiratory diseases and risk factors, 1990&#x2013;2019: an update from the Global Burden of Disease Study. EClinicalMedicine 2023; 59:101936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat TA, Panzica L, Kalathil SG, et al. Immune dysfunction in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2015; 12 (Suppl 2):S169&#x2013;S175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albano GD, Gagliardo RP, Montalbano AM, et al. Overview of the mechanisms of oxidative stress: impact in inflammation of the airway diseases. Antioxidants (Basel) 2022; 11:2237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Wang L, Mutlu GM, et al. More to explore: further definition of risk factors for COPD - differential gender difference, modest elevation in PM2.5, and e-cigarette use. Front Physiol 2021; 12:669152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowler RP, Hansel NN, Jacobson S, et al. Electronic cigarette use in US adults at risk for or with COPD: analysis from two observational cohorts. J Gen Intern Med 2017; 32:1315&#x2013;1322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Arcos I, Geraghty P, Baumlin N, et al. Chronic electronic cigarette exposure in mice induces features of COPD in a nicotine-dependent manner. Thorax 2016; 71:1119&#x2013;1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wawryk-Gawda E, Chyli&#x144;ska-Wrzos P, Zarobkiewicz MK, et al. Lung histomorphological alterations in rats exposed to cigarette smoke and electronic cigarette vapour. Exp Ther Med 2020; 19:2826&#x2013;2832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns AJ, Steinberg AW, Sargent JD, et al. Association of e-cigarette and cigarette use with self-reported chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD): a multivariable analysis of a large United States data set. Respir Res 2025; 26:49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bircan E, Bezirhan U, Porter A, et al. Electronic cigarette use and its association with asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and asthma-COPD overlap syndrome among never cigarette smokers. Tob Induc Dis 2021; 19:75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabil M, Malvi A, Khatib MN, et al. Association of electronic cigarette use and risk of COPD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. NPJ Prim Care Respir Med 2025; 35:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osei AD, Mirbolouk M, Orimoloye OA, et al. The association between e-cigarette use and asthma among never combustible cigarette smokers: behavioural risk factor surveillance system (BRFSS) 2016 &amp;. BMC Pulm Med 2019; 19:180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chand BR, Hosseinzadeh H. Association between e-cigarette use and asthma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Asthma 2022; 59:1722&#x2013;1731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Zhang Y, Zhang R, et al. Association between e-cigarettes and asthma in adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Prev Med 2022; 62:953&#x2013;960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotoulas SC, Pataka A, Domvri K, et al. Acute effects of e-cigarette vaping on pulmonary function and airway inflammation in healthy individuals and in patients with asthma. Respirology 2020; 25:1037&#x2013;1045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel A, Cook S, Mattingly DT, et al. Longitudinal association between exclusive and dual use of cigarettes and electronic nicotine delivery systems and asthma among U.S. adolescents. J Adolesc Health 2023; 73:437&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez A, Valencia S, Jani PP, Harrell MB. Use of electronic nicotine delivery systems and age of asthma onset among US adults and youths. JAMA Netw Open 2024; 7:e2410740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi D, Duong M, Kirkland S, et al. Impact of electronic cigarette ever use on lung function in adults aged 45-85: a cross-sectional analysis from the Canadian Longitudinal Study on Aging. BMJ Open 2021; 11:e051519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selya A, La Rosa GRM, Spicuzza L, et al. Association between electronic cigarette use and respiratory outcomes among people with no established smoking history: a comprehensive review and critical appraisal. Intern Emerg Med 2025; 20:667&#x2013;680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caci G, Selya A, La Rosa GRM, et al. Respiratory effects of electronic cigarette use in individuals who never smoked: a systematic review. Clin Med (Lond) 2025; 25:100295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YW, Park EJ, Kwak KI, et al. Association of electronic cigarette use after conventional smoking cessation with lung cancer risk: a nationwide cohort study [abstract.]. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2024; 209:A3051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittoni MA, Carbone DP, Harris RE. Vaping, smoking and lung cancer risk. J Oncol Res Ther 2024; 9:10229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layden JE, Ghinai I, Pray I, et al. Pulmonary illness related to e-cigarette use in Illinois and Wisconsin - final report. N Engl J Med 2020; 382:903&#x2013; 916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebuli ME, Rose JJ, No&#xeb;l A, et al. The e-cigarette or vaping product use&#x2013;associated lung injury epidemic: pathogenesis, management, and future directions: an official American Thoracic Society Workshop Report. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2023; 20:1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Outbreak of lung injury associated with the use of e-cigarette, or vaping, products. https://www.cdc.gov/tobacco/basic_information/e-cigarettes/severe-lung-disease.html#latest-information.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonas AM, Raj R. Vaping-related acute parenchymal lung injury: a systematic review. Chest 2020; 158:1555&#x2013;1565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aberegg SK, Cirulis MM, Maddock SD, et al. Clinical, bronchoscopic, and imaging findings of e-cigarette, or vaping, product use-associated lung injury among patients treated at an Academic Medical Center. JAMA Netw Open 2020; 3:e2019176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roslly MZ, Syed Rozhan SAA. E-cigarette or vaping &#x2013;associated lung injury. N Engl J Med 2025; 393:592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner AK, Koumans EH, Chatham-Stephens K, et al. Hospitalizations and deaths associated with EVALI. N Engl J Med 2020; 382:1589&#x2013;1598.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41399072</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1671-167X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Beijing da xue xue bao. Yi xue ban = Journal of Peking University. Health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Beijing Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Clinical characteristics, efficacy and safety of antifibrotic agents in elderly patients with connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1101</StartPage><EndPage>1106</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1101-1106</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the clinical characteristics, treatment regimens, and the efficacy and safety of antifibrotic agents in elderly patients with connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease (CTD-ILD).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This single-center retrospective cohort study enrolled 129 elderly patients (&#x2265;60 years) with a confirmed diagnosis of CTD-ILD at Beijing Hospital from June 2016 to June 2024. Baseline data, including comorbidities and CTD subtypes, treatment regimens (glucocorticoids, immunosuppressants, antifibrotic agents), pulmonary function parameters, high-resolution computed tomography (HRCT) imaging features, and adverse events were retrieved from the electronic medical record system. Treatment efficacy was evaluated according to the 2022 American Thoracic Society/European Respiratory Society criteria for progressive pulmonary fibrosis. Statistical analyses were performed using SPSS 26.0, with <i>&#x3c7;</i><sup>2</sup> tests or <i>t</i>-tests applied for between-group comparisons.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">(1) Clinical characteristics: The predominant CTD subtypes were rheumatoid arthritis (RA), primary Sj&#xf6;gren syndrome (pSS), and polymyositis or dermatomyositis (PM/DM). Hypertension was present in 45.7% of the patients, reflecting the characteristics of multiple comorbidities in the elderly population. (2) CTD treatment regimens: 76.0% of the patients received glucocorticoid therapy, 83.7% used immunosuppressants (IS)/conventional synthetic disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs (csDMARDs), among which cyclophosphamide had the highest usage rate (47.3%); 31.8% of the patients were combined with antifibrotic drugs (nintedanib 16.3%, pirfenidone 10.1%, and 5.4% used both). (3) Efficacy of antifibrotic therapy: There was no statistically significant difference in the 6-month HRCT progression rate between the antifibrotic and non-antifibrotic groups (31.3% <i>vs</i>. 45.2%, <i>P</i>=0.193). However, the proportion of the patients with pulmonary function deterioration in the antifibrotic group was significantly lower than that in the non-antifibrotic group (34.1% <i>vs</i>. 53.4%, <i>P</i>=0.041), suggesting a potential role in delaying pulmonary function deterioration. (4) Safety of antifibrotic agents: Gastrointestinal adverse events occurred in 39.0% of the patients receiving antifibrotics (26.8% diarrhea, 22.0% nausea), and abnormal liver function was observed in 17.1%. (5) Long-term outcomes: During a 2-year follow-up, 67.4% of the patients experienced infections (47.3% pulmonary infections), 14.0% progressed to respiratory failure, and the all-cause mortality rate was 2.3%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The main subtypes of CTD-ILD in the elderly are RA, pSS, and PM/DM, which are often complicated with hypertension. Antifibrotic agents may significantly delay the deterioration of pulmonary function, but attention should be paid to the risks of gastrointestinal adverse effects and hepatotoxicity. Infection remains the primary complication, emphasizing the need to balance benefits of immunosuppressive therapy and the risk of infection to formulate treatment strategies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lan</LastName><ForeName>Jingwen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Beijing Hospital; National Center of Gerontology; Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing 100730, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Beijing Hospital; National Center of Gerontology; Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing 100730, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Yongjing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Beijing Hospital; National Center of Gerontology; Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing 100730, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Like</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Beijing Hospital; National Center of Gerontology; Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing 100730, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>chi</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Beijing Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101125284</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1671-167X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000088962">Antifibrotic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007166">Immunosuppressive Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>G6HRD2P839</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C530716">nintedanib</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>D7NLD2JX7U</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C093844">pirfenidone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011728">Pyridones</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007211">Indoles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005938">Glucocorticoids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017563" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Diseases, Interstitial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003240" MajorTopicYN="Y">Connective Tissue Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000088962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antifibrotic Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007166" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunosuppressive Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011728" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyridones</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007211" MajorTopicYN="N">Indoles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005938" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucocorticoids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014057" MajorTopicYN="N">Tomography, X-Ray Computed</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antifibrotic agents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41399072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41399061</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1671-167X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Beijing da xue xue bao. Yi xue ban = Journal of Peking University. Health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Beijing Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Rheumatic disease spectrum and immunological profile of anti-PM/Scl antibodies in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1018</StartPage><EndPage>1023</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1018-1023</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To systematically investigate the rheumatic disease spectrum associated with anti-PM/Scl antibodies and to clarify their clinical significance in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies (IIM).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients who were tested positive for anti-PM/Scl antibodies by immunoblotting at Peking University People' s Hospital from January 2016 to December 2024 were enrolled. Clinical and immunolo gical data were systematically collected and compared across the subgroups defined by anti-PM/Scl75, anti-PM/Scl100, or dual antibody positivity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 422 anti-PM/Scl-positive patients were enrolled. Among them, 83.2% (351/422) were diagnosed with connective tissue disease (CTD), 7.8% (33/422) were not diagnosed with CTD, and 9.0% (38/422) had an undetermined clinical diagnosis. Among 422 patients, most commonly represented by IIM (19.7%), systemic sclerosis (SSc, 14.2%), overlap syndrome (11.8%), undifferentiated CTD (UCTD, 10.4%), rheumatoid arthritis (6.9%), Sj&#xf6;gren syndrome (6.4%), and systemic lupus erythematosus (6.2%), the remaining diseases accounting for 24.4%. Within the IIM subgroup, dermatomyositis predominated (74.7%), followed next by anti-synthetase syndrome (21.7%) and immune-mediated necrotizing myopathy (3.6%). Anti-PM/Scl75 antibodies were detected in 52.1% (220/422) of the total patients, anti-PM/Scl100 in 43.6% (184/422), and both in 4.3% (18/422). In the subsequent detailed analysis of the anti-PM/ Scl-positive subgroup, double-positive patients showed a significantly higher prevalence of SSc (38.9% <i>vs</i>. 14.1% <i>vs</i>. 12.0%, <i>P</i>=0.015) and interstitial lung disease (ILD, 70.6% <i>vs</i>. 28.8% <i>vs</i>. 35.4%, <i>P</i>=0.002) than those individuals with single antibody positivity alone. Raynaud phenomenon was observed more frequently in both the double-positive and anti-PM/Scl75-positive groups than in the anti-PM/Scl100-positive group (29.4% <i>vs</i>. 21.3% <i>vs</i>. 10.9%, <i>P</i>=0.007). The measured proportion of peri-pheral CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells was also higher in double-positive patients (35.9%&#xb1;14.1% <i>vs</i>. 30.4%&#xb1;11.2% <i>vs</i>. 26.5%&#xb1;9.7%, <i>P</i>= 0.008), whereas absolute regulatory T-cell levels were lower in the anti-PM/Scl75-positive group compared directly with the anti-PM/Scl100-positive group [7.6% (5.4%, 10.9%) <i>vs</i>. 9.0% (7.9%, 12.0%) <i>vs</i>. 8.8% (5.2%, 9.7%), <i>P=</i>0.017]. Additionally, co-positivity for anti-PM/Scl and other myositis- specific or myositis-associated antibodies was strongly associated with an increased frequency of ILD (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Anti-PM/Scl antibodies define a broad disease spectrum encompassing IIM, SSc, overlap syndromes, and UCTD. Dual positivity for anti-PM/Scl75 and anti-PM/Scl100 identifies patients prone to systemic sclerosis and pulmonary involvement, suggesting additive pathogenic effects of the two antibody specificities.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lian</LastName><ForeName>Yirui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People' s Hospital, Beijing 1000444, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jingxuan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People' s Hospital Qingdao Hospital, Qingdao 266000, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People' s Hospital, Beijing 1000444, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People' s Hospital, Beijing 1000444, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zang</LastName><ForeName>Sitian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People' s Hospital, Beijing 1000444, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yuhui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People' s Hospital, Beijing 1000444, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People' s Hospital Qingdao Hospital, Qingdao 266000, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>chi</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Beijing Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101125284</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1671-167X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009220" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myositis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rheumatic Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003240" MajorTopicYN="N">Connective Tissue Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012595" MajorTopicYN="N">Scleroderma, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-PM/Scl antibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CD8+ T cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Connective tissue disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Idiopathic inflammatory myopathy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41399061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41378083</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2950-3299</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular therapy. Oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Ther Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Akt inhibition enhances the antitumor efficacy of immune checkpoint blockades and radiotherapy in a syngeneic breast cancer model.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>201087</StartPage><MedlinePgn>201087</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">201087</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201087</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Immune checkpoint blockades (ICBs) have limited efficacy against immunologically cold breast cancers. Although radiotherapy (RT) can potentiate antitumor immunity, many patients fail to benefit, partly due to activation of immunosuppressive cells. Given the ability of PI3K inhibition to regulate immunosuppressive repertoires, we hypothesized that inhibition of Akt, a key effector of PI3K, could enhance the efficacy of RT and ICBs. In this study, we investigated antitumor effects and immune cell phenotypes in 4T1 syngeneic triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) models treated with RT, ICBs, and an Akt inhibitor. RT + &#x3b1;PD-L1 + Akt inhibitor most reduced tumor size and lung metastases. The Akt inhibitor increased the M1/M2 macrophage ratio and the proportion of CD86<sup>+</sup> dendritic cells (DCs). Interestingly, RT + &#x3b1;PD-L1 increased M2 macrophages, while adding the Akt inhibitor partially restored M1/M2 balance. When combined with RT + &#x3b1;PD-L1/&#x3b1;CTLA-4, Akt inhibition further elevated the M1/M2 ratio and CD86<sup>+</sup> DC frequency and reduced monocytic myeloid-derived suppressor cells (M-MDSCs). These findings suggest that addition of an Akt inhibitor to RT and ICBs leads to a less immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment by modulating myeloid cells. Taken together, Akt inhibition could be a viable strategy to overcome therapeutic resistance of ICBs and RT in breast cancer.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Nawon</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Tumor Biology and Cancer Research Institute, Graduate School of Medicine, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Science Research Institute, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeon</LastName><ForeName>Seung Hyuck</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Yoomin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Tumor Biology and Cancer Research Institute, Graduate School of Medicine, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Science Research Institute, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Seongmin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Tumor Biology and Cancer Research Institute, Graduate School of Medicine, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Science Research Institute, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Major in Innovative Medical Science, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>In Ah</ForeName><Initials>IA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Tumor Biology and Cancer Research Institute, Graduate School of Medicine, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Science Research Institute, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Major in Innovative Medical Science, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Ther Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918752083706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2950-3299</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Akt inhibition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MT: Regular Issue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PD-L1 blockade</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combination immunotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immune checkpoint blockade</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiation therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">triple-negative breast cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumor-infiltrating myeloid cells</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>I.A.K. received research support from AstraZeneca in the form of study drugs (capivasertib, &#x3b1;-PD-L1, and &#x3b1;-CTLA-4 antibodies) used in this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41378083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12686700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2950-3299(25)00156-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Braun D.A., Burke K.P., Van Allen E.M. Genomic Approaches to Understanding Response and Resistance to Immunotherapy. Clin. Cancer Res. 2016;22:5642&#x2013;5650. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-16-0066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-16-0066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5135569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27698000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna A., Balko J.M. Breast cancer resistance mechanisms: challenges to immunotherapy. Breast Cancer Res. Treat. 2021;190:5&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1007/s10549-021-06337-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-021-06337-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8560575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34322780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng J., See A.P., Phallen J., Jackson C.M., Belcaid Z., Ruzevick J., Durham N., Meyer C., Harris T.J., Albesiano E., et al. Anti-PD-1 blockade and stereotactic radiation produce long-term survival in mice with intracranial gliomas. Int. J. Radiat. Oncol. Biol. Phys. 2013;86:343&#x2013;349. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrobp.2012.12.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrobp.2012.12.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23462419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dovedi S.J., Adlard A.L., Lipowska-Bhalla G., McKenna C., Jones S., Cheadle E.J., Stratford I.J., Poon E., Morrow M., Stewart R., et al. Acquired resistance to fractionated radiotherapy can be overcome by concurrent PD-L1 blockade. Cancer Res. 2014;74:5458&#x2013;5468. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.Can-14-1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.Can-14-1258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25274032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong X., Li X., Jiang T., Xie H., Zhu Z., Zhou F., Zhou C. Combined Radiotherapy and Anti-PD-L1 Antibody Synergistically Enhances Antitumor Effect in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer. J. Thorac. Oncol. 2017;12:1085&#x2013;1097. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2017.04.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2017.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28478231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theelen W.S.M.E., Chen D., Verma V., Hobbs B.P., Peulen H.M.U., Aerts J.G.J.V., Bahce I., Niemeijer A.L.N., Chang J.Y., de Groot P.M., et al. Pembrolizumab with or without radiotherapy for metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer: a pooled analysis of two randomised trials. Lancet Respir. Med. 2021;9:467&#x2013;475. doi: 10.1016/s2213-2600(20)30391-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s2213-2600(20)30391-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33096027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkari L., Bowman R.L., Tessier J., Klemm F., Handgraaf S.M., de Groot M., Quail D.F., Tillard L., Gadiot J., Huse J.T., et al. Dynamic changes in glioma macrophage populations after radiotherapy reveal CSF-1R inhibition as a strategy to overcome resistance. Sci. Transl. Med. 2020;12 doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.aaw7843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.aaw7843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian B.Z., Pollard J.W. Macrophage diversity enhances tumor progression and metastasis. Cell. 2010;141:39&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2010.03.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2010.03.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4994190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20371344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Wang J., Chen Z., Luo J., Guo W., Sun L., Lin L. Targeting M2-like tumor-associated macrophages is a potential therapeutic approach to overcome antitumor drug resistance. npj Precis. Oncol. 2024;8:31. doi: 10.1038/s41698-024-00522-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41698-024-00522-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10858952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38341519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sica A., Mantovani A. Macrophage plasticity and polarization: in vivo veritas. J. Clin. Investig. 2012;122:787&#x2013;795. doi: 10.1172/jci59643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci59643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3287223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22378047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehne N., Mora J., Namgaladze D., Weigert A., Br&#xfc;ne B. Cancer cell and macrophage cross-talk in the tumor microenvironment. Curr. Opin. Pharmacol. 2017;35:12&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1016/j.coph.2017.04.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coph.2017.04.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sica A., Schioppa T., Mantovani A., Allavena P. Tumour-associated macrophages are a distinct M2 polarised population promoting tumour progression: potential targets of anti-cancer therapy. Eur. J. Cancer. 2006;42:717&#x2013;727. doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2006.01.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2006.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16520032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S.U., Khan M.U., Azhar Ud Din M., Khan I.M., Khan M.I., Bungau S., Hassan S.S.U. Reprogramming tumor-associated macrophages as a unique approach to target tumor immunotherapy. Front. Immunol. 2023;14 doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1166487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1166487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10149956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37138860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Dong Y., Li Y., Wang D., Liu S., Wang D., Gao Q., Ji S., Chen X., Lei Q., et al. IL-10 derived from M2 macrophage promotes cancer stemness via JAK1/STAT1/NF-&#x3ba;B/Notch1 pathway in non-small cell lung cancer. Int. J. Cancer. 2019;145:1099&#x2013;1110. doi: 10.1002/ijc.32151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijc.32151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30671927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.J., Li G.N., Li X.J., Wei L.X., Fu M.J., Cheng Z.L., Yang Z., Zhu G.Q., Wang X.D., Zhang C., et al. Targeting IRG1 reverses the immunosuppressive function of tumor-associated macrophages and enhances cancer immunotherapy. Sci. Adv. 2023;9 doi: 10.1126/sciadv.adg0654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adg0654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10146892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37115931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y.T., Wang X.R., Yan C., Huang F., Zhang Y., Liu X., Wen Z.F., Sun X.T., Zhang Y., Chen Y.Q., et al. Thymosin &#x3b1;-1 Reverses M2 Polarization of Tumor-Associated Macrophages during Efferocytosis. Cancer Res. 2022;82:1991&#x2013;2002. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.Can-21-4260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.Can-21-4260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35364609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohila D., Park I.H., Pham T.V., Jones R., Tapia E., Liu K.X., Tamayo P., Yu A., Sharabi A.B., Joshi S. Targeting macrophage Syk enhances responses to immune checkpoint blockade and radiotherapy in high-risk neuroblastoma. Front. Immunol. 2023;14 doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1148317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1148317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10283071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37350973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K., Shi H., Zhang B., Ou X., Ma Q., Chen Y., Shu P., Li D., Wang Y. Myeloid-derived suppressor cells as immunosuppressive regulators and therapeutic targets in cancer. Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 2021;6:362. doi: 10.1038/s41392-021-00670-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-021-00670-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34620838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marciscano A.E., Anandasabapathy N. The role of dendritic cells in cancer and anti-tumor immunity. Semin. Immunol. 2021;52 doi: 10.1016/j.smim.2021.101481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smim.2021.101481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8545750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34023170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaviano A., Foo A.S.C., Lam H.Y., Yap K.C.H., Jacot W., Jones R.H., Eng H., Nair M.G., Makvandi P., Geoerger B., et al. PI3K/AKT/mTOR signaling transduction pathway and targeted therapies in cancer. Mol. Cancer. 2023;22:138. doi: 10.1186/s12943-023-01827-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12943-023-01827-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10436543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37596643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paplomata E., O'Regan R. The PI3K/AKT/mTOR pathway in breast cancer: targets, trials and biomarkers. Ther. Adv. Med. Oncol. 2014;6:154&#x2013;166. doi: 10.1177/1758834014530023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1758834014530023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4107712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25057302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim I.A., Bae S.S., Fernandes A., Wu J., Muschel R.J., McKenna W.G., Birnbaum M.J., Bernhard E.J. Selective inhibition of Ras, phosphoinositide 3 kinase, and Akt isoforms increases the radiosensitivity of human carcinoma cell lines. Cancer Res. 2005;65:7902&#x2013;7910. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.Can-05-0513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.Can-05-0513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16140961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks D.K., Gartrell R.D., El Asmar M., Boboila S., Hart T., Lu Y., Pan Q., Yu J., Hibshoosh H., Guo H., et al. Akt Inhibition Is Associated With Favorable Immune Profile Changes Within the Tumor Microenvironment of Hormone Receptor Positive, HER2 Negative Breast Cancer. Front. Oncol. 2020;10:968. doi: 10.3389/fonc.2020.00968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2020.00968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7308467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32612958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneda M.M., Messer K.S., Ralainirina N., Li H., Leem C.J., Gorjestani S., Woo G., Nguyen A.V., Figueiredo C.C., Foubert P., et al. PI3K&#x3b3; is a molecular switch that controls immune suppression. Nature. 2016;539:437&#x2013;442. doi: 10.1038/nature19834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature19834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5479689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27642729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang W.I., Han M.G., Kang M.H., Park J.M., Kim E.E., Bae J., Ahn S., Kim I.A. PI3K&#x3b1;&#x3b4; Inhibitor Combined With Radiation Enhances the Antitumor Immune Effect of Anti-PD1 in a Syngeneic Murine Triple-Negative Breast Cancer Model. Int. J. Radiat. Oncol. Biol. Phys. 2021;110:845&#x2013;858. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrobp.2021.01.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrobp.2021.01.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33642128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han M.G., Jang B.S., Kang M.H., Na D., Kim I.A. PI3K&#x3b3;&#x3b4; inhibitor plus radiation enhances the antitumour immune effect of PD-1 blockade in syngenic murine breast cancer and humanised patient-derived xenograft model. Eur. J. Cancer. 2021;157:450&#x2013;463. doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2021.08.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2021.08.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34601286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covarrubias A.J., Aksoylar H.I., Horng T. Control of macrophage metabolism and activation by mTOR and Akt signaling. Semin. Immunol. 2015;27:286&#x2013;296. doi: 10.1016/j.smim.2015.08.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smim.2015.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4682888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26360589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;ckerl D., Jenkins S.J., Laqtom N.N., Gallagher I.J., Sutherland T.E., Duncan S., Buck A.H., Allen J.E. Induction of IL-4R&#x3b1;-dependent microRNAs identifies PI3K/Akt signaling as essential for IL-4-driven murine macrophage proliferation in vivo. Blood. 2012;120:2307&#x2013;2316. doi: 10.1182/blood-2012-02-408252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2012-02-408252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3501641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22855601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gris-Oliver A., Palafox M., Monserrat L., Bras&#xf3;-Maristany F., &#xd2;dena A., S&#xe1;nchez-Guix&#xe9; M., Ibrahim Y.H., Villacampa G., Grueso J., Par&#xe9;s M., et al. Genetic Alterations in the PI3K/AKT Pathway and Baseline AKT Activity Define AKT Inhibitor Sensitivity in Breast Cancer Patient-derived Xenografts. Clin. Cancer Res. 2020;26:3720&#x2013;3731. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-19-3324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-19-3324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7814659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Wang W., Hu S., Jia B., Tuo B., Sun H., Wang Q., Liu Y., Sun Z. Radiotherapy remodels the tumor microenvironment for enhancing immunotherapeutic sensitivity. Cell Death Dis. 2023;14:679. doi: 10.1038/s41419-023-06211-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41419-023-06211-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10575861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37833255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid P., Adams S., Rugo H.S., Schneeweiss A., Barrios C.H., Iwata H., Di&#xe9;ras V., Hegg R., Im S.A., Shaw Wright G., et al. Atezolizumab and Nab-Paclitaxel in Advanced Triple-Negative Breast Cancer. N. Engl. J. Med. 2018;379:2108&#x2013;2121. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1809615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1809615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30345906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vito A., Salem O., El-Sayes N., MacFawn I.P., Portillo A.L., Milne K., Harrington D., Ashkar A.A., Wan Y., Workenhe S.T., et al. Immune checkpoint blockade in triple negative breast cancer influenced by B cells through myeloid-derived suppressor cells. Commun. Biol. 2021;4:859. doi: 10.1038/s42003-021-02375-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-021-02375-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8275624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34253827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua H., Zhang H., Chen J., Wang J., Liu J., Jiang Y. Targeting Akt in cancer for precision therapy. J. Hematol. Oncol. 2021;14:128. doi: 10.1186/s13045-021-01137-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13045-021-01137-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8379749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34419139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman N., Moyers J.T., Harbery A., Vivanco I., Yap T.A. Clinical Development of AKT Inhibitors and Associated Predictive Biomarkers to Guide Patient Treatment in Cancer Medicine. Pharmgenomics. Pers. Med. 2021;14:1517&#x2013;1535. doi: 10.2147/pgpm.S305068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/pgpm.S305068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8630372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34858045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., He Y., Sun X., Li Q., Wang W., Zhao A., Di W. A high M1/M2 ratio of tumor-associated macrophages is associated with extended survival in ovarian cancer patients. J. Ovarian Res. 2014;7:19. doi: 10.1186/1757-2215-7-19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1757-2215-7-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3939626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24507759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Italiani P., Boraschi D. From Monocytes to M1/M2 Macrophages: Phenotypical vs. Functional Differentiation. Front. Immunol. 2014;5:514. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2014.00514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2014.00514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4201108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25368618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisser S.B., McLarren K.W., Voglmaier N., van Netten-Thomas C.J., Antov A., Flavell R.A., Sly L.M. Alternative activation of macrophages by IL-4 requires SHIP degradation. Eur. J. Immunol. 2011;41:1742&#x2013;1753. doi: 10.1002/eji.201041105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.201041105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21469115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creighton C.J. A gene transcription signature of the Akt/mTOR pathway in clinical breast tumors. Oncogene. 2007;26:4648&#x2013;4655. doi: 10.1038/sj.onc.1210245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.onc.1210245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17213801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez F.O., Gordon S., Locati M., Mantovani A. Transcriptional profiling of the human monocyte-to-macrophage differentiation and polarization: new molecules and patterns of gene expression. J. Immunol. 2006;177:7303&#x2013;7311. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.177.10.7303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.177.10.7303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17082649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41357378</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3230</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of transplantation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Transplant</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Increase in failed swallows from pre- to post-lung transplant esophageal function testing is associated with acute rejection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>107149</StartPage><MedlinePgn>107149</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">107149</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5500/wjt.v15.i4.107149</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The pathophysiology behind gastroesophageal reflux disease and its association with poor outcomes after lung transplantation is incompletely understood. The physiologic impact of lung transplantation on pulmonary function, intrathoracic pressures, and vagal innervation may affect esophageal motility, bolus clearance and reflux risk. However, the effect of changes in esophageal function after lung transplantation on the risk of poor post-transplant outcomes remains unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the association between change in esophageal motility pre-/post-lung transplantation and rejection outcome.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a retrospective cohort study of lung transplant recipients who underwent both pre-and post-transplant esophageal testing including high resolution manometry (HRM) at a tertiary center. Acute cellular rejection (ACR) was defined histologically per International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation criteria. Univariate analyses were performed using student's <i>t</i>-test, <i>&#x3c7;</i> <sup>2</sup> test, and Spearman's correlation where appropriate. Multivariable time-to-event analysis using Cox proportional hazards model was applied. Subjects not meeting ACR outcome were censored at death or date of last clinic visit.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">55 subjects (65% men, mean age: 61, median follow-up: 840 days) were included, with 17 (31%) experiencing ACR. Increase in failed swallows correlated with lower baseline total lung capacity (TLC) (R = -0.32, <i>P</i> = 0.05) and decreased post-transplant esophageal bolus clearance (R = -0.45, <i>P</i> = 0.004). On multivariable analysis, post-transplant hypomotility independently predicted increased ACR (HR: 3.62, 95%CI: 1.11-11.8; <i>P</i> = 0.03). Kaplan-Meier analysis demonstrated increased ACR for subjects with increased <i>vs</i> unchanged failed swallows post-transplant (<i>P</i> = 0.048). On Cox regression, a 20% elevated risk of ACR was found for every 10% increase in failed swallows, after controlling for confounders including reflux severity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Esophageal hypomotility, specifically an increase in failed swallows on HRM, from pre- to post-lung transplantation was independently associated with ACR. Additionally, lower baseline TLC correlated with increase in failed swallows, suggesting restrictive lung disease may be associated with post-transplant esophageal hypomotility. Lung transplantation may affect esophageal function and contribute to rejection outcomes. Routine esophageal function testing may help identify patients at higher risk for poor lung transplantation outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lo</LastName><ForeName>Wai-Kit</ForeName><Initials>WK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Endoscopy, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA 02115, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nadella</LastName><ForeName>Pranay</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA 02115, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feldman</LastName><ForeName>Natan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Endoscopy, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA 02115, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Nirmal</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA 02115, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldberg</LastName><ForeName>Hilary J</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA 02115, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Walter W</ForeName><Initials>WW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Endoscopy, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA 02115, United States. wwchan@bwh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Transplant</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101608356</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-3230</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute rejection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Esophageal dysmotility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Failed swallows</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-resolution manometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ineffective esophageal motility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lung transplantation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41357378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12679242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5500/wjt.v15.i4.107149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lo WK, Moniodis A, Goldberg HJ, Feldman N, Chan WW. Increased Acid Exposure on Pretransplant Impedance-pH Testing Is Associated With Chronic Rejection After Lung Transplantation. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2020;54:517&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32091450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo WK, Burakoff R, Goldberg HJ, Feldman N, Chan WW. Pre-transplant impedance measures of reflux are associated with early allograft injury after lung transplantation. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2015;34:26&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25444368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang CYK, Ahmed M, Huszti E, Levy L, Hunter SE, Boonstra KM, Moshkelgosha S, Sage AT, Azad S, Zamel R, Ghany R, Yeung JC, Crespin OM, Frankel C, Budev M, Shah P, Reynolds JM, Snyder LD, Belperio JA, Singer LG, Weigt SS, Todd JL, Palmer SM, Keshavjee S, Martinu T CTOT-20 investigators. Bronchoalveolar bile acid and inflammatory markers to identify high-risk lung transplant recipients with reflux and microaspiration. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2020;39:934&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32487471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo WK, Hiramoto B, Goldberg HJ, Sharma N, Chan WW. Ineffective esophageal motility is associated with acute rejection after lung transplantation independent of gastroesophageal reflux. World J Gastroenterol. 2023;29:3292&#x2013;3301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10292138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37377592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuda T, Mittal SK, Kov&#xe1;cs B, Smith MA, Walia R, Huang JL, Bremner RM. Foregut function before and after lung transplant. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2019;158:619&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31084982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung R, Lo WK, Sharma NS, Goldberg HJ, Chan WW. Esophageal Function and Reflux Evaluations in Lung Transplantation: A Nationwide Survey of UNOS-Accredited Transplant Centers in the United States. Clin Transl Gastroenterol. 2023;14:e00641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10749699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37747103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larrieu D, Thi&#xe9;baud P, Dupl&#xe0;a C, Sibon I, Th&#xe9;z&#xe9; N, Lamazi&#xe8;re JM. Activation of the Ca(2+)/calcineurin/NFAT2 pathway controls smooth muscle cell differentiation. Exp Cell Res. 2005;310:166&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16129432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bielefeldt K, Sharma RV, Whiteis C, Yedidag E, Abboud FM. Tacrolimus (FK506) modulates calcium release and contractility of intestinal smooth muscle. Cell Calcium. 1997;22:507&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9502200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touchon F, Bermudez J, Habert P, Bregeon F, Thomas PA, Reynaud-Gaubert M, Coiffard B. Change in diaphragmatic morphology in single-lung transplant recipients: a computed tomographic study. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1220463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10562565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37822681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Groote A, Van Muylem A, Scillia P, Cheron G, Verleden G, Paiva M, Estenne M. Ventilation asymmetry after transplantation for emphysema: role of chest wall and mediastinum. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2004;170:1233&#x2013;1238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15333332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curcic J, Roy S, Schwizer A, Kaufman E, Forras-Kaufman Z, Menne D, Hebbard GS, Treier R, Boesiger P, Steingoetter A, Fried M, Schwizer W, Pal A, Fox M. Abnormal structure and function of the esophagogastric junction and proximal stomach in gastroesophageal reflux disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 2014;109:658&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24589669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Hern&#xe1;ndez MA, S&#xe1;nchez-Moreno L, Orizaola P, Iturbe D, &#xc1;lvar&#xe9;z C, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rozas S, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Novoa V, Llorca J, Hern&#xe1;ndez JL, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Torre JL, Parra JA. A prospective evaluation of phrenic nerve injury after lung transplantation: Incidence, risk factors, and analysis of the surgical procedure. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2022;41:50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34756781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferdinande P, Bruyninckx F, Van Raemdonck D, Daenen W, Verleden G Leuven Lung Transplant Group. Phrenic nerve dysfunction after heart-lung and lung transplantation. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2004;23:105&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14734134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haenssgen K, Herrmann G, Draeger A, Essig M, Djonov V. The Contribution of the Left Phrenic Nerve to Innervation of the Esophagogastric Junction. Clin Anat. 2020;33:265&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7027871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31625208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Shi J, Peng G, Yang C, Liu M, Zhao Y, Liang H, Zhong R, Cheng B, Cui W, Wei B, Xiao D, Liang W, Xie S, He J. Non-In Situ Technique of Heart-Lung Transplantation: Case Series and Technique Description. Ann Thorac Surg. 2021;112:661&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucente G, Martinez-Barenys C, Ramos-Fransi A, Almendrote-Mu&#xf1;oz M, L&#xf3;pez de Castro P, Deletis V, Coll-Canti J, Mart&#xed;nez-Pi&#xf1;eiro A. A New Methodology for Intraoperative Monitoring of the Functional Integrity of the Phrenic Nerve During Cardiothoracic Surgery. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;38:226&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah R, Chirnaksorn S, Abdelrahim AH, Horgan L, Capstick T, Casey J, Peckham D, Boland A, Sutherland TJT, Beirne P, Lee AS, DeVault KR, Houghton LA. The Perils and Pitfalls of Esophageal Dysmotility in Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2021;116:1189&#x2013;1200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34074825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghubari A, Cheah R, Z Shah S, Naser AN, Lee AS, DeVault KR, Houghton LA. The impact of lung transplantation on esophageal motility and inter-relationships with reflux and lung mechanics in patients with restrictive and obstructive respiratory disease. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2024;36:e14788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38523356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giulini L, Mittal SK, Masuda T, Razia D, Csucska M, Walia R, Smith MA, Bremner RM. Factors associated with esophageal motility improvement after bilateral lung transplant in patients with an aperistaltic esophagus. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2022;163:1979&#x2013;1986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33568319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu WS, Park CH, Paik HC, Lee JG, You S, Shin J, Jung J, Haam S. Changes in Thoracic Cavity Volume After Bilateral Lung Transplantation. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;9:881119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9204381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35721055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardinello N, Cocconcelli E, Boscolo A, Castelli G, Sella N, Giraudo C, Zanatta E, Rea F, Saetta M, Navalesi P, Spagnolo P, Balestro E. Prevalence of diaphragm dysfunction in patients with interstitial lung disease (ILD): The role of diaphragmatic ultrasound. Respir Med. 2023;216:107293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37271302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41322191</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2950-3299</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular therapy. Oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Ther Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional characterization of tumor-specific CRISPR-directed gene editing as a combinatorial therapy for the treatment of solid tumors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>201079</StartPage><MedlinePgn>201079</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">201079</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201079</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As we pursue clinical applications for CRISPR-directed gene editing in overcoming resistance to anticancer drugs, we have focused on genetic disruption of the transcription factor, NRF2, a master regulator of cellular stress and detoxification. The level of NRF2 in tumor cells is often a clear determinant of the effectiveness of standard of care. We began to craft a therapeutic approach using tumor-specific CRISPR editing, building upon our previous work elucidating the effect of NRF2 knockout. We selected a prevalent mutation, R34G, that occurs in the Neh2 domain of NRF2, which has been shown to disrupt KEAP1-mediated degradation, thus impacting the NRF2-KEAP1 pathway. Here, we take a global approach by assessing the genomic, transcriptomic, proteomic, and phenotypic profile of a CRISPR-targeted population of cells, both <i>in vitro</i> and <i>in vivo</i>. We detail the design and generation of a clinically relevant cell model and its translation into an animal model, characterizing the efficacy of disabling NRF2 concomitant with the restoration of chemosensitivity. We demonstrate that 20%-40% gene editing activity is sufficient to improve response to chemotherapy in animal models. We suggest that understanding the genetic diversity of CRISPR outcomes must be a key consideration in identifying effective CRISPR molecules for clinical application.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banas</LastName><ForeName>Kelly H</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bialk</LastName><ForeName>Pawel A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rivera-Torres</LastName><ForeName>Natalia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owens</LastName><ForeName>Katelynn</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reiner</LastName><ForeName>Tori N</ForeName><Initials>TN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pisarcik</LastName><ForeName>Kristen M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haas</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gielda</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Komal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narra</LastName><ForeName>Krishna Priya</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kmiec</LastName><ForeName>Eric B</ForeName><Initials>EB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gene Editing Institute, ChristianaCare Health System, Newark, DE 19713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Ther Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918752083706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2950-3299</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CRISPR-Cas9</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MT: Regular Issue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NRF2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemosensitivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gene editing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipid nanoparticles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-small cell lung carcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">solid tumors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumor specific</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>E.B.K. is a founder of CorriXR Therapeutics. E.K.B., K.H.B., P.A.B., and N.R.-T hold shares in CorriXR Therapeutics. K.H.B., P.A.B., and E.B.K. have a granted patent for &#x201c;Gene knockout of variant NRF2 for treatment of cancer,&#x201d; US Patent no. 12037581B2.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41322191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12663020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2950-3299(25)00148-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sung H., Ferlay J., Siegel R.L., Laversanne M., Soerjomataram I., Jemal A., Bray F. Global Cancer Statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN Estimates of Incidence and Mortality Worldwide for 36 Cancers in 185 Countries. CA Cancer J. Clin. 2021;71:209&#x2013;249. doi: 10.3322/caac.21660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min H.Y., Lee H.Y. Mechanisms of resistance to chemotherapy in non-small cell lung cancer. Arch Pharm. Res. (Seoul) 2021;44:146&#x2013;164. doi: 10.1007/S12272-021-01312-Y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S12272-021-01312-Y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33608812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Ortega M., Carrera A.C., Garrido A. Role of NRF2 in Lung Cancer. Cells. 2021;10 doi: 10.3390/CELLS10081879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/CELLS10081879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astolfi A., Nannini M., Indio V., Schipani A., Rizzo A., Perrone A.M., De Iaco P., Pirini M.G., De Leo A., Urbini M., et al. Genomic Database Analysis of Uterine Leiomyosarcoma Mutational Profile. Cancers (Basel) 2020;12:2126. doi: 10.3390/CANCERS12082126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/CANCERS12082126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7464219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32751892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bas O., Sahin T.K., Karahan L., Rizzo A., Guven D.C. Prognostic significance of the cachexia index (CXI) in patients with cancer: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin. Nutr. ESPEN. 2025;68:240&#x2013;247. doi: 10.1016/j.clnesp.2025.03.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2025.03.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40157535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bialk P., Wang Y., Banas K., Kmiec E.B. Functional Gene Knockout of NRF2 Increases Chemosensitivity of Human Lung Cancer A549 Cells In Vitro and in a Xenograft Mouse Model. Mol. Ther. Oncolytics. 2018;11:75&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1016/J.OMTO.2018.10.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.OMTO.2018.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6251792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30505938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banas K., Rivera-Torres N., Bialk P., Yoo B.C., Kmiec E.B. Kinetics of Nuclear Uptake and Site-Specific DNA Cleavage during CRISPR-Directed Gene Editing in Solid Tumor Cells. Mol. Cancer Res. 2020;18:891&#x2013;902. doi: 10.1158/1541-7786.MCR-19-1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1541-7786.MCR-19-1208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32184217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banas K., Modarai S., Rivera-Torres N., Yoo B.C., Bialk P.A., Barrett C., Batish M., Kmiec E.B. Exon skipping induced by CRISPR-directed gene editing regulates the response to chemotherapy in non-small cell lung carcinoma cells. Gene Ther. 2022;29:357&#x2013;367. doi: 10.1038/S41434-022-00324-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/S41434-022-00324-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9203268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35314779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J., Lin X., Meng D., Zeng L., Zhuang R., Huang S., Lv W., Hu J. Nrf2 Mediates Metabolic Reprogramming in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer. Front. Oncol. 2020;10 doi: 10.3389/FONC.2020.578315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/FONC.2020.578315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7726415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuoka Y., Yoshida R., Kawahara K., Sakata J., Arita H., Nkashima H., Takahashi N., Hirayama M., Nagata M., Hirosue A., et al. The antioxidative stress regulator Nrf2 potentiates radioresistance of oral squamous cell carcinoma accompanied with metabolic modulation. Lab. Invest. 2022;102:896&#x2013;907. doi: 10.1038/S41374-022-00776-W.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/S41374-022-00776-W</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9309095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35414650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng L., Zhao K., Sun L., Yin X., Zhang J., Liu C., Li B. SLC7A11 regulated by NRF2 modulates esophageal squamous cell carcinoma radiosensitivity by inhibiting ferroptosis. J. Transl. Med. 2021;19 doi: 10.1186/S12967-021-03042-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/S12967-021-03042-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8393811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34446045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata T., Kokubu A., Saito S., Narisawa-Saito M., Sasaki H., Aoyagi K., Yoshimatsu Y., Tachimori Y., Kushima R., Kiyono T., Yamamoto M. NRF2 mutation confers malignant potential and resistance to chemoradiation therapy in advanced esophageal squamous cancer. Neoplasia. 2011;13:864&#x2013;873. doi: 10.1593/NEO.11750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1593/NEO.11750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21969819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes J.D., McMahon M. NRF2 and KEAP1 mutations: permanent activation of an adaptive response in cancer. Trends Biochem. Sci. 2009;34:176&#x2013;188. doi: 10.1016/J.TIBS.2008.12.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TIBS.2008.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19321346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menegon S., Columbano A., Giordano S. The Dual Roles of NRF2 in Cancer. Trends Mol. Med. 2016;22:578&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1016/J.MOLMED.2016.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.MOLMED.2016.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27263465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson D.E., Burtness B., Leemans C.R., Lui V.W.Y., Bauman J.E., Grandis J.R. Head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. Nat. Rev. Dis. Primers. 2020;6:92. doi: 10.1038/S41572-020-00224-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/S41572-020-00224-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7944998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X.J., Sun Z., Villeneuve N.F., Zhang S., Zhao F., Li Y., Chen W., Yi X., Zheng W., Wondrak G.T., et al. Nrf2 enhances resistance of cancer cells to chemotherapeutic drugs, the dark side of Nrf2. Carcinogenesis. 2008;29:1235&#x2013;1243. doi: 10.1093/CARCIN/BGN095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/CARCIN/BGN095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3312612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18413364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan J., Zhang Y., Chen R., Liang L., Huo Y., Lu S., Zhao J., Hu C., Sun Y., Yang K., et al. Tumor-immune microenvironment and NRF2 associate with clinical efficacy of PD-1 blockade combined with chemotherapy in lung squamous cell carcinoma. Cell Rep. Med. 2023;4 doi: 10.1016/J.XCRM.2023.101302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.XCRM.2023.101302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10772345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38052215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerins M.J., Ooi A. A catalogue of somatic NRF2 gain-of-function mutations in cancer. Sci. Rep. 2018;8 doi: 10.1038/S41598-018-31281-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/S41598-018-31281-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6110754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30150714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement K., Rees H., Canver M.C., Gehrke J.M., Farouni R., Hsu J.Y., Cole M.A., Liu D.R., Joung J.K., Bauer D.E., Pinello L. CRISPResso2 provides accurate and rapid genome editing sequence analysis. Nat. Biotechnol. 2019;37:224&#x2013;226. doi: 10.1038/s41587-019-0032-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41587-019-0032-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6533916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30809026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansbury B.M., Hewes A.M., Kmiec E.B. Understanding the diversity of genetic outcomes from CRISPR-Cas generated homology-directed repair. Commun. Biol. 2019;2:458. doi: 10.1038/s42003-019-0705-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-019-0705-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6898364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31840103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taheri-Ghahfarokhi A., Taylor B.J.M., Nitsch R., Lundin A., Cavallo A.L., Madeyski-Bengtson K., Karlsson F., Clausen M., Hicks R., Mayr L.M., et al. Decoding non-random mutational signatures at Cas9 targeted sites. Nucleic Acids Res. 2018;46:8417&#x2013;8434. doi: 10.1093/NAR/GKY653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/NAR/GKY653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6144780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30032200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Overbeek M., Capurso D., Carter M.M., Thompson M.S., Frias E., Russ C., Reece-Hoyes J.S., Nye C., Gradia S., Vidal B., et al. DNA Repair Profiling Reveals Nonrandom Outcomes at Cas9-Mediated Breaks. Mol. Cell. 2016;63:633&#x2013;646. doi: 10.1016/j.molcel.2016.06.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2016.06.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27499295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakrabarti A.M., Henser-Brownhill T., Monserrat J., Poetsch A.R., Luscombe N.M., Scaffidi P. Target-Specific Precision of CRISPR-Mediated Genome Editing. Mol. Cell. 2019;73:699&#x2013;713.e6. doi: 10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2018.11.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2018.11.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6395888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloh K., Kanchana R., Bialk P., Banas K., Zhang Z., Yoo B.C., Kmiec E.B. Deconvolution of Complex DNA Repair (DECODR): Establishing a Novel Deconvolution Algorithm for Comprehensive Analysis of CRISPR-Edited Sanger Sequencing Data. CRISPR J. 2021;4:120&#x2013;131. doi: 10.1089/crispr.2020.0022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/crispr.2020.0022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7898406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgenstern C., Lastres-Becker I., Demird&#xf6;&#x11f;en B.C., Costa V.M., Daiber A., Foresti R., Motterlini R., Kalyoncu S., Arioz B.I., Genc S., et al. Biomarkers of NRF2 signalling: Current status and future challenges. Redox Biol. 2024;72 doi: 10.1016/J.REDOX.2024.103134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.REDOX.2024.103134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11046063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38643749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobosy J.R., Rose S.D., Beltz K.R., Rupp S.M., Powers K.M., Behlke M.A., Walder J.A. RNase H-dependent PCR (rhPCR): improved specificity and single nucleotide polymorphism detection using blocked cleavable primers. BMC Biotechnol. 2011;11:80. doi: 10.1186/1472-6750-11-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6750-11-80</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3224242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21831278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltz K., Tsang D., Wang J., Rose S., Bao Y., Wang Y., Larkin K., Rupp S., Schrepfer D., Datta K., et al. A High-Performing and Cost-Effective SNP Genotyping Method Using rhPCR and Universal Reporters. Adv. Biosci. Biotechnol. 2018;09:497&#x2013;512. doi: 10.4236/ABB.2018.99034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ABB.2018.99034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurgan G., Turk R., Li H., Roberts N., Rettig G.R., Jacobi A.M., Tso L., Sturgeon M., Mertens M., Noten R., et al. CRISPAltRations: a validated cloud-based approach for interrogation of double-strand break repair mediated by CRISPR genome editing. Mol. Ther. Methods Clin. Dev. 2021;21:478&#x2013;491. doi: 10.1016/J.OMTM.2021.03.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.OMTM.2021.03.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8082044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33981780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae S., Park J., Kim J.S. Cas-OFFinder: a fast and versatile algorithm that searches for potential off-target sites of Cas9 RNA-guided endonucleases. Bioinformatics. 2014;30:1473&#x2013;1475. doi: 10.1093/BIOINFORMATICS/BTU048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/BIOINFORMATICS/BTU048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4016707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24463181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron P., Fuller C.K., Donohoue P.D., Jones B.N., Thompson M.S., Carter M.M., Gradia S., Vidal B., Garner E., Slorach E.M., et al. Mapping the genomic landscape of CRISPR-Cas9 cleavage. Nat. Methods. 2017;14:600&#x2013;606. doi: 10.1038/NMETH.4284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/NMETH.4284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28459459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai S.Q., Zheng Z., Nguyen N.T., Liebers M., Topkar V.V., Thapar V., Wyvekens N., Khayter C., Iafrate A.J., Le L.P., et al. GUIDE-seq enables genome-wide profiling of off-target cleavage by CRISPR-Cas nucleases. Nat. Biotechnol. 2015;33:187&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1038/NBT.3117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/NBT.3117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4320685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25513782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos E.S., Rodriguez E. Treatment Considerations for Patients With Advanced Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Lung. Clin. Lung Cancer. 2022;23:457&#x2013;466. doi: 10.1016/J.CLLC.2022.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CLLC.2022.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35872084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellar A., Egan C., Morris D. Preclinical Murine Models for Lung Cancer: Clinical Trial Applications. BioMed Res. Int. 2015;2015 doi: 10.1155/2015/621324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/621324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4433653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26064932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettinger D.S., Wood D.E., Aisner D.L., Akerley W., Bauman J.R., Bharat A., Bruno D.S., Chang J.Y., Chirieac L.R., DeCamp M., et al. NCCN Guidelines&#xae; Insights: Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer, Version 2.2023. J. Natl. Compr. Canc. Netw. 2023;21:340&#x2013;350. doi: 10.6004/JNCCN.2023.0020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6004/JNCCN.2023.0020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37015337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A., Bodas M., Wakabayashi N., Bunz F., Biswal S. Gain of Nrf2 Function in Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer Cells Confers Radioresistance. Antioxid. Redox Signal. 2010;13:1627&#x2013;1637. doi: 10.1089/ARS.2010.3219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ARS.2010.3219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3541552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20446773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abazeed M., Hammerman P., Creighton C., Adams D., Giacomelli A., Meyerson M. NRF2 Pathway Activation Regulates Radiation Resistance in Lung Squamous Cell Carcinoma. Int. J. Radiat. Oncol. Biol. Phys. 2012;84:S179&#x2013;S180. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrobp.2012.07.465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrobp.2012.07.465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scalera S., Mazzotta M., Corleone G., Sperati F., Terrenato I., Krasniqi E., Pizzuti L., Barba M., Vici P., Gallo E., et al. KEAP1 and TP53 Frame Genomic, Evolutionary, and Immunologic Subtypes of Lung Adenocarcinoma With Different Sensitivity to Immunotherapy. J. Thorac. Oncol. 2021;16:2065&#x2013;2077. doi: 10.1016/J.JTHO.2021.08.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JTHO.2021.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34450259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinelli D., Mazzotta M., Scalera S., Terrenato I., Sperati F., D&#x2019;Ambrosio L., Pallocca M., Corleone G., Krasniqi E., Pizzuti L., et al. KEAP1-driven co-mutations in lung adenocarcinoma unresponsive to immunotherapy despite high tumor mutational burden. Ann. Oncol. 2020;31:1746&#x2013;1754. doi: 10.1016/J.ANNONC.2020.08.2105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.ANNONC.2020.08.2105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32866624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A., Daemen A., Nickles D., Jeon S.M., Foreman O., Sudini K., Gnad F., Lajoie S., Gour N., Mitzner W., et al. NRF2 Activation Promotes Aggressive Lung Cancer and Associates with Poor Clinical Outcomes. Clin. Cancer Res. 2021;27:877&#x2013;888. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-20-1985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-20-1985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10867786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33077574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torrente L., Sanchez C., Moreno R., Chowdhry S., Cabello P., Isono K., Koseki H., Honda T., Hayes J.D., Dinkova-Kostova A.T., de la Vega L. Crosstalk between NRF2 and HIPK2 shapes cytoprotective responses. Oncogene. 2017;36:6204&#x2013;6212. doi: 10.1038/ONC.2017.221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ONC.2017.221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5641449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28692050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D., Rennhack J., Andrechek E.R., Rockwell C.E., Liby K.T. Identification of an Unfavorable Immune Signature in Advanced Lung Tumors from Nrf2-Deficient Mice. Antioxid. Redox Signal. 2018;29:1535&#x2013;1552. doi: 10.1089/ARS.2017.7201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ARS.2017.7201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6421995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29634345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homma S., Ishii Y., Morishima Y., Yamadori T., Matsuno Y., Haraguchi N., Kikuchi N., Satoh H., Sakamoto T., Hizawa N., et al. Nrf2 enhances cell proliferation and resistance to anticancer drugs in human lung cancer. Clin. Cancer Res. 2009;15:3423&#x2013;3432. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-08-2822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-08-2822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19417020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y., Wu K., Liu Q., Han N., Zhang L., Chu Q., Chen Y. Modification of platinum sensitivity by KEAP1/NRF2 signals in non-small cell lung cancer. J. Hematol. Oncol. 2016;9 doi: 10.1186/S13045-016-0311-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/S13045-016-0311-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5012055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27601007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H., Wang W., Zhang Y., Zhao J., Lin E., Gao J., He J. The role of NF-E2-related factor 2 in predicting chemoresistance and prognosis in advanced non-small-cell lung cancer. Clin. Lung Cancer. 2011;12:166&#x2013;171. doi: 10.1016/J.CLLC.2011.03.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CLLC.2011.03.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21663859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaffl M.W. A new mathematical model for relative quantification in real-time RT&#x2013;PCR. Nucleic Acids Res. 2001;29:e45. doi: 10.1093/NAR/29.9.E45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/NAR/29.9.E45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC55695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11328886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41244267</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2950-3299</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular therapy. Oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Ther Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Longitudinal tracking of <i>MALAT1</i> level over a breast cancer patient's course of treatment and disease progression.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>201070</StartPage><MedlinePgn>201070</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">201070</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201070</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) have emerged as important regulators of the hallmarks of cancer, yet their potential remains under-explored in clinical studies. <i>Metastasis-Associated Lung Adenocarcinoma Transcript 1</i> (<i>MALAT1</i>), an lncRNA upregulated in over 20 tumor types including breast tumors, has been associated with metastasis, yet its expression across the clinical course of treatment and disease progression remains uncharacterized. For the first time, this case report evaluated <i>MALAT1</i> level in multiple biopsies collected over a breast cancer patient's clinical course of treatment spanning 2.5 years, using quantitative single-molecule RNA fluorescence <i>in situ</i> hybridization. We observed that <i>MALAT1</i> levels were consistently elevated in tumor cells relative to adjacent stroma, reduced upon standard-of-care therapeutic interventions, and markedly increased in distant metastatic lesions. These longitudinal changes in expression level demonstrate a link between <i>MALAT1</i> and disease progression. Our findings highlight the potential of <i>MALAT1</i> as a prognostic marker for treatment response and metastatic risk stratification and support pursuing <i>MALAT1</i> as a therapeutic target.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aggarwal</LastName><ForeName>Disha</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Cold Spring Harbor, NY 11724, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genetics Graduate Program, Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, NY 11794, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wee</LastName><ForeName>Tse-Luen</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Cold Spring Harbor, NY 11724, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Satpathy</LastName><ForeName>Shuchismita</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Cold Spring Harbor, NY 11724, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology/Hematology, Northwell Health, New Hyde Park, New York 11042, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russo</LastName><ForeName>Suzanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Cold Spring Harbor, NY 11724, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spector</LastName><ForeName>David L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Cold Spring Harbor, NY 11724, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genetics Graduate Program, Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, NY 11794, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Ther Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918752083706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2950-3299</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MALAT1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MT: Regular Issue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TNBC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lncRNA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metastasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smRNA-FISH</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>D.L.S. is on the Scientific Advisory Board of Amaroq Therapeutics.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41244267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12617757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2950-3299(25)00139-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kim J., Harper A., McCormack V., Sung H., Houssami N., Morgan E., Mutebi M., Garvey G., Soerjomataram I., Fidler-Benaoudia M.M. Global patterns and trends in breast cancer incidence and mortality across 185 countries. Nat. Med. 2025;31:1154&#x2013;1162. doi: 10.1038/s41591-025-03502-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-025-03502-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39994475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray F., Laversanne M., Sung H., Ferlay J., Siegel R.L., Soerjomataram I., Jemal A. Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J. Clin. 2024;74:229&#x2013;263. doi: 10.3322/CAAC.21834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/CAAC.21834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burguin A., Diorio C., Durocher F. Breast Cancer Treatments: Updates and New Challenges. J. Pers. Med. 2021;11 doi: 10.3390/JPM11080808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/JPM11080808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8399130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34442452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dittmer J. Mechanisms governing metastatic dormancy in breast cancer. Semin. Cancer Biol. 2017;44:72&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/J.SEMCANCER.2017.03.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.SEMCANCER.2017.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28344165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkholi I.E., Lalonde A., Park M., C&#xf4;t&#xe9; J.F. Breast Cancer Metastatic Dormancy and Relapse: An Enigma of Microenvironment(s) Cancer Res. 2022;82:4497&#x2013;4510. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-22-1902/709673/AM/BREAST-CANCER-METASTATIC-DORMANCY-AND-RELAPSE-AN.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-22-1902/709673/AM/BREAST-CANCER-METASTATIC-DORMANCY-AND-RELAPSE-AN</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9755970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36214624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fein M.R., Egeblad M. Caught in the act: Revealing the metastatic process by live imaging. Dis. Model. Mech. 2013;6:580&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1242/DMM.009282/VIDEO-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/DMM.009282/VIDEO-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3634643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23616077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattick J.S., Amaral P.P., Carninci P., Carpenter S., Chang H.Y., Chen L.L., Chen R., Dean C., Dinger M.E., Fitzgerald K.A., et al. Long non-coding RNAs: definitions, functions, challenges and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 2023;24:430&#x2013;447. doi: 10.1038/s41580-022-00566-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41580-022-00566-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10213152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36596869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun G., Aggarwal D., Spector D.L. MALAT1 Long Non-Coding RNA: Functional Implications. Noncoding. RNA. 2020;6:22. doi: 10.3390/ncrna6020022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ncrna6020022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7344863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32503170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji P., Diederichs S., Wang W., B&#xf6;ing S., Metzger R., Schneider P.M., Tidow N., Brandt B., Buerger H., Bulk E., et al. MALAT-1, a novel noncoding RNA, and thymosin &#x3b2;4 predict metastasis and survival in early-stage non-small cell lung cancer. Oncogene. 2003;22:8031&#x2013;8041. doi: 10.1038/sj.onc.1206928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.onc.1206928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12970751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amodio N., Raimondi L., Juli G., Stamato M.A., Caracciolo D., Tagliaferri P., Tassone P. MALAT1: A druggable long non-coding RNA for targeted anti-cancer approaches. J. Hematol. Oncol. 2018;11:63. doi: 10.1186/s13045-018-0606-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13045-018-0606-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29739426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemson C.M., Hutchinson J.N., Sara S.A., Ensminger A.W., Fox A.H., Chess A., Lawrence J.B. An Architectural Role for a Nuclear Non-coding RNA: NEAT1 RNA is Essential for the Structure of Paraspeckles. Mol. Cell. 2009;33:717&#x2013;726. doi: 10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2009.01.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2009.01.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2696186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19217333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchinson J.N., Ensminger A.W., Clemson C.M., Lynch C.R., Lawrence J.B., Chess A. A screen for nuclear transcripts identifies two linked noncoding RNAs associated with SC35 splicing domains. BMC Genom. 2007;8:39. doi: 10.1186/1471-2164-8-39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-8-39</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1800850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17270048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi V., Ellis J.D., Shen Z., Song D.Y., Pan Q., Watt A.T., Freier S.M., Bennett C.F., Sharma A., Bubulya P.A., et al. The nuclear-retained noncoding RNA MALAT1 regulates alternative splicing by modulating SR splicing factor phosphorylation. Mol. Cell. 2010;39:925&#x2013;938. doi: 10.1016/j.molcel.2010.08.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2010.08.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4158944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20797886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang N.S., Chi Y.Y., Xue J.Y., Liu M.Y., Huang S., Mo M., Zhou S.L., Wu J. Long non-coding RNA metastasis associated in lung adenocarcinoma transcript 1 (MALAT1) interacts with estrogen receptor and predicted poor survival in breast cancer. Oncotarget. 2016;7:37957&#x2013;37965. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.9364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.9364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5122363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27191888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao J., Zhang Q., Wang P., Wang Z. LncRNA MALAT1 promotes breast cancer progression by sponging miR101-3p to mediate mTOR/PKM2 signal transmission. Am. J. Transl. Res. 2021;13:10262&#x2013;10275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8507063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue X., Wu W.Y., Dong M., Guo M. LncRNA MALAT1 promotes breast cancer progression and doxorubicin resistance via regulating miR-570&#x2013;3p. Biomed. J. 2021;44:S296&#x2013;S304. doi: 10.1016/J.BJ.2020.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.BJ.2020.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35410813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng T., Shao F., Wu Q., Zhang X., Xu D., Qian K., Xie Y., Wang S., Xu N., Wang Y., Qi C. miR-124 downregulation leads to breast cancer progression via LncRNA-MALAT1 regulation and CDK4/E2F1 signal activation. Oncotarget. 2016;7:16205&#x2013;16216. doi: 10.18632/ONCOTARGET.7578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/ONCOTARGET.7578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4941308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26918449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadaliha M., Zong X., Malakar P., Ray T., Singh D.K., Freier S.M., Jensen T., Prasanth S.G., Karni R., Ray P.S., Prasanth K.V. Functional and prognostic significance of long non-coding RNA MALAT1 as a metastasis driver in ER negative lymph node negative breast cancer. Oncotarget. 2016;7:40418&#x2013;40436. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.9622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.9622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5130017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27250026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Katsaros D., Biglia N., Shen Y., Fu Y., Loo L.W.M., Jia W., Obata Y., Yu H. High expression of long non-coding RNA MALAT1 in breast cancer is associated with poor relapse-free survival. Breast Cancer Res. Treat. 2018;171:261&#x2013;271. doi: 10.1007/s10549-018-4839-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-018-4839-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6488226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zhang Y., Hu K., Qiu J., Hu Y., Zhou M., Zhang S. Elevated long noncoding RNA MALAT-1 expression is predictive of poor prognosis in patients with breast cancer: A meta-analysis. Biosci. Rep. 2020;40 doi: 10.1042/BSR20200215/225866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/BSR20200215/225866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7419804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32700729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar D., Gurrapu S., Wang Y., Bae S.Y., Pandey P.R., Chen H., Mondal J., Han H., Wu C.J., Karaiskos S., et al. LncRNA Malat1 suppresses pyroptosis and T cell-mediated killing of incipient metastatic cells. Nat. Cancer. 2024;5:262&#x2013;282. doi: 10.1038/S43018-023-00695-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/S43018-023-00695-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38195932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun G., Spector D.L. MALAT1 long non-coding RNA and breast cancer. RNA Biol. 2019;16:860&#x2013;863. doi: 10.1080/15476286.2019.1592072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15476286.2019.1592072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6546402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30874469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok Z.H., Roche V., Chew X.H., Fadieieva A., Tay Y. A non-canonical tumor suppressive role for the long non-coding RNA MALAT1 in colon and breast cancers. Int. J. Cancer. 2018;143:668&#x2013;678. doi: 10.1002/ijc.31386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijc.31386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29574704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J., Piao H.-L., Kim B.-J., Yao F., Han Z., Wang Y., Xiao Z., Siverly A.N., Lawhon S.E., Ton B.N., et al. Long noncoding RNA MALAT1 suppresses breast cancer metastasis. Nat. Genet. 2018;50:1705&#x2013;1715. doi: 10.1038/s41588-018-0252-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41588-018-0252-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6265076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastlack S.C., Dong S., Mo Y.Y., Alahari S.K. Expression of long noncoding RNA MALAT1 correlates with increased levels of Nischarin and inhibits oncogenic cell functions in breast cancer. PLoS One. 2018;13 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0198945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0198945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6005468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29912916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Arun G., Mao Y.S., Lazar Z., Hung G., Bhattacharjee G., Xiao X., Booth C.J., Wu J., Zhang C., Spector D.L. The lncRNA Malat1 is dispensable for mouse development but its transcription plays a cis-regulatory role in the adult. Cell Rep. 2012;2:111&#x2013;123. doi: 10.1016/J.CELREP.2012.06.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CELREP.2012.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3408587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22840402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat A.A., Afzal O., Afzal M., Gupta G., Thapa R., Ali H., Hassan almalki W., Kazmi I., Alzarea S.I., Saleem S., et al. MALAT1: A key regulator in lung cancer pathogenesis and therapeutic targeting. Pathol. Res. Pract. 2024;253 doi: 10.1016/J.PRP.2023.154991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.PRP.2023.154991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38070223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein M.A., Valinezhad K., Adel E., Munirathinam G. MALAT-1 Is a Key Regulator of Epithelial&#x2013;Mesenchymal Transition in Cancer: A Potential Therapeutic Target for Metastasis. Cancers. 2024;16 doi: 10.3390/CANCERS16010234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/CANCERS16010234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10778055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38201661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthman Y.A., Ibrahim K.G., Abubakar B., Bello M.B., Malami I., Imam M.U., Qusty N., Cruz-Martins N., Batiha G.E.S., Abubakar M.B. MALAT1: A Promising Therapeutic Target for the Treatment of Metastatic Colorectal Cancer. Biochem. Pharmacol. 2021;190 doi: 10.1016/J.BCP.2021.114657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.BCP.2021.114657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34144008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Lieberman J. MALAT1 protects dormant tumor cells from immune elimination. Nat. Cancer. 2024;5:218&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1038/s43018-023-00682-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43018-023-00682-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38195934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adewunmi O., Shen Y., Zhang X.H.F., Rosen J.M. Targeted Inhibition of lncRNA Malat1 Alters the Tumor Immune Microenvironment in Preclinical Syngeneic Mouse Models of Triple-Negative Breast Cancer. Cancer Immunol. Res. 2023;11:1462&#x2013;1479. doi: 10.1158/2326-6066.CIR-23-0045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/2326-6066.CIR-23-0045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10618655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37603945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meseure D., Vacher S., Lallemand F., Alsibai K.D., Hatem R., Chemlali W., Nicolas A., De Koning L., Pasmant E., Callens C., et al. Prognostic value of a newly identified MALAT1 alternatively spliced transcript in breast cancer. Br. J. Cancer. 2016;114:1395&#x2013;1404. doi: 10.1038/bjc.2016.123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bjc.2016.123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4984455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27172249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirks R.M., Pierce N.A. Triggered amplification by hybridization chain reaction. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2004;101:15275&#x2013;15278. doi: 10.1073/PNAS.0407024101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/PNAS.0407024101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC524468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15492210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun G., Diermeier S., Akerman M., Chang K.-C., Wilkinson J.E., Hearn S., Kim Y., MacLeod A.R., Krainer A.R., Norton L., et al. Differentiation of mammary tumors and reduction in metastasis upon Malat1 lncRNA loss. Genes Dev. 2016;30:34&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1101/gad.270959.115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gad.270959.115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4701977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26701265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi H.M.T., Schwarzkopf M., Fornace M.E., Acharya A., Artavanis G., Stegmaier J., Cunha A., Pierce N.A. Third-generation in situ hybridization chain reaction: Multiplexed, quantitative, sensitive, versatile, robust. Development. 2018;145 doi: 10.1242/DEV.165753/48466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/DEV.165753/48466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6031405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29945988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Cui Z., Li H., Lv X., Gao M., Yang Z., Bi Y., Zhang Z., Wang S., Zhou B., Yin Z. Clinicopathological and prognostic significance of long noncoding RNA MALAT1 in human cancers: A review and meta-analysis. Cancer Cell Int. 2018;18:109. doi: 10.1186/s12935-018-0606-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12935-018-0606-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6080354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30093838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Terroba E., Plasek-Hegde L.M., Chiotakakos I., Li V., de Miguel F.J., Robles-Oteiza C., Tyagi A., Politi K., Zamudio J.R., Dimitrova N. Overexpression of Malat1 drives metastasis through inflammatory reprogramming of the tumor microenvironment. Sci. Immunol. 2024;9:5462. doi: 10.1126/sciimmunol.adh5462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciimmunol.adh5462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12087577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38875320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutschner T., H&#xe4;mmerle M., Eissmann M., Hsu J., Kim Y., Hung G., Revenko A., Arun G., Stentrup M., Gross M., et al. The noncoding RNA MALAT1 is a critical regulator of the metastasis phenotype of lung cancer cells. Cancer Res. 2013;73:1180&#x2013;1189. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-12-2850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-12-2850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3589741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23243023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaath H., Vishnubalaji R., Elango R., Khattak S., Alajez N.M. Single-cell long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) transcriptome implicates MALAT1 in triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) resistance to neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Cell Death Discov. 2021;7:23. doi: 10.1038/s41420-020-00383-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41420-020-00383-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7835365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33495450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team . R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2024. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H. Springer-Verlag; 2016. ggplot2: Elegant Graphics for Data Analysis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu A., Ibrahim J.G., Love M.I. Heavy-tailed prior distributions for sequence count data: removing the noise and preserving large differences. Bioinformatics. 2019;35:2084&#x2013;2092. doi: 10.1093/BIOINFORMATICS/BTY895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/BIOINFORMATICS/BTY895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6581436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H., Fran&#xe7;ois R., Henry L., M&#xfc;ller K., Vaughan D. dplyr: A Grammar of Data Manipulation. 2023. https://github.com/tidyverse/dplyr</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41050430</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2950-3299</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular therapy. Oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Ther Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>HIF1A, BRG1, and p300 interaction confers paclitaxel-induced drug resistance by enabling the overexpression of <i>ABCC</i> genes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>201049</StartPage><MedlinePgn>201049</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">201049</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201049</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The development of resistance to paclitaxel (PTX), which is a vital anticancer drug treating breast and lung cancers, can cause treatment failure and limit further use of taxanes and similar drugs. As previously documented, PTX-induced irresponsiveness to chemotherapy involves the overexpression of ABCC3, ABCC5, and ABCC10 members of the ATP-binding cassette (ABC) transmembrane proteins, which are enriched in the lysosomes of drug-resistant cells where anticancer drugs are actively trapped. In this paper, the role of HIF1A in a BRG1-p300-dependent overexpression of 3 <i>ABCC</i> genes in drug resistant cells was examined. Although motive spacing analysis of BRG1 enriched regions indicated that HIF1A, ISL1, MAF, and ZNF76 could be possible BRG1 co-regulators, <i>bona fide</i> co-operation with BRG1 and the contribution to drug resistance was only confirmed for HIF1A. HIF1A deficiency abolished the transcription promoting effect of BRG1 and p300, thereby suggesting that this protein acts as the master regulator of ABCC transcription. Analysis of The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) and The Genotype-Tissue Expression (GTEx) databases confirmed a likely role of HIF1A-BRG1-p300 overexpression in the taxanes resistance of cancer patients and the possible biomarker function of this protein in cancer responses to chemotherapy. Therefore, the complex comprising BRG1-EP300-HIF1A can be considered for further clinical investigation and planning for patient therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gronkowska</LastName><ForeName>Karolina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Biophysics, Faculty of Biology and Environmental Protection, University of Lodz, Pomorska 141/143, 90-236 Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bio-Med-Chem Doctoral School of the University of Lodz and Lodz Institutes of the Polish Academy of Sciences, University of Lodz, Banacha 12/16, 90-237 Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ko&#x142;acz-Milewska</LastName><ForeName>Kinga</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Biophysics, Faculty of Biology and Environmental Protection, University of Lodz, Pomorska 141/143, 90-236 Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bio-Med-Chem Doctoral School of the University of Lodz and Lodz Institutes of the Polish Academy of Sciences, University of Lodz, Banacha 12/16, 90-237 Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michlewska</LastName><ForeName>Sylwia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Microscopic Imaging and Specialized Biological Techniques, Faculty of Biology and Environmental Protection, University of Lodz, Banacha 12/16, 90-237 Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P&#x142;oszaj</LastName><ForeName>Tomasz</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Genetics, Medical University of Lodz, Pomorska 251, 92-213 Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borowiec</LastName><ForeName>Maciej</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Genetics, Medical University of Lodz, Pomorska 251, 92-213 Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robaszkiewicz</LastName><ForeName>Agnieszka</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Biophysics, Faculty of Biology and Environmental Protection, University of Lodz, Pomorska 141/143, 90-236 Lodz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Ther Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918752083706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2950-3299</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ATP-binding cassette transporters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BRG1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EP300</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIF1a</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MT: Regular Issue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemotherapy response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lysosomal trapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multidrug resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paclitaxel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcription co-activation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41050430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12493206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2950-3299(25)00118-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bray F., Laversanne M., Sung H., Ferlay J., Siegel R.L., Soerjomataram I., Jemal A. Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J. Clin. 2024;74:229&#x2013;263. doi: 10.3322/caac.21834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sati P., Sharma E., Dhyani P., Attri D.C., Rana R., Kiyekbayeva L., B&#xfc;sselberg D., Samuel S.M., Sharifi-Rad J. Paclitaxel and its semi-synthetic derivatives: comprehensive insights into chemical structure, mechanisms of action, and anticancer properties. Eur. J. Med. Res. 2024;29:90. doi: 10.1186/s40001-024-01657-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40001-024-01657-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10826257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38291541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney S.M., Hoover C.A., Morejon-Lasso L.V., Prosperi J.R. Mechanisms of Taxane Resistance. Cancers (Basel) 2020;12 doi: 10.3390/cancers12113323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers12113323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7697134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33182737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;kubn&#xed;k J., Pavl&#xed;&#x10d;kov&#xe1; V., Ruml T., Rimpelov&#xe1; S. Current Perspectives on Taxanes: Focus on Their Bioactivity, Delivery and Combination Therapy. Plants. 2021;10:569. doi: 10.3390/plants10030569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants10030569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8002726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das T., Anand U., Pandey S.K., Ashby C.R., Assaraf Y.G., Chen Z.S., Dey A. Therapeutic strategies to overcome taxane resistance in cancer. Drug Resist. Updates. 2021;55 doi: 10.1016/J.DRUP.2021.100754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.DRUP.2021.100754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33691261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alalawy A.I. Key genes and molecular mechanisms related to Paclitaxel Resistance. Cancer Cell Int. 2024;24:244. doi: 10.1186/S12935-024-03415-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/S12935-024-03415-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11245874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39003454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q., Song Y., Cheng X., Xu Z., Matthew O.A., Wang J.I.A., Sun Z., Zhang X. Apatinib Reverses Paclitaxel-resistant Lung Cancer Cells (A549) Through Blocking the Function of ABCB1 Transporter. Anticancer Res. 2019;39:5461&#x2013;5471. doi: 10.21873/anticanres.13739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21873/anticanres.13739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31570440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguri T., Ozasa H., Uemura T., Bessho Y., Miyazaki M., Maeno K., Maeda H., Sato S., Ueda R. MRP7/ABCC10 expression is a predictive biomarker for the resistance to paclitaxel in non-small cell lung cancer. Mol. Cancer Therapeut. 2008;7:1150&#x2013;1155. doi: 10.1158/1535-7163.MCT-07-2088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1535-7163.MCT-07-2088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18445659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melguizo C., Prados J., Luque R., Ortiz R., Caba O., Alvarez P.J., Gonzalez B., Aranega A. Modulation of MDR1 and MRP3 gene expression in lung cancer cells after paclitaxel and carboplatin exposure. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2012;13:16624&#x2013;16635. doi: 10.3390/ijms131216624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms131216624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3546711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23443122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprouse A.A., Herbert B.-S. Resveratrol Augments Paclitaxel Treatment in MDA-MB-231 and Paclitaxel-resistant MDA-MB-231 Breast Cancer Cells. Anticancer Res. 2014;34:5363&#x2013;5374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25275030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCorkle J.R., Gorski J.W., Liu J., Riggs M.B., McDowell A.B., Lin N., Wang C., Ueland F.R., Kolesar J.M. Lapatinib and poziotinib overcome ABCB1-mediated paclitaxel resistance in ovarian cancer. PLoS One. 2021;16 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0254205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0254205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8336885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#x11b;mcov&#xe1;-F&#xfc;rstov&#xe1; V., Kopperov&#xe1; D., Balu&#x161;&#xed;kov&#xe1; K., Ehrlichov&#xe1; M., Brynychov&#xe1; V., V&#xe1;clav&#xed;kov&#xe1; R., Daniel P., Sou&#x10d;ek P., Kov&#xe1;&#x159; J. Characterization of acquired paclitaxel resistance of breast cancer cells and involvement of ABC transporters. Toxicol. Appl. Pharmacol. 2016;310:215&#x2013;228. doi: 10.1016/J.TAAP.2016.09.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TAAP.2016.09.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27664577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien C., Cavet G., Pandita A., Hu X., Haydu L., Mohan S., Toy K., Rivers C.S., Modrusan Z., Amler L.C., Lackner M.R. Functional Genomics Identifies ABCC3 as a Mediator of Taxane Resistance in HER2-Amplified Breast Cancer. Cancer Res. 2008;68:5380&#x2013;5389. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-08-0234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-08-0234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18593940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y., Zhu Q., Li Z., Peng Y., Yu X., Yuan B., Liu Y., Liu Y., Yin L., Peng Y., et al. The FOXM1&#x2013;ABCC5 axis contributes to paclitaxel resistance in nasopharyngeal carcinoma cells. Cell Death Dis. 2017;8:e2659. doi: 10.1038/cddis.2017.53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cddis.2017.53</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5386553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28277541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gronkowska K., Michlewska S., Robaszkiewicz A. Activity of Lysosomal ABCC3, ABCC5 and ABCC10 is Responsible for Lysosomal Sequestration of Doxorubicin and Paclitaxel-Oregongreen488 in Paclitaxel-Resistant Cancer Cell Lines. Cell. Physiol. Biochem. 2023;57:360&#x2013;378. doi: 10.33594/000000663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33594/000000663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37767694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gronkowska K., Michlewska S., P&#x142;oszaj T., Strachowska M., St&#x119;pie&#x144; A., Borowiec M., Bednarek A., Robaszkiewicz A. BRG1 targeting overcomes ABCC-based multidrug resistance induced by paclitaxel. bioRxiv. 2025;57:360. doi: 10.1101/2025.05.01.651609. Preprint at.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2025.05.01.651609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F., Marshall C.B., Ikura M. Transcriptional/epigenetic regulator CBP/p300 in tumorigenesis: structural and functional versatility in target recognition. Cell. Mol. Life Sci. 2013;70:3989&#x2013;4008. doi: 10.1007/S00018-012-1254-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S00018-012-1254-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11113169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23307074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobczak M., Pietrzak J., Tomasz P., Robaszkiewicz A. BRG1 Activates Proliferation and Transcription of Cell Cycle-Dependent Genes in Breast Cancer Cells. Cancers (Basel) 2020;12:1&#x2013;18. doi: 10.3390/cancers12020349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers12020349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7072512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q., Sharma S., Cui H., LeBlanc S.E., Zhang H., Muthuswami R., Nickerson J.A., Imbalzano A.N. Targeting the chromatin remodeling enzyme BRG1 increases the efficacy of chemotherapy drugs in breast cancer cells. Oncotarget. 2016;7:27158&#x2013;27175. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.8384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.8384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5053639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27029062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Yue L., Hong W., Zhou J. SMARCA4 (BRG1) activates ABCC3 transcription to promote hepatocellular carcinogenesis. Life Sci. 2024;347 doi: 10.1016/J.LFS.2024.122605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.LFS.2024.122605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38642845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strachowska M., Gronkowska K., Michlewska S., Robaszkiewicz A. CBP/p300 Bromodomain Inhibitor-I-CBP112 Declines Transcription of the Key ABC Transporters and Sensitizes Cancer Cells to Chemotherapy Drugs. Cancers (Basel) 2021;13 doi: 10.3390/CANCERS13184614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/CANCERS13184614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8467251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34572840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrie J.J., Karr J.P., Graham T.G.W., Dailey G.M., Zhang G., Tjian R., Darzacq X. p300 is an obligate integrator of combinatorial transcription factor inputs. Mol. Cell. 2024;84:234&#x2013;243.e4. doi: 10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2023.12.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2023.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38159566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez J.C., Zhang L., Evoli S., Schnicker N.J., Nunez-Hernandez M., Yu L., Wereszczynski J., Pufall M.A., Musselman C.A. The molecular basis of selective DNA binding by the BRG1 AT-hook and bromodomain. Biochim. Biophys. Acta. Gene Regul. Mech. 2020;1863 doi: 10.1016/j.bbagrm.2020.194566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbagrm.2020.194566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7350285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y., Dong Z., Zhong W., Yin L., Li X., Kuerban G., Huang H. FOXM1 Promotes Drug Resistance in Cervical Cancer Cells by Regulating ABCC5 Gene Transcription. BioMed Res. Int. 2022;2022 doi: 10.1155/2022/3032590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/3032590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Zhang X., Jiang L., Zhang L., Xiang M., Ren H. FoxM1 Induced Paclitaxel Resistance via Activation of the FoxM1/PHB1/RAF-MEK-ERK Pathway and Enhancement of the ABCA2 Transporter. Mol. Ther. Oncolytics. 2019;14:196&#x2013;212. doi: 10.1016/j.omto.2019.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.omto.2019.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6616481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31334335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Sun J., Gao S., Hu H., Xie P. HOXB4 knockdown enhances the cytotoxic effect of paclitaxel and cisplatin by downregulating ABC transporters in ovarian cancer cells. Gene. 2018;663:9&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1016/j.gene.2018.04.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2018.04.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29660518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si X., Gao Z., Xu F., Zheng Y. SOX2 upregulates side population cells and enhances their chemoresistant ability by transactivating ABCC1 expression contributing to intrinsic resistance to paclitaxel in melanoma. Mol. Carcinog. 2020;59:257&#x2013;264. doi: 10.1002/mc.23148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mc.23148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31883360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee P., Gupta A., Chattopadhyay D., Chatterji U. Modulation of SOX2 expression delineates an end-point for paclitaxel-effectiveness in breast cancer stem cells. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:9170. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-08971-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-08971-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5569040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28835684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nian F., Zhu J., Chang H. Long non-coding RNA ANGPTL1-3 promotes multiple myeloma bortezomib resistance by sponging miR-30a-3p to activate c-Maf expression. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2019;514:1140&#x2013;1146. doi: 10.1016/j.bbrc.2019.05.078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2019.05.078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flamant L., Notte A., Ninane N., Raes M., Michiels C. Anti-apoptotic role of HIF-1 and AP-1 in paclitaxel exposed breast cancer cells under hypoxia. Mol. Cancer. 2010;9:191. doi: 10.1186/1476-4598-9-191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-4598-9-191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3098009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20626868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L., Ao Q., Zhang Q., Yang X., Xing H., Li F., Chen G., Zhou J., Wang S., Xu G., et al. Hypoxia induced paclitaxel resistance in human ovarian cancers via hypoxia-inducible factor 1&#x3b1;. J. Cancer Res. Clin. Oncol. 2010;136:447&#x2013;456. doi: 10.1007/s00432-009-0675-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00432-009-0675-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11828325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19760195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu K., Zhan Y., Yuan Z., Qiu Y., Wang H., Fan G., Wang J., Li W., Cao Y., Shen X., et al. Hypoxia Induces Drug Resistance in Colorectal Cancer through the HIF-1&#x3b1;/miR-338-5p/IL-6 Feedback Loop. Mol. Ther. 2019;27:1810&#x2013;1824. doi: 10.1016/j.ymthe.2019.05.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymthe.2019.05.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6822233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31208913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Bernauer A.M., Yingling C.M., Belinsky S.A. HIF1&#x3b1; regulated expression of XPA contributes to cisplatin resistance in lung cancer. Carcinogenesis. 2012;33:1187&#x2013;1192. doi: 10.1093/carcin/bgs142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/carcin/bgs142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3388491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22467238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncuzzi L., Pancotti F., Baldini N. Involvement of HIF-1&#x3b1; activation in the doxorubicin resistance of human osteosarcoma cells. Oncol. Rep. 2014;32:389&#x2013;394. doi: 10.3892/or.2014.3181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/or.2014.3181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24840054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua T., Wang R.-M., Zhang X.-C., Zhao B.-B., Fan S.-B., Liu D.-X., Wang W. ZNF76 predicts prognosis and response to platinum chemotherapy in human ovarian cancer. Biosci. Rep. 2021;41 doi: 10.1042/BSR20212026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/BSR20212026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8661506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34793589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi J.D., Kim T.J., Jeong B.C., Jeon H.G., Jeon S.S., Kang M.Y., Yeom S.Y., Seo S.I. ISL1 promotes enzalutamide resistance in castration-resistant prostate cancer (CRPC) through epithelial to mesenchymal transition (EMT) Sci. Rep. 2021;11 doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-01003-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-01003-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8578390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34753990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Wang L., Gao P., Sun Z., Li N., Lu Y., Shen J., Sun J., Yang Y., Dai H., Cai H. ISL1 promotes cancer progression and inhibits cisplatin sensitivity in triple-negative breast cancer cells. Int. J. Mol. Med. 2018;42:2343&#x2013;2352. doi: 10.3892/ijmm.2018.3842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijmm.2018.3842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6192754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30226569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J., Milligan J., Huang L.E. Molecular mechanism of hypoxia-inducible factor 1&#x3b1;-p300 interaction. A leucine-rich interface regulated by a single cysteine. J. Biol. Chem. 2001;276:3550&#x2013;3554. doi: 10.1074/JBC.M009522200/ASSET/7A138DC6-1652-4655-A943-50E5A6F969FA/MAIN.ASSETS/GR4.JPG.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/JBC.M009522200/ASSET/7A138DC6-1652-4655-A943-50E5A6F969FA/MAIN.ASSETS/GR4.JPG</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11063749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Z., Kang B., Li C., Chen T., Zhang Z. GEPIA2: an enhanced web server for large-scale expression profiling and interactive analysis. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47:W556&#x2013;W560. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkz430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkz430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31114875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gronkowska K., Robaszkiewicz A. Genetic dysregulation of EP300 in cancers in light of cancer epigenome control &#x2013; perspectives of specific targeting of p300 proficient and deficient cancers. Mol. Ther. Oncol. 2024;32 doi: 10.1016/J.OMTON.2024.200871/ASSET/FC0F14FC-216D-4F53-882F-A32A42F56E24/MAIN.ASSETS/GR5.JPG.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.OMTON.2024.200871/ASSET/FC0F14FC-216D-4F53-882F-A32A42F56E24/MAIN.ASSETS/GR5.JPG</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11440307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39351073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fekete J.T., Gy&#x151;rffy B. ROCplot.org: Validating predictive biomarkers of chemotherapy/hormonal therapy/anti-HER2 therapy using transcriptomic data of 3,104 breast cancer patients. Int. J. Cancer. 2019;145:3140&#x2013;3151. doi: 10.1002/IJC.32369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/IJC.32369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo Y., Oh J., Kim J.-S. Suppression of Nrf2 Activity by Chestnut Leaf Extract Increases Chemosensitivity of Breast Cancer Stem Cells to Paclitaxel. Nutrients. 2017;9 doi: 10.3390/nu9070760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9070760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28718813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K., Li M., Luo Z., Mao Y., Yu Y., He Y., Zhou J., Fei Y., Pei Y., Cai K. Overcoming the hypoxia-induced drug resistance in liver tumor by the concurrent use of apigenin and paclitaxel. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2020;526:321&#x2013;327. doi: 10.1016/j.bbrc.2020.03.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2020.03.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J., Li D.-W., Chen X.-W., Wang F., Dong P. Expression and significance of hypoxia-inducible factor-1&#x3b1; and MDR1/P-glycoprotein in laryngeal carcinoma tissue and hypoxic Hep-2 cells. Oncol. Lett. 2013;6:232&#x2013;238. doi: 10.3892/ol.2013.1321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ol.2013.1321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3742502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23946810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Ding Z., Peng Y., Pan F., Li J., Zou L., Zhang Y., Liang H. HIF-1&#x3b1; Inhibition Reverses Multidrug Resistance in Colon Cancer Cells via Downregulation of MDR1/P-Glycoprotein. PLoS One. 2014;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4047061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24901645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv Y., Zhao S., Han J., Zheng L., Yang Z., Zhao L. Hypoxia-inducible factor-1&#x3b1; induces multidrug resistance protein in colon cancer. OncoTargets Ther. 2015;8:1941&#x2013;1948. doi: 10.2147/OTT.S82835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OTT.S82835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4524588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26251616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doublier S., Belisario D.C., Polimeni M., Annaratone L., Riganti C., Allia E., Ghigo D., Bosia A., Sapino A. HIF-1 activation induces doxorubicin resistance in MCF7 3-D spheroids via P-glycoprotein expression: a potential model of the chemo-resistance of invasive micropapillary carcinoma of the breast. BMC Cancer. 2012;12:4. doi: 10.1186/1471-2407-12-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2407-12-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3262753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22217342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strachowska M., Gronkowska K., Sobczak M., Grodzicka M., Michlewska S., Ko&#x142;acz K., Sarkar T., Korszun J., Ionov M., Robaszkiewicz A. I-CBP112 declines overexpression of ATP-binding cassette transporters and sensitized drug-resistant MDA-MB-231 and A549 cell lines to chemotherapy drugs. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2023;168 doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2023.115798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.115798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37913733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galaxy Community The Galaxy platform for accessible, reproducible and collaborative biomedical analyses: 2022 update. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;50:W345&#x2013;W351. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkac247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkac247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9252830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35446428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amemiya H.M., Kundaje A., Boyle A.P. The ENCODE Blacklist: Identification of Problematic Regions of the Genome. Sci. Rep. 2019;9:9354. doi: 10.1038/s41598-019-45839-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-45839-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6597582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31249361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey T.L., Johnson J., Grant C.E., Noble W.S. The MEME Suite. Nucleic Acids Res. 2015;43:W39&#x2013;W49. doi: 10.1093/NAR/GKV416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/NAR/GKV416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25953851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman M.J., Craft B., Hastie M., Repe&#x10d;ka K., McDade F., Kamath A., Banerjee A., Luo Y., Rogers D., Brooks A.N., et al. Visualizing and interpreting cancer genomics data via the Xena platform. Nat. Biotechnol. 2020;38:675&#x2013;678. doi: 10.1038/s41587-020-0546-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41587-020-0546-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerami E., Gao J., Dogrusoz U., Gross B.E., Sumer S.O., Aksoy B.A., Jacobsen A., Byrne C.J., Heuer M.L., Larsson E., et al. The cBio cancer genomics portal: an open platform for exploring multidimensional cancer genomics data. Cancer Discov. 2012;2:401&#x2013;404. doi: 10.1158/2159-8290.CD-12-0095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/2159-8290.CD-12-0095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3956037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22588877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menyhart O., Kothalawala W.J., Gy&#x151;rffy B. A gene set enrichment analysis for the cancer hallmarks. J. Pharm. Anal. 2024;15 doi: 10.1016/J.JPHA.2024.101065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JPHA.2024.101065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12151186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40496069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobczak M., Strachowska M., Gronkowska K., Robaszkiewicz A. Activation of ABCC Genes by Cisplatin Depends on the CoREST Occurrence at Their Promoters in A549 and MDA-MB-231 Cell Lines. Cancers (Basel) 2022;14:894. doi: 10.3390/CANCERS14040894/S1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/CANCERS14040894/S1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8870433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35205642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wi&#x15b;nik E., P&#x142;oszaj T., Robaszkiewicz A. Downregulation of PARP1 transcription by promoter-associated E2F4-RBL2-HDAC1-BRM complex contributes to repression of pluripotency stem cell factors in human monocytes. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-10307-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-10307-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5572705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28842672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41018975</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2950-3299</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular therapy. Oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Ther Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epigenetic co-regulator HCF-1 promotes lung cancer via O-GlcNAcylation-dependent pathways.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>201046</StartPage><MedlinePgn>201046</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">201046</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201046</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rise in the incidences of lung cancer currently poses a global health challenge, making it crucial to understand the underlying molecular and cellular mechanisms. Host cell factor-1 (HCF-1), a conserved epigenetic transcriptional co-regulator, undergoes proteolytic maturation and glycosylation by O-linked N-acetylglucosamine (O-GlcNAc) transferase (OGT). Elevated O-GlcNAc and OGT levels have been observed in lung cancer, highlighting their potential significance in disease progression. In human lung cancer tissues, we observed a significant upregulation of HCF-1, which coincides with increased OGT, O-GlcNAc, and Nkx2.1 (a diagnostic marker for non-small cell lung cancer [NSCLSC]) levels. To further explore HCF-1's role mechanistically, we utilized the NSCLC cell lines, where HCF-1 depletion resulted in reduced proliferation, O-GlcNAcylation, Nkx2.1 expression, and O-GlcNAcylated proteins upon wheat germ agglutinin (WGA) pull-down, reinforcing its role in lung cancer progression. Additionally, Nkx2.1-mediated conditional knockout of HCF-1 impaired murine lung development and cell proliferation. Interestingly, OGT inhibition with OSMI-1 also reduced HCF-1, Nkx2.1 levels, and proliferation, suggesting a role for O-GlcNAcylation in HCF-1-mediated signaling cascades. Thus, our findings elucidate the critical role of HCF-1 and O-GlcNAcylation in lung cancer pathogenesis. These insights not only deepen our understanding of lung cancer pathogenesis but also identify potential molecular targets for studies aimed at intervention.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srivastava</LastName><ForeName>Priyanka P</ForeName><Initials>PP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kusuma School of Biological Sciences (KSBS), Indian Institute of Technology Delhi (IITD), Hauz Khas, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dasari</LastName><ForeName>Abhilash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemical Engineering and Biotechnology (DBEB), Indian Institute of Technology Delhi (IITD), Hauz Khas, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Saran</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kusuma School of Biological Sciences (KSBS), Indian Institute of Technology Delhi (IITD), Hauz Khas, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Ishaan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemical Engineering and Biotechnology (DBEB), Indian Institute of Technology Delhi (IITD), Hauz Khas, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>Deepali</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Ansari Nagar East, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minocha</LastName><ForeName>Shilpi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kusuma School of Biological Sciences (KSBS), Indian Institute of Technology Delhi (IITD), Hauz Khas, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Ther Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918752083706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2950-3299</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HCF-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MT: Regular Issue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NSCLC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nkx2.1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">O-GlcNAcylation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OGT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">host cell factor 1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung cancer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41018975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12475861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.omton.2025.201046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2950-3299(25)00115-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thai A.A., Solomon B.J., Sequist L.V., Gainor J.F., Heist R.S. Lung cancer. Lancet. 2021;398:535&#x2013;554. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00312-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00312-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferlay J., Colombet M., Soerjomataram I., Parkin D.M., Pi&#xf1;eros M., Znaor A., Bray F. Cancer statistics for the year 2020: An overview. Int. J. Cancer. 2021;149:778&#x2013;789. doi: 10.1002/ijc.33588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijc.33588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33818764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis W.D., Brambilla E., Nicholson A.G., Yatabe Y., Austin J.H.M., Beasley M.B., Chirieac L.R., Dacic S., Duhig E., Flieder D.B., et al. The 2015 World Health Organization Classification of Lung Tumors: Impact of Genetic, Clinical and Radiologic Advances since the 2004 Classification. J. Thorac. Oncol. 2015;10:1243&#x2013;1260. doi: 10.1097/JTO.0000000000000630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JTO.0000000000000630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26291008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones G.S., Baldwin D.R. Recent advances in the management of lung cancer. Clin. Med. 2018;18 s41&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6334032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29700092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zappa C., Mousa S.A. Non-small cell lung cancer: current treatment and future advances. Transl. Lung Cancer Res. 2016;5:288&#x2013;300. doi: 10.21037/TLCR.2016.06.07.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/TLCR.2016.06.07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4931124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27413711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araghi M., Mannani R., Heidarnejad maleki A., Hamidi A., Rostami S., Safa S.H., Faramarzi F., Khorasani S., Alimohammadi M., Tahmasebi S., Akhavan-Sigari R. Recent advances in non-small cell lung cancer targeted therapy; an update review. Cancer Cell Int. 2023;23:162. doi: 10.1186/s12935-023-02990-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12935-023-02990-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10416536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37568193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristie T.M., Pomerantz J.L., Twomey T.C., Parent S.A., Sharp P.A. The cellular C1 factor of the herpes simplex virus enhancer complex is a family of polypeptides. J. Biol. Chem. 1995;270:4387&#x2013;4394. doi: 10.1074/jbc.270.9.4387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.270.9.4387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7876203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristie T.M., Vogel J.L., Sears A.E. Nuclear localization of the C1 factor (host cell factor) in sensory neurons correlates with reactivation of herpes simplex virus from latency. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 1999;96:1229&#x2013;1233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC15445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9990006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wysocka J., Herr W. The herpes simplex virus VP16-induced complex: the makings of a regulatory switch. Trends Biochem. Sci. 2003;28:294&#x2013;304. doi: 10.1016/S0968-0004(03)00088-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0968-0004(03)00088-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12826401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wysocka J., Myers M.P., Laherty C.D., Eisenman R.N., Herr W. Human Sin3 deacetylase and trithorax-related Set1/Ash2 histone H3-K4 methyltransferase are tethered together selectively by the cell-proliferation factor HCF-1. Genes Dev. 2003;17:896&#x2013;911. doi: 10.1101/gad.252103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gad.252103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC196026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12670868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zargar Z., Tyagi S. Role of Host Cell Factor-1 in cell cycle regulation. Transcription. 2012;3:187&#x2013;192. doi: 10.4161/TRNS.20711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/TRNS.20711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3654768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22771988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minocha S., Sung T.L., Villeneuve D., Lammers F., Herr W. Compensatory embryonic response to allele-specific inactivation of the murine X-linked gene Hcfc1. Dev. Biol. 2016;412:1&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1016/j.ydbio.2016.02.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ydbio.2016.02.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26921005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minocha S., Bessonnard S., Sung T.L., Moret C., Constam D.B., Herr W. Epiblast-specific loss of HCF-1 leads to failure in anterior-posterior axis specification. Dev. Biol. 2016;418:75&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1016/j.ydbio.2016.08.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ydbio.2016.08.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27521049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minocha S., Villeneuve D., Praz V., Moret C., Lopes M., Pinatel D., Rib L., Guex N., Herr W. Rapid Recapitulation of Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis upon Loss of Host Cell Factor 1 Function in Mouse Hepatocytes. Mol. Cell Biol. 2019;39:e00405-18. doi: 10.1128/mcb.00405-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mcb.00405-18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6379584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30559308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minocha S., Herr W. Cortical and Commissural Defects Upon HCF-1 Loss in Nkx2.1-Derived Embryonic Neurons and Glia. Dev. Neurobiol. 2019;79:578&#x2013;595. doi: 10.1002/DNEU.22704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/DNEU.22704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6771735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31207118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minocha S., Villeneuve D., Rib L., Moret C., Guex N., Herr W. Segregated hepatocyte proliferation and metabolic states within the regenerating mouse liver. Hepatol. Commun. 2017;1:871&#x2013;885. doi: 10.1002/hep4.1102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep4.1102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5721458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29404499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capotosti F., Guernier S., Lammers F., Waridel P., Cai Y., Jin J., Conaway J.W., Conaway R.C., Herr W. O-GlcNAc transferase catalyzes site-specific proteolysis of HCF-1. Cell. 2011;144:376&#x2013;388. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2010.12.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2010.12.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21295698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julien E., Herr W. A switch in mitotic histone H4 lysine 20 methylation status is linked to M phase defects upon loss of HCF-1. Mol. Cell. 2004;14:713&#x2013;725. doi: 10.1016/j.molcel.2004.06.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2004.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15200950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly P.T., Herr W. Spontaneous reversion of tsBN67 cell proliferation and cytokinesis defects in the absence of HCF-1 function. Exp. Cell Res. 2002;277:119&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1006/excr.2002.5551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/excr.2002.5551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12061822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang P., Li F., Ma Z., Yue J., Lu C., You Y., Hou L., Yin B., Qiang B., Shu P., Peng X. HCF-1 promotes cell cycle progression by regulating the expression of CDC42. Cell Death Dis. 2020;11 doi: 10.1038/s41419-020-03094-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41419-020-03094-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7584624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33097698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julien E., Herr W. Proteolytic processing is necessary to separate and ensure proper cell growth and cytokinesis functions of HCF-1. EMBO J. 2003;22:2360&#x2013;2369. doi: 10.1093/emboj/cdg242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/emboj/cdg242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC156000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12743030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhuiyan T., Waridel P., Kapuria V., Zoete V., Herr W. Distinct OGT-Binding Sites Promote HCF-1 Cleavage. PLoS One. 2015;10 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0136636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0136636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4549301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26305326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapuria V., R&#xf6;hrig U.F., Bhuiyan T., Borodkin V.S., Van Aalten D.M.F., Zoete V., Herr W. Proteolysis of HCF-1 by Ser/Thr glycosylation-incompetent O-GlcNAc transferase:UDP-GlcNAc complexes. Genes Dev. 2016;30:960&#x2013;972. doi: 10.1101/gad.275925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gad.275925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4840301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27056667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daou S., Mashtalir N., Hammond-Martel I., Pak H., Yu H., Sui G., Vogel J.L., Kristie T.M., Affar E.B. Crosstalk between O-GlcNAcylation and proteolytic cleavage regulates the host cell factor-1 maturation pathway. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2011;108:2747&#x2013;2752. doi: 10.1073/PNAS.1013822108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/PNAS.1013822108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3041071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21285374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapuria V., R&#xf6; Hrig &#xa7; U.F., Waridel P., Lammers F., Borodkin V.S., Daan X., Van Aalten M.F., Zoete V., Herr W. The conserved threonine-rich region of the HCF-1 PRO repeat activates promiscuous OGT:UDP-GlcNAc glycosylation and proteolysis activities. J. Biol. Chem. 2018;293:17754&#x2013;17768. doi: 10.1074/jbc.RA118.004185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.RA118.004185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6240873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30224358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong D.-D., Feng Z.-B., Lai Z.-F., Qin Y., Liu L.-M., Fu H.-X., He R.-Q., Wu H.-Y., Dang Y.-W., Chen G., Luo D.Z. High throughput circRNA sequencing analysis reveals novel insights into the mechanism of nitidine chloride against hepatocellular carcinoma. Cell Death Dis. 2019;10 doi: 10.1038/s41419-019-1890-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41419-019-1890-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6737102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31506425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Yu M., Yang C., Li Q. Upregulation of HCFC1 expression promoted hepatocellular carcinoma progression through inhibiting cell cycle arrest and correlated with immune infiltration. J. Cancer. 2023;14:1381&#x2013;1397. doi: 10.7150/jca.84579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/jca.84579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10240668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37283799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popay T.M., Wang J., Adams C.M., Howard G.C., Codreanu S.G., Sherrod S.D., McLean J.A., Thomas L.R., Lorey S.L., Machida Y.J., et al. Myc regulates ribosome biogenesis and mitochondrial gene expression programs through its interaction with host cell factor&#x2013;1. eLife. 2021;10:e60191. doi: 10.7554/eLife.60191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.60191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7793627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33416496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker J.B., Palchaudhuri S., Yin H., Wei J., Chakravarti D. A Transcriptional Regulatory Role of the THAP11&#x2013;HCF-1 Complex in Colon Cancer Cell Function. Mol. Cell Biol. 2012;32:1654&#x2013;1670. doi: 10.1128/MCB.06033-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/MCB.06033-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3347244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22371484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K.H., Kim B.C., Jeong C.W., Ku J.H., Kim H.H., Kwak C. MLL5, a histone modifying enzyme, regulates androgen receptor activity in prostate cancer cells by recruiting co-regulators, HCF1 and SET1. BMB Rep. 2020;53:634&#x2013;639. doi: 10.5483/BMBRep.2020.53.12.162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5483/BMBRep.2020.53.12.162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7781910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33050986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus M.B., Jiang J., Kapuria V., Bhuiyan T., Janetzko J., Zandberg W.F., Vocadlo D.J., Herr W., Walker S. HCF-1 is cleaved in the active site of O-GlcNAc transferase. Science. 2013;342:1235&#x2013;1239. doi: 10.1126/science.1243990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1243990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3930058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24311690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi W., Gu Y., Han C., Liu H., Fan Q., Zhang X., Cong Q., Yu W. O-GlcNAcylation is a novel regulator of lung and colon cancer malignancy. Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2011;1812:514&#x2013;519. doi: 10.1016/j.bbadis.2011.01.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadis.2011.01.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21255644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S., Xia J., Yang Z., Xu M., Li S. Lung cancer molecular mutations and abnormal glycosylation as biomarkers for early diagnosis. Cancer Treat. Res. Commun. 2021;27 doi: 10.1016/j.ctarc.2021.100311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctarc.2021.100311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33465560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang K., Long Q., Liao Z., Zhang C., Jiang Z. Glycoproteomics revealed novel N-glycosylation biomarkers for early diagnosis of lung adenocarcinoma cancers. Clin. Proteomics. 2022;19:43. doi: 10.1186/s12014-022-09376-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12014-022-09376-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9675222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36401165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo K., Harada Y., Nakano M., Suzuki T., Fukushige T., Hanzawa K., Yagi H., Takagi K., Mizuno K., Miyamoto Y., et al. Identification of distinct N-glycosylation patterns on extracellular vesicles from small-cell and non-small-cell lung cancer cells. J. Biol. Chem. 2022;298 doi: 10.1016/j.jbc.2022.101950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbc.2022.101950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9117544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35447118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y.C., Lin C.H., Yeh Y.C., Ho H.L., Wu Y.C., Chen M.Y., Chou T.Y. High O-linked N-acetylglucosamine transferase expression predicts poor survival in patients with early stage lung adenocarcinoma. Oncotarget. 2018;9:31032&#x2013;31044. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.25772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.25772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6089550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson A.C., Parrish J.E., Massa H.F., Nelson D.L., Trask B.J., Herr W. The gene encoding the VP16-accessory protein HCF (HCFC1) resides in human Xq28 and is highly expressed in fetal tissues and the adult kidney. Genomics. 1995;25:462&#x2013;468. doi: 10.1016/0888-7543(95)80046-O.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0888-7543(95)80046-O</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7789979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mois&#xe9;s J., Navarro A., Santasusagna S., Vi&#xf1;olas N., Molins L., Ramirez J., Osorio J., Saco A., Castellano J.J., Mu&#xf1;oz C., et al. NKX2-1 expression as a prognostic marker in early-stage non-small-cell lung cancer. BMC Pulm. Med. 2017;17:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1186/s12890-017-0542-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-017-0542-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5727907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29237428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicke L., Schubert H.L., Hill C.P. Ubiquitin-binding domains. Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 2005;6:610&#x2013;621. doi: 10.1038/nrm1701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrm1701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16064137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Z., Yang J., Jiang H., Zhan X., Smokovski I., Tong Y., Peter Lucke-Wold B., Liang Y. The roles of protein ubiquitination in tumorigenesis and targeted drug discovery in lung cancer OPEN ACCESS EDITED BY Highlights. Frontiers in Endocrinology frontiersin.org Front. Endocrinol. 2023;14 doi: 10.3389/fendo.2023.1220108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1220108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10546409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37795365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder E.L., Watanabe H., Magendantz M., Hoersch S., Chen T.A., Wang D.G., Crowley D., Whittaker C.A., Meyerson M., Kimura S., Jacks T. Nkx2-1 Represses a Latent Gastric Differentiation Program in Lung Adenocarcinoma. Mol. Cell. 2013;50:185&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1016/j.molcel.2013.02.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2013.02.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23523371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julien E., Herr W. A Switch in Mitotic Histone H4 Lysine 20 Methylation Status Is Linked to M Phase Defects upon Loss of HCF-1. Mol. Cell. 2004;14:713&#x2013;725. doi: 10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2004.06.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2004.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15200950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyagi S., Chabes A.L., Wysocka J., Herr W. E2F Activation of S Phase Promoters via Association with HCF-1 and the MLL Family of Histone H3K4 Methyltransferases. Mol. Cell. 2007;27:107&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2007.05.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2007.05.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17612494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P.M., Wu T.C., Cheng Y.W., Chen C.Y., Lee H. NKX2-1-mediated p53 expression modulates lung adenocarcinoma progression via modulating IKK&#x3b2;/NF-&#x3ba;B activation. Oncotarget. 2015;6:14274&#x2013;14289. doi: 10.18632/ONCOTARGET.3695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/ONCOTARGET.3695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4546466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25881545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu Y.F., Wang X.C., Chen Y., Wang J.Y., Liu X., Li X., Li C.W., Xie Y.C., Luo Y., Shang X.Q., Guo J. Thyroid transcription factor 1 represses the expression of Ki-67 and induces apoptosis in non-small cell lung cancer. Oncol. Rep. 2012;28:1544&#x2013;1550. https://www.spandidos-publications.com/10.3892/or.2012.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/or.2012.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3583567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22940844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastromarino M.G., Parini S., Azzolina D., Habib S., De Marni M.L., Luise C., Restelli S., Baietto G., Trisolini E., Massera F., et al. Liquid Biopsy Detecting Circulating Tumor Cells in Patients with Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer: Preliminary Results of a Pilot Study. Biomedicines. 2023;11 doi: 10.3390/BIOMEDICINES11010153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/BIOMEDICINES11010153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9855397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36672660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon T.Y.Y., Ngan E.S.W., Poon H.C., So M.T., Lui V.C.H., Tam P.K.H., Garcia-Barcelo M.M. Transcriptional regulation of RET by Nkx2-1, Phox2b, Sox10, and Pax3. J. Pediatr. Surg. 2009;44:1904&#x2013;1912. doi: 10.1016/J.JPEDSURG.2008.11.055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JPEDSURG.2008.11.055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19853745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du H., Chen Y., Hou X., Huang Y., Wei X., Yu X., Feng S., Wu Y., Zhan M., Shi X., et al. Plod2 regulated by transcription factor foxa1 promotes metastasis in nsclc. Cell Death Dis. 2017;8:e3143. doi: 10.1038/cddis.2017.553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cddis.2017.553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5680920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29072684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong Y., Qi Y., Xiong G., Li J., Scott T.L., Chen J., He D., Li L., Wang C., Lane A.N., Xu R. The PLOD2/succinate axis regulates the epithelial&#x2013;mesenchymal plasticity and cancer cell stemness. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2023;120 doi: 10.1073/pnas.2214942120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2214942120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10194013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37155842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji X., Qian J., Rahman S.M.J., Siska P.J., Zou Y., Harris B.K., Hoeksema M.D., Trenary I.A., Heidi C., Eisenberg R., et al. xCT (SLC7A11)-mediated metabolic reprogramming promotes non-small cell lung cancer progression. Oncogene. 2018;37:5007&#x2013;5019. doi: 10.1038/s41388-018-0307-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41388-018-0307-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6127081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29789716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumardika I.W., Chen Y., Tomonobu N., Kinoshita R., Ruma I.M.W., Sato H., Kondo E., Inoue Y., Yamauchi A., Murata H., et al. Neuroplastin-&#x3b2; mediates S100A8/A9-induced lung cancer disseminative progression. Mol. Carcinog. 2019;58:980&#x2013;995. doi: 10.1002/mc.22987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mc.22987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30720226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Lu Q., Cai J., Wang Y., Lai X., Qiu Y., Huang Y., Ke Q., Zhang Y., Guan Y., et al. Nestin regulates cellular redox homeostasis in lung cancer through the Keap1&#x2013;Nrf2 feedback loop. Nat. Commun. 2019;10 doi: 10.1038/s41467-019-12925-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-12925-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6834667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31695040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E.Y., Cha Y.J., Jeong S., Chang Y.S. Overexpression of CEACAM6 activates Src-FAK signaling and inhibits anoikis, through homophilic interactions in lung adenocarcinomas. Transl. Oncol. 2022;20 doi: 10.1016/j.tranon.2022.101402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranon.2022.101402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8968058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35358791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonias S.L., Karimi-Mostowfi N., Murray S.S., Mantuano E., Gilder A.S. Expression of LDL receptor-related proteins (LRPs) in common solid malignancies correlates with patient survival. PLoS One. 2017;12 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0186649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0186649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5663383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29088295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H., Liu H., Wen J., Yuan T., Ren G., Jiang Y., Yuan Y., Mei J., Yu Y., Li G. Overexpression of Human Aspartyl (Asparaginyl) &#x3b2;-hydroxylase in NSCLC: Its Diagnostic Value by Means of Exosomes of Bronchoalveolar Lavage. Appl. Immunohistochem. Mol. Morphol. 2021;29:720&#x2013;727. doi: 10.1097/PAI.0000000000000963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PAI.0000000000000963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34433181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B.-W., Sun N., Lin H., Zhou X.-J., Ma H.-Y., Wang X., Cao X.-C., Yu Y. ARTICLE The p53/ZEB1-PLD3 feedback loop regulates cell proliferation in breast cancer. Cell Death Dis. 2023;14 doi: 10.1038/s41419-023-06271-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41419-023-06271-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10656518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37978168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai C., Dang W., Liu S., Huang L., Li Y., Li G., Yan S., Jiang C., Song X., Hu Y., Gu J. Anthrax toxin receptor 1/tumor endothelial marker 8 promotes gastric cancer progression through activation of the PI3K/AKT/mTOR signaling pathway. Cancer Sci. 2020;111:1132&#x2013;1145. doi: 10.1111/cas.14326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cas.14326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31977138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y.H., Kim D., Jin E.J. Down-regulation of Phospholipase D Stimulates Death of Lung Cancer Cells Involving Up-regulation of the Long ncRNA ANRIL. Anticancer Res. 2015;35:2795&#x2013;2803. https://ar.iiarjournals.org/content/35/5/2795.long</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25964559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salucci S., Aramini B., Bartoletti-Stella A., Versari I., Martinelli G., Blalock W., Stella F., Faenza I. Phospholipase Family Enzymes in Lung Cancer: Looking for Novel Therapeutic Approaches. Cancers (Basel) 2023;15:3245. doi: 10.3390/cancers15123245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers15123245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10296511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37370855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J., Liu Y., Xie B., Ye P., Huang J., Lu Z. Roles of toll-like receptors: From inflammation to lung cancer progression. Biomed. Rep. 2018;8:126&#x2013;132. doi: 10.3892/br.2017.1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/br.2017.1034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5778860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29435270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoden B., DeRubeis D., Martinez-Moczygemba M., Ramos K.S., Zhang D. Understanding the role of Toll-like receptors in lung cancer immunity and immunotherapy. Front. Immunol. 2022;13 doi: 10.3389/FIMMU.2022.1033483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/FIMMU.2022.1033483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9659925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36389785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Zhang X., Shi Y., Ni Y., Fei J., Jin Z., Li W., Wang X., Wu N. Role and potential therapeutic value of histone methyltransferases in drug resistance mechanisms in lung cancer. Front. Oncol. 2024;14 doi: 10.3389/FONC.2024.1376916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/FONC.2024.1376916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10957659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38525426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz-Meoz R.F., Jiang J., Lazarus M.B., Orman M., Janetzko J., Fan C., Duveau D.Y., Tan Z.-W., Thomas C.J., Walker S. A Small Molecule That Inhibits OGT Activity in Cells. ACS Chem. Biol. 2015;10:1392&#x2013;1397. doi: 10.1021/acschembio.5b00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acschembio.5b00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4475500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25751766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barkovskaya A., Seip K., Prasmickaite L., Mills I.G., Moestue S.A., Itkonen H.M. Inhibition of O-GlcNAc transferase activates tumor-suppressor gene expression in tamoxifen-resistant breast cancer cells. Sci. Rep. 2020;10 doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-74083-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-74083-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7552408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33046784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q., Tam M., Anderson S.A. Fate mapping Nkx2.1-lineage cells in the mouse telencephalon. J. Comp. Neurol. 2008;506:16&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1002/cne.21529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.21529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17990269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiozzo C., De Langhe S., Yu M., Londhe V.A., Carraro G., Li M., Li C., Xing Y., Anderson S., Borok Z., et al. Deletion of Pten expands lung epithelial progenitor pools and confers resistance to airway injury. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2009;180:701&#x2013;712. doi: 10.1164/rccm.200901-0100OC.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200901-0100OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2778148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19574443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoyama M., Ozaki T., Inuzuka H., Tomotsune D., Hirato J., Okamoto Y., Tokita H., Ohira M., Nakagawara A. LMO3 Interacts with Neuronal Transcription Factor, HEN2, and Acts as an Oncogene in Neuroblastoma. Cancer Res. 2005;65:4587&#x2013;4597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15930276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y.-F., Hong J.-F., Liu D.-L., Lin Q.-A., Lan X.-P., Lai G.-X. miR-630 targets LMO3 to regulate cell growth and metastasis in lung cancer. Am. J. Transl. Res. 2015;7:1271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4548319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26328011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y., Hou T., Ping J., Chen T., Yin B. LMO3 promotes hepatocellular carcinoma invasion, metastasis and anoikis inhibition by directly interacting with LATS1 and suppressing Hippo signaling 06 Biological Sciences 0601 Biochemistry and Cell Biology. J. Exp. Clin. Cancer Res. 2018;37 doi: 10.1186/s13046-018-0903-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13046-018-0903-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6139164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30219064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang J., Song Q., Yang Z., Li D., Chen W., Luo L., Wang Y., Yang J., Li S. Identification of lung adenocarcinoma specific dysregulated genes with diagnostic and prognostic value across 27 TCGA cancer types. Oncotarget. 2017;8:87292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5675633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29152081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Ji W., Yu Y., Li Z., Niu X., Xia W., Lu S. FGFR1-ERK1/2-SOX2 axis promotes cell proliferation, epithelial&#x2013;mesenchymal transition, and metastasis in FGFR1-amplified lung cancer. Oncogene. 2018;37:5340&#x2013;5354. doi: 10.1038/s41388-018-0311-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41388-018-0311-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29858603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu T., Li Z., Yang Y., Ji W., Yu Y., Niu X., Zeng Q., Xia W., Lu S. The Hippo/YAP1 pathway interacts with FGFR1 signaling to maintain stemness in lung cancer. Cancer Lett. 2018;423:36&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1016/J.CANLET.2018.02.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CANLET.2018.02.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29452146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintanal-Villalonga &#xc1;., Ferrer I., Guruceaga E., Cirauqui C., Marrugal &#xc1;., Ojeda L., Garc&#xed;a S., Zugazagoitia J., Mu&#xf1;oz-Galv&#xe1;n S., Lopez-Rios F., et al. FGFR1 and FGFR4 oncogenicity depends on n-cadherin and their co-expression may predict FGFR-targeted therapy efficacy. EBioMedicine. 2020;53 doi: 10.1016/j.ebiom.2020.102683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2020.102683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7047190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32114392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>XIE Y., NAIZABEKOV S., CHEN Z., TOKAY T. Power of PTEN/AKT: Molecular switch between tumor suppressors and oncogenes. Oncol. Lett. 2016;12:375&#x2013;378. doi: 10.3892/ol.2016.4636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ol.2016.4636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4906924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S., Allis C.D., Wang G.G. The language of chromatin modification in human cancers. Nat. Rev. Cancer. 2021;21:413&#x2013;430. doi: 10.1038/S41568-021-00357-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/S41568-021-00357-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10507815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34002060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel J.L., Kristie T.M. The Dynamics of HCF-1 Modulation of Herpes Simplex Virus Chromatin during Initiation of Infection. Viruses. 2013;5:1272&#x2013;1291. doi: 10.3390/V5051272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/V5051272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3712308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23698399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane E.A., Choi D.W., Garcia-Haro L., Levine Z.G., Tedoldi M., Walker S., Danial N.N. HCF-1 Regulates De Novo Lipogenesis through a Nutrient-Sensitive Complex with ChREBP. Mol. Cell. 2019;75:357&#x2013;371.e7. doi: 10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2019.05.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.MOLCEL.2019.05.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6744259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31227231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P., Wang Z., Yuan X., Zhou C., Liu L., Wan X., Zhang F., Ding X., Wang C., Xiong S., et al. Mixed Lineage Leukemia 5 (MLL5) Protein Regulates Cell Cycle Progression and E2F1-responsive Gene Expression via Association with Host Cell Factor-1 (HCF-1) J. Biol. Chem. 2013;288:17532&#x2013;17543. doi: 10.1074/JBC.M112.439729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/JBC.M112.439729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3682552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23629655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristie T.M., Liang Y., Vogel J.L. Control of &#x3b1;-herpesvirus IE gene expression by HCF-1 coupled chromatin modification activities. Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2010;1799:257&#x2013;265. doi: 10.1016/J.BBAGRM.2009.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.BBAGRM.2009.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19682612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang T., Wang Y., Zhou F., Gao G., Ren S., Zhou C. Prognostic value of high EZH2 expression in patients with different types of cancer: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Oncotarget. 2016;7:4584&#x2013;4597. doi: 10.18632/ONCOTARGET.6612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/ONCOTARGET.6612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4826228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26683709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajbouj K., Al-ali A., Ramakrishnan R.K., Saber-ayad M., Hamid Q. Histone Modification in NSCLC: Molecular Mechanisms and Therapeutic Targets. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021;22 doi: 10.3390/IJMS222111701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/IJMS222111701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8584007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramazi S., Dadzadi M., Sahafnejad Z., Allahverdi A. Epigenetic regulation in lung cancer. MedComm. 2023;4 doi: 10.1002/MCO2.401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/MCO2.401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10600507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37901797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onishi T., Takashima T., Kurashige M., Ohshima K., Morii E. Mutually exclusive expression of EZH2 and H3K27me3 in non-small cell lung carcinoma. Pathol. Res. Pract. 2022;238 doi: 10.1016/J.PRP.2022.154071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.PRP.2022.154071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35985089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Song N., Matsumoto K., Nanashima A., Nagayasu T., Hayashi T., Ying M., Endo D., Wu Z., Koji T. High expression of trimethylated histone H3 at lysine 27 predicts better prognosis in non-small cell lung cancer. Int. J. Oncol. 2013;43:1467&#x2013;1480. doi: 10.3892/ijo.2013.2062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijo.2013.2062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23969945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zheng B., Lou K., Xu X., Xu Y. Methylation patterns of Lys9 and Lys27 on histone H3 correlate with patient outcome and tumor progression in lung cancer. Ann. Diagn. Pathol. 2022;61 doi: 10.1016/j.anndiagpath.2022.152045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anndiagpath.2022.152045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36115104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat K.P., &#xdc;mit Kaniskan H., Jin J., Gozani O. Epigenetics and beyond: targeting writers of protein lysine methylation to treat disease. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 2021;20:265&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1038/s41573-020-00108-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41573-020-00108-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8035164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33469207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari J., Shackelford R.E., El-Osta H. Epigenetics in non-small cell lung cancer: from basics to therapeutics. Transl. Lung Cancer Res. 2016;5:155&#x2013;171. doi: 10.21037/TLCR.2016.02.02.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/TLCR.2016.02.02</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4858572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27186511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrer C.M., Sodi V.L., Reginato M.J. O-GlcNAcylation in Cancer Biology: Linking Metabolism and Signaling. J. Mol. Biol. 2016;428:3282&#x2013;3294. doi: 10.1016/j.jmb.2016.05.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmb.2016.05.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4983259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27343361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szymura S.J., Zaemes J.P., Allison D.F., Clift S.H., D&#x2019;innocenzi J.M., Gray L.G., Mckenna B.D., Morris B.B., Bekiranov S., Legallo R.D., et al. NF-&#x3ba;B upregulates glutamine-fructose-6-phosphate transaminase 2 to promote migration in non-small cell lung cancer. Cell Commun. Signal. 2019;17 doi: 10.1186/s12964-019-0335-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12964-019-0335-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6421657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30885209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Wang J., Xiang Y., Wang K., Yan D., Tong Y. The roles of OGT and its mechanisms in cancer. Cell Biosci. 2024:121. doi: 10.1186/S13578-024-01301-W.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/S13578-024-01301-W</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11406787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39285476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Minh G., Esquea E.M., Young R.G., Huang J., Reginato M.J. On a sugar high: Role of O-GlcNAcylation in cancer. J. Biol. Chem. 2023;299 doi: 10.1016/J.JBC.2023.105344/ASSET/889AB41F-DE26-4B9D-A31B-F276A22F2A34/MAIN.ASSETS/GR2.JPG.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JBC.2023.105344/ASSET/889AB41F-DE26-4B9D-A31B-F276A22F2A34/MAIN.ASSETS/GR2.JPG</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10641670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37838167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capotosti F., Guernier S., Lammers F., Waridel P., Cai Y., Jin J., Conaway J.W., Conaway R.C., Herr W. O-GlcNAc Transferase Catalyzes Site-Specific Proteolysis of HCF-1. Cell. 2011;144:376&#x2013;388. doi: 10.1016/J.CELL.2010.12.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CELL.2010.12.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21295698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh J.P., Zhang K., Wu J., Yang X. O-GlcNAc Signaling in Cancer Metabolism and Epigenetics. Cancer Lett. 2015;356:244&#x2013;250. doi: 10.1016/J.CANLET.2014.04.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CANLET.2014.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24769077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H., Yanagisawa K., Shinjo K., Taguchi A., Maeno K., Tomida S., Shimada Y., Osada H., Kosaka T., Matsubara H., et al. Lineage-Specific Dependency of Lung Adenocarcinomas on the Lung Development Regulator TTF-1. Cancer Res. 2007;67:6007&#x2013;6011. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-06-4774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-06-4774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17616654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herriges M., Morrisey E.E. Lung development: Orchestrating the generation and regeneration of a complex organ. Development. 2014;141:502&#x2013;513. doi: 10.1242/dev.098186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/dev.098186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3899811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24449833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Z., Kang B., Li C., Chen T., Zhang Z. GEPIA2: an enhanced web server for large-scale expression profiling and interactive analysis. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47:W556&#x2013;W560. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkz430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkz430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31114875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guinez C., Filhoulaud G., Rayah-Benhamed F., Marmier S., Dubuquoy C., Dentin R., Moldes M., Burnol A.F., Yang X., Lefebvre T., et al. O-GlcNAcylation increases ChREBP protein content and transcriptional activity in the liver. Diabetes. 2011;60:1399&#x2013;1413. doi: 10.2337/db10-0452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db10-0452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3292313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21471514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">40865895</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-0183</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Autoimmunity reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Autoimmun Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Animal models for connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease: Current status and future directions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103919</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103919</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.autrev.2025.103919</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1568-9972(25)00180-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Interstitial lung disease (ILD) significantly contributes to connective tissue disease (CTD) mortality. Although guidelines for managing CTD-associated ILD (CTD-ILD) exist, many patients respond poorly to treatment owing to two key factors: (1) incomplete understanding of subtype-specific pathogenic mechanisms, and (2) reliance on therapies adapted from systemic sclerosis or nonpulmonary rheumatic diseases, which fail to address the unique pathophysiology of distinct CTD-ILD subtypes. This hinders personalized treatment and underscores the need for robust preclinical models that accurately replicate disease-specific mechanisms. However, challenges remain: (1) the lack of models that fully capture the heterogeneity of these disorders and (2) the absence of systematic structured reviews to guide model selection, despite recent advancements in experimental methodologies. These issues often result in mismatches between research goals and model utility. This review summarizes current CTD-ILD animal models, focusing on their construction, characteristics, and limitations, and highlighting differences between each model and the corresponding human disease. We summarize these disparities and propose emerging technologies, including CRISPR/Cas9-mediated genome editing, humanized mice, and lung organoids/lung-on-a-chip systems, that may facilitate the development of next-generation models. By integrating established and emerging strategies, we aim to provide guidance for model selection and development, promote precision modeling, accelerate targeted therapy discovery, and ultimately improve clinical outcomes. We emphasize the importance of developing subtype-specific models to avoid a "one-model-fits-all" approach.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Ziyi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; Laboratory of Rheumatology and Immunology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610093, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Hang</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Xiuping</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; Laboratory of Rheumatology and Immunology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610093, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jiehao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Animal Laboratory Center, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610213, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Dezhi</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; Laboratory of Rheumatology and Immunology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610093, China; West China Lecheng Hospital, Sichuan University, Boao, Hainan 571435, China. Electronic address: yiliu8999@wchscu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Autoimmun Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101128967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1568-9972</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017563" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Diseases, Interstitial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003240" MajorTopicYN="Y">Connective Tissue Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Animal models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Connective tissue disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interstitial lung disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Methods</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40865895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2025.103919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1568-9972(25)00180-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40876558</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-0183</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Autoimmunity reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Autoimmun Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Updated systematic literature review and meta-analysis to inform the Italian Society of Rheumatology Recommendations on the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103922</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103922</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.autrev.2025.103922</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1568-9972(25)00183-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease (RA-ILD) is a severe extra-articular manifestation of rheumatoid arthritis (RA). Despite recent guideline initiatives, no treatment recommendations specifically tailored to RA-ILD have been developed in Italy. This systematic literature review (SLR) and meta-analysis was conducted to inform the Italian Society of Rheumatology (SIR) national recommendations for the management of RA-ILD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">we conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of studies evaluating pharmacological interventions for RA-ILD from inception up to October 2023, followed by an update up to April 2025, with a pre-defined protocol. Eligible studies included randomized controlled trials, cohort studies, and case series reporting pulmonary function outcomes, radiological progression, adverse events, and mortality. Meta-analyses were performed, and heterogeneity and publication bias were thoroughly assessed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">sixty-nine studies encompassing 7879 RA-ILD patients were included. Treatments with conventional synthetic disease modifying anti-rheumatic drugs (csDMARDs), rituximab (RTX), mycophenolate mofetil (MMF), abatacept (ABA), and Janus kinase inhibitors (JAKi) were associated with stabilization or improvement of forced vital capacity (FVC). Methotrexate (MTX) was associated with reduced risk of ILD progression and mortality. Antifibrotics, particularly nintedanib, demonstrated variable efficacy, while pirfenidone showed limited benefit. Safety profiles favored antifibrotics over csDMARDs/immunosuppressants regarding serious adverse events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">this SLR provides an updated synthesis of evidence on RA-ILD treatments, supporting the forthcoming SIR recommendations. Despite inherent limitations of observational studies and heterogeneity, the data highlight the safety of MTX and particularly support ABA, RTX, and nintedanib as promising options, while underscoring the need for further high-quality trials specifically in RA-ILD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fassio</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, University of Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sebastiani</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Parma, Parma, Italy; Rheumatology Unit, AUSL Piacenza, Piacenza, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pollastri</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, University of Verona, Italy. Electronic address: franpollastri@yahoo.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cozzini</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Parma, Parma, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crotti</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bone Disease Unit, Department of Rheumatology and Medical Science, ASST-G.Pini-CTO, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ughi</LastName><ForeName>N</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Multispecialist Medical Department, ASST Grande Ospedale Metropolitano Niguarda, Milan, Italy; Epidemiology Research Unit, Societ&#xe0; Italiana di Reumatologia, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Lorenzis</LastName><ForeName>E</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aging Diseases, Orthopedic and Rheumatology, Rheumatology Division, Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Agostino Gemelli IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mancuso</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, Department of Clinical, Internal, Anaesthesiologic and Cardiovascular, Sciences, Sapienza University of Rome, Viale del Policlinico 155, 00161 Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Radin</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology and Dialysis Unit and Center of Immuno-Rheumatology and Rare Diseases (CMID), Coordinating Center of the Interregional Network for Rare Diseases of Piedmont and Aosta Valley, San Giovanni Bosco Hub Hospital ASL Citt&#xe0; di Torino and Department of Clinical and Biological Sciences, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carrara</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology Research Unit, Societ&#xe0; Italiana di Reumatologia, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Landolfi</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology Research Unit, Societ&#xe0; Italiana di Reumatologia, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rozza</LastName><ForeName>D</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology Research Unit, Societ&#xe0; Italiana di Reumatologia, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manfredi</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, Italy; Rheumatology Unit, AUSL-IRCCS Reggio Emilia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Autoimmun Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101128967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1568-9972</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018501">Antirheumatic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthritis, Rheumatoid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017563" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Diseases, Interstitial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018501" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antirheumatic Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007558" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Italy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012219" MajorTopicYN="N">Rheumatology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017410" MajorTopicYN="N">Practice Guidelines as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interstitial lung disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Italian recommendations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metanalysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rheumatoid arthritis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper. Professor Marco Sebastiani has received consultancy fees, and/or speaker fees from Boehringer Ingelheim, outside the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40876558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2025.103922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1568-9972(25)00183-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>