<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41417666</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-0237</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of thoracic imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Thorac Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Quantitative CT and Artificial Intelligence in Chronic Lung Disease.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000867</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Computed tomography (CT) is routinely used in diagnosing and managing patients with chronic lung diseases such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and fibrosing interstitial lung disease (ILD). Visual assessment of disease morphology/phenotype and extent correlates with lung function and patient prognosis, but it is limited by reader subjectivity and interobserver variability. Quantitative CT (QCT) techniques based on density and texture-based features of the lungs have shown stronger correlations with physiologic and survival outcomes in both COPD and ILD cohort studies. Moreover, recent advances in computer processing capabilities have led to the implementation of machine and deep learning-based approaches, allowing for greater robustness and reproducibility beyond visual assessment and density-based methods. This review focuses on QCT and artificial intelligence (AI) techniques for COPD, ILD, and bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome in lung and hematopoietic stem cell transplant recipients. Current challenges and limitations for adoption of these techniques and future directions of QCT and AI in thoracic imaging are also discussed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Andrea S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8212-524</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Humphries</LastName><ForeName>Stephen M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, National Jewish Health, Denver, CO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Augustine</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, Allergy, and Immunology, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weigt</LastName><ForeName>S Samuel</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, Allergy, and Immunology, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Grace Hyun J</ForeName><Initials>GHJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belperio</LastName><ForeName>John A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, Allergy, and Immunology, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldin</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Thorac Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8606160</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0883-5993</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interstitial lung disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative CT</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>S.M.H. reports grants or contracts from NHLBI, Boehringer Ingelheim Pharmaceuticals and Perceptive, and US Patents 10,706,533; 11,4685,64; 11,494,902 and 11,922,626 (unlicensed and assigned to my institution). A.C. reports salary support from Boehringer Ingelheim Pharmaceuticals. M.B. is a board member of Voiant Clinical, LLC. GHK reports grant support from Boehringer Ingelheim Pharmaceuticals. The remaining authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41417666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005382-990000000-00206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kessler LG, Barnhart HX, Buckler AJ, et al. The emerging science of quantitative imaging biomarkers terminology and definitions for scientific studies and regulatory submissions. Stat Methods Med Res. 2015;24:9&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank Country and Lending Groups&#x2014;World Bank Data Help Desk. Accessed May 25, 2025. https://datahelpdesk.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/906519-world-bank-country-and-lending-groups</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogelmeier CF, Criner GJ, Martinez FJ, et al. Global Strategy for the Diagnosis, Management, and Prevention of Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease 2017 Report. GOLD Executive Summary. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017;195:557&#x2013;582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch DA, Al-Qaisi ML. Quantitative CT in COPD. J Thorac Imaging. 2013;28:284&#x2013;290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>San Jos&#xe9; Est&#xe9;par R, Barr RG, Fain SB, et al. The use of CT densitometry for the assessment of emphysema in clinical trials: a position paper from the Fleischner Society. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2025;211:709&#x2013;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baraghoshi D, Strand M, Humphries SM, et al. Quantitative CT evaluation of emphysema progression over 10 years in the COPDGene study. Radiology. 2023;307:e222786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash SY, Est&#xe9;par RSJ, Fain SB, et al. Relationship between emphysema progression at CT and mortality in ever-smokers: results from the COPDGene and ECLIPSE cohorts. Radiology. 2021;299:222&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieren JP, Newell JD, Barr RG, et al. SPIROMICS protocol for multicenter quantitative computed tomography to phenotype the lungs. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2016;194:794&#x2013;806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller NL, Staples CA, Miller RR, et al. &#x201c;Density Mask&#x201d;: an objective method to quantitate emphysema using computed tomography. Chest. 1988;94:782&#x2013;787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heussel CP, Herth FJF, Kappes J, et al. Fully automatic quantitative assessment of emphysema in computed tomography: comparison with pulmonary function testing and normal values. Eur Radiol. 2009;19:2391&#x2013;2402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gevenois PA, de Maertelaer V, De Vuyst P, et al. Comparison of computed density and macroscopic morphometry in pulmonary emphysema. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1995;152:653&#x2013;657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parr DG, Stoel BC, Stolk J, et al. Pattern of emphysema distribution in &#x3b1;1-antitrypsin deficiency influences lung function impairment. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2004;170:1172&#x2013;1178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaker SB, Dirksen A, Laursen LC, et al. Volume adjustment of lung density by computed tomography scans in patients with emphysema. Acta Radiol Stockh Swed 1987. 2004;45:417&#x2013;423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishima M, Hirai T, Itoh H, et al. Complexity of terminal airspace geometry assessed by lung computed tomography in normal subjects and patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1999;96:8829&#x2013;8834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madani A, Van Muylem A, de Maertelaer V, et al. Pulmonary emphysema: size distribution of emphysematous spaces on multidetector CT images&#x2014;comparison with macroscopic and microscopic morphometry. Radiology. 2008;248:1036&#x2013;1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu K, Tanabe N, Tho NV, et al. Per cent low attenuation volume and fractal dimension of low attenuation clusters on CT predict different long-term outcomes in COPD. Thorax. 2020;75:116&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virdee S, Tan WC, Hogg JC, et al. Spatial dependence of CT emphysema in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease quantified by using join-count statistics. Radiology. 2021;301:702&#x2013;709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busacker A, Newell JD, Keefe T, et al. A multivariate analysis of risk factors for the air-trapping asthmatic phenotype as measured by quantitative CT analysis. Chest. 2009;135:48&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy K, Pluim JPW, van Rikxoort EM, et al. Toward automatic regional analysis of pulmonary function using inspiration and expiration thoracic CT. Med Phys. 2012;39:1650&#x2013;1662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder JD, McKenzie AS, Zach JA, et al. Relationships between airflow obstruction and quantitative CT measurements of emphysema, air trapping, and airways in subjects with and without chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Roentgenol. 2013;201:W460&#x2013;W470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuoka S, Kurihara Y, Yagihashi K, et al. Quantitative assessment of peripheral airway obstruction on paired expiratory/inspiratory thin-section computed tomography in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease with emphysema. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 2007;31:384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Eda S, Yamamoto H, et al. Expiratory and inspiratory chest computed tomography and pulmonary function tests in cigarette smokers. Eur Respir J. 1999;13:252&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashiro T, Matsuoka S, Bartholmai BJ, et al. Collapsibility of lung volume by paired inspiratory and expiratory CT scans: correlations with lung function and mean lung density. Acad Radiol. 2010;17:489&#x2013;495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nambu A, Zach J, Schroeder J, et al. Relationships between diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO), and quantitative computed tomography measurements and visual assessment for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Eur J Radiol. 2015;84:980&#x2013;985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mets OM, Zanen P, Lammers JWJ, et al. Early identification of small airways disease on lung cancer screening CT: comparison of current air trapping measures. Lung. 2012;190:629&#x2013;633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pompe E, Strand M, van Rikxoort EM, et al. Five-year progression of emphysema and air trapping at CT in smokers with and those without chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: results from the COPDGene study. Radiology. 2020;295:218&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galb&#xe1;n CJ, Han MK, Boes JL, et al. Computed tomography-based biomarker provides unique signature for diagnosis of COPD phenotypes and disease progression. Nat Med. 2012;18:1711&#x2013;1715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pompe E, van Rikxoort EM, Schmidt M, et al. Parametric response mapping adds value to current computed tomography biomarkers in diagnosing chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2015;191:1084&#x2013;1086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labaki WW, Gu T, Murray S, et al. Voxel-wise longitudinal parametric response mapping analysis of chest computed tomography in smokers. Acad Radiol. 2019;26:306&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JM, Bell AJ, Ram S, et al. Topologic parametric response mapping identifies tissue subtypes associated with emphysema progression. Acad Radiol. 2024;31:1148&#x2013;1159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho TT, Kim T, Kim WJ, et al. A 3D-CNN model with CT-based parametric response mapping for classifying COPD subjects. Sci Rep. 2021;11:34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Liu Z, Lu J, et al. Deep learning parametric response mapping from inspiratory chest CT scans: a new approach for small airway disease screening. Respir Res. 2023;24:299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasenstab KA, Tabalon J, Yuan N, et al. CNN-based deformable registration facilitates fast and accurate air trapping measurements at inspiratory and expiratory CT. Radiol Artif Intell. 2022;4:e210211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasenstab KA, Yuan N, Retson T, et al. Automated CT staging of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease severity for predicting disease progression and mortality with a deep learning convolutional neural network. Radiol Cardiothorac Imaging. 2021;3:e200477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonough JE, Yuan R, Suzuki M, et al. Small-airway obstruction and emphysema in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. N Engl J Med. 2011;365:1567&#x2013;1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano Y, Wong JC, de Jong PA, et al. The prediction of small airway dimensions using computed tomography. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2005;171:142&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washko GR, Dransfield MT, Est&#xe9;par RSJ, et al. Airway wall attenuation: a biomarker of airway disease in subjects with COPD. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:185&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han MK, Kazerooni EA, Lynch DA, et al. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbations in the COPDGene study: associated radiologic phenotypes. Radiology. 2011;261:274&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mair G, Maclay J, Miller JJ, et al. Airway dimensions in COPD: relationships with clinical variables. Respir Med. 2010;104:1683&#x2013;1690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weikert T, Friebe L, Wilder-Smith A, et al. Automated quantification of airway wall thickness on chest CT using retina U-Nets&#x2014;performance evaluation and application to a large cohort of chest CTs of COPD patients. Eur J Radiol. 2022;155:110460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Thoracic Society meeting. Assessment of 10-year Progression in COPDGene Using Automated Measurements of Bronchus-Artery Ratios and Mucus Plugging Latisenko Rudolfs, Tiddens Harm, Charbonnier Jean-Paul, Crapo James, Lynch David, et al. 2025. Assessment of 10-year Progression in COPDGene Using Automated Measurements of Bronchus-Artery Ratios and Mucus Plugging. doi:10.1164/ajrccm.2025.211.Abstracts.A3375</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphries SM, Notary AM, Centeno JP, et al. Deep learning enables automatic classification of emphysema pattern at CT. Radiology. 2020;294:434&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh AS, Baraghoshi D, Lynch DA, et al. Emphysema progression at CT by deep learning predicts functional impairment and mortality: results from the COPDGene study. Radiology. 2022;304:672&#x2013;679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baraghoshi D, Strand MJ, Humphries SM, et al. Uncertainty-aware quantitative CT evaluation of emphysema and mortality risk from variable radiation dose images. Eur Radiol. 2025;35:6115&#x2013;6126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary MFA, Awan HA, Gerard SE, et al. Deep learning estimation of small airways disease from inspiratory chest CT: clinical validation, repeatability, and associations with adverse clinical outcomes in COPD. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2025;211:1185&#x2013;1195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COPDGene 2025 Diagnosis Working Group and CanCOLD Investigators. A multidimensional diagnostic approach for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. JAMA. 2025;333:2164&#x2013;2175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee AN, Hsiao A, Hasenstab KA. Evaluating the cumulative benefit of inspiratory CT, expiratory CT, and clinical data for COPD diagnosis and staging through deep learning. Radiol Cardiothorac Imaging. 2024;6:e240005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King TE, Bradford WZ, Castro-Bernardini S, et al. A phase 3 trial of pirfenidone in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:2083&#x2013;2092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flaherty KR, Wells AU, Cottin V, et al. Nintedanib in progressive fibrosing interstitial lung diseases. N Engl J Med. 2019;381:1718&#x2013;1727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher TM, Assassi S, Azuma A, et al. Nerandomilast in patients with progressive pulmonary fibrosis. N Engl J Med. 2025;392:2203&#x2013;2214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooney JJ, Elicker BM, Urbania TH, et al. Radiographic fibrosis score predicts survival in hypersensitivity pneumonitis. Chest. 2013;144:586&#x2013;592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh SLF, Sverzellati N, Devaraj A, et al. Connective tissue disease related fibrotic lung disease: high resolution computed tomographic and pulmonary function indices as prognostic determinants. Thorax. 2014;69:216&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh AS, Lynch DA, Swigris JJ, et al. Deep learning&#x2013;based fibrosis extent on computed tomography predicts outcome of fibrosing interstitial lung disease independent of visually assessed computed tomography pattern. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2024;21:218&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu G, Remy-Jardin M, Myers JL, et al. Diagnosis of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. An Official ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT Clinical Practice Guideline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;198:e44&#x2013;e68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch DA, Sverzellati N, Travis WD, et al. Diagnostic criteria for idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: a Fleischner Society White Paper. Lancet Respir Med. 2018;6:138&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best AC, Lynch AM, Bozic CM, et al. Quantitative CT indexes in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: relationship with physiologic impairment. Radiology. 2003;228:407&#x2013;414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash SY, Harmouche R, Vallejo DLL, et al. Densitometric and local histogram based analysis of computed tomography images in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respir Res. 2017;18:45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Kim GH, Salisbury ML, et al. Computed tomographic biomarkers in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. the future of quantitative analysis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;199:12&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uppaluri R, Hoffman EA, Sonka M, et al. Computer recognition of regional lung disease patterns. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1999;160:648&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphries SM, Yagihashi K, Huckleberry J, et al. Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: data-driven textural analysis of extent of fibrosis at baseline and 15-month follow-up. Radiology. 2017;285:270&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, van Beek EJR, Hwanjo Y, et al. Computer-aided classification of interstitial lung diseases via MDCT: 3D adaptive multiple feature method (3D AMFM). Acad Radiol. 2006;13:969&#x2013;978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Tashkin DP, Clements P, et al. A computer-aided diagnosis system for quantitative scoring of extent of lung fibrosis in scleroderma patients. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2010;28(5 Suppl 62):S26&#x2013;S35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartholmai BJ, Raghunath S, Karwoski RA, et al. Quantitative CT imaging of interstitial lung diseases. J Thorac Imaging. 2013;28(5):298&#x2013;307. doi:10.1097/RTI.0b013e3182a21969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RTI.0b013e3182a21969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphries SM, Mackintosh JA, Jo HE, et al. Quantitative computed tomography predicts outcomes in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respirology. 2022;27:1045&#x2013;1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphries SM, Adegunsoye A, Demoruelle MK, et al. Quantitative CT scan analysis in rheumatoid arthritis-related interstitial lung disease. CHEST. 2025;167:1428&#x2013;1439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldin JG, Kim GHJ, Tseng CH, et al. Longitudinal changes in quantitative interstitial lung disease on computed tomography after immunosuppression in the scleroderma lung study II. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2018;15:1286&#x2013;1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatabu H, Hunninghake GM, Richeldi L, et al. Interstitial lung abnormalities detected incidentally on CT: a Position Paper from the Fleischner Society. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:726&#x2013;737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash SY, Choi B, Oh A, et al. Deep learning assessment of progression of emphysema and fibrotic interstitial lung abnormality. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;208:666&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matson SM, Deane KD, Peljto AL, et al. Prospective identification of subclinical interstitial lung disease in rheumatoid arthritis cohort is associated with the MUC5B promoter variant. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2021;205:473&#x2013;476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathai SK, Humphries S, Kropski JA, et al. MUC5B variant is associated with visually and quantitatively detected preclinical pulmonary fibrosis. Thorax. 2019;74:1131&#x2013;1139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh SL, Mackintosh JA, Calandriello L, et al. Deep Learning-based outcome prediction in progressive fibrotic lung disease using high-resolution computed tomography. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;206:883&#x2013;891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphries SM, Thieke D, Baraghoshi D, et al. Deep learning classification of usual interstitial pneumonia predicts outcomes. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2024;209:1121&#x2013;1131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob J, Bartholmai BJ, Rajagopalan S, et al. Serial automated quantitative CT analysis in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: functional correlations and comparison with changes in visual CT scores. Eur Radiol. 2018;28:1318&#x2013;1327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thillai M, Oldham JM, Ruggiero A, et al. Deep learning-based segmentation of CT scans predicts disease progression and mortality in IPF. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2024;210:465&#x2013;472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbie H, Wells AU, Fang C, et al. Serial decline in lung volume parameters on computed tomography (CT) predicts outcome in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF). Eur Radiol. 2022;32:2650&#x2013;2660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si-Mohamed SA, Nasser M, Colevray M, et al. Automatic quantitative computed tomography measurement of longitudinal lung volume loss in interstitial lung diseases. Eur Radiol. 2022;32:4292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob J, Bartholmai BJ, Rajagopalan S, et al. Mortality prediction in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: evaluation of computer-based CT analysis with conventional severity measures. Eur Respir J. 2017;49:1601011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob J, Bartholmai BJ, Rajagopalan S, et al. Predicting outcomes in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis using automated computed tomographic analysis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;198:767&#x2013;776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devaraj A, Ottink F, Rennison-Jones C, et al. e-Lung computed tomography biomarker stratifies patients at risk of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis progression in a 52-week clinical trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2024;209:1168&#x2013;1169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlesinger C, Meyer CA, Veeraraghavan S, et al. Constrictive (obliterative) bronchiolitis: diagnosis, etiology, and a critical review of the literature. Ann Diagn Pathol. 1998;2:321&#x2013;334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams KM. How I treat bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome after hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Blood. 2017;129:448&#x2013;455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansell DM, Rubens MB, Padley SP, et al. Obliterative bronchiolitis: individual CT signs of small airways disease and functional correlation. Radiology. 1997;203:721&#x2013;726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunn MLD, Godwin JD, Kanne JP, et al. High-resolution CT findings of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome after hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. J Thorac Imaging. 2008;23:244&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bankier AA, Van Muylem A, Knoop C, et al. Bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome in heart-lung transplant recipients: diagnosis with expiratory CT. Radiology. 2001;218:533&#x2013;539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konen E, Gutierrez C, Chaparro C, et al. Bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome in lung transplant recipients: can thin-section CT findings predict disease before its clinical appearance? Radiology. 2004;231:467&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento DZ, Watte G, Torres FS, et al. Utilization of quantitative computed tomography assessment to identify bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome after single lung transplantation. Lung. 2021;199:29&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solyanik O, Hollmann P, Dettmer S, et al. Quantification of pathologic air trapping in lung transplant patients using CT density mapping: comparison with other CT air trapping measures. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0139102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kloth C, Thaiss WM, Hetzel J, et al. Results of quantitative chest-CT in chronic pulmonary graft-vs.-host disease (cGvHD) 3 years after allogeneic stem cell transplantation. J Thorac Dis. 2017;9:2521&#x2013;2527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galb&#xe1;n CJ, Boes JL, Bule M, et al. Parametric response mapping as an indicator of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome after hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2014;20:1592&#x2013;1598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verleden SE, Vos R, Vandermeulen E, et al. Parametric Response Mapping of Bronchiolitis Obliterans Syndrome progression after lung transplantation. Am J Transplant Off J Am Soc Transplant Am Soc Transpl Surg. 2016;16:3262&#x2013;3269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi H, Lai YK, Guo H, et al. Machine learning algorithms to differentiate among pulmonary complications after hematopoietic cell transplant. Chest. 2020;158:1090&#x2013;1103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retson TA, Hasenstab KA, Kligerman SJ, et al. Reader perceptions and impact of AI on CT assessment of air trapping. Radiol Artif Intell. 2022;4:e210160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozi&#x144;ski M, Oner D, Gwizda&#x142;a J, et al. Harnessing deep learning to detect bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome from chest CT. Commun Med. 2025;5:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motahari A, Barr RG, Han MK, et al. Repeatability of pulmonary quantitative computed tomography measurements in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;208:657&#x2013;665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi Y, Yu W, Nagarajan MB, et al. Translating AI to clinical practice: overcoming data shift with explainability. Radiographics. 2023;43:e220105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh SLF, De Backer J, Prosch H, et al. Towards the adoption of quantitative computed tomography in the management of interstitial lung disease. Eur Respir Rev. 2024;33:230055.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>