<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41359390</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-7072</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in critical care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Crit Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How I monitor lung function during mechanical ventilation and veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for acute respiratory distress syndrome.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCC.0000000000001344</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Mechanical ventilation (MV) is central to the management of acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). In refractory cases, veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (VV-ECMO) can provide adequate gas exchange and facilitate protective ventilation. Effective management requires systematic monitoring of both the native lung (NL) and the membrane lung (ML). This review outlines an approach to monitoring ventilated patients, integrating physiological principles with clinical assessment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Monitoring respiratory mechanics and inspiratory effort during controlled or assisted ventilation is essential to minimize the risk of ventilator-induced lung injury (VILI) and patient self-inflicted lung injury (P-SILI). New bedside methods have been validated, linking these measurements to both risk of injury and clinical outcomes. During VV-ECMO, accurate monitoring of ML function enables reduction in the intensity of MV and, subsequently, modulation of respiratory drive and effort.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Monitoring the respiratory system during MV and VV-ECMO in ARDS is essential to understand the interplay between the native and membrane lungs, both in controlled and assisted ventilation, where respiratory drive and effort are often unmeasured and overlooked. Careful selection and application of monitoring strategies therefore remain a cornerstone of safe management in these complex patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fumagalli</LastName><ForeName>Benedetta</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Guy's and St Thomas' National Health Service Foundation Trust.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collins</LastName><ForeName>Patrick Duncan</ForeName><Initials>PD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Guy's and St Thomas' National Health Service Foundation Trust.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Human and Applied Physiological Sciences, School of Basic and Medical Biosciences, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Camporota</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Guy's and St Thomas' National Health Service Foundation Trust.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Human and Applied Physiological Sciences, School of Basic and Medical Biosciences, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Crit Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9504454</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1070-5295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute respiratory distress syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extracorporeal membrane oxygenation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ventilator-induced lung injury</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41359390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCC.0000000000001344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00075198-990000000-00329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Catozzi G, Pozzi T, Nocera D, et al. Rethinking ARDS classification: oxygenation impairment fails to predict VILI risk. Intensive Care Med 2025; 51:62&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezoagli E, Laffey JG, Bellani G. Monitoring lung injury severity and ventilation intensity during mechanical ventilation. Semin Respir Crit Care Med 2022; 43:346&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasselli G, Calfee CS, Camporota L, et al. ESICM guidelines on acute respiratory distress syndrome: definition, phenotyping and respiratory support strategies. Intensive Care Med 2023; 49:727&#x2013;759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattinoni L, Tonetti T, Cressoni M, et al. Ventilator-related causes of lung injury: the mechanical power. Intensive Care Med 2016; 42:1567&#x2013;1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serpa Neto A, Deliberato RO, Johnson AEW, et al. Mechanical power of ventilation is associated with mortality in critically ill patients: an analysis of patients in two observational cohorts. Intensive Care Med 2018; 44:1914&#x2013;1922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt M, Pham T, Arcadipane A, et al. Mechanical ventilation management during extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for acute respiratory distress syndrome. an international multicenter prospective cohort. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2019; 200:1002&#x2013;1012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combes A, Supady A, Abrams D, et al. Extracorporeal life support for adult patients with ARDS. Intensive Care Med 2025; 51:1674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combes A, Hajage D, Capellier G, et al. Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med 2018; 378:1965&#x2013;1975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins PD, Giosa L, Camporota L, Barrett NA. State of the art: Monitoring of the respiratory system during veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Perfusion 2024; 39:7&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Albo R, Pozzi T, Nicolardi RV, et al. Mechanical power ratio threshold for ventilator-induced lung injury. Intensive Care Med Exp 2024; 12:65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa ELV, Slutsky AS, Brochard LJ, et al. Ventilatory variables and mechanical power in patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2021; 204:303&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amato MB, Meade MO, Slutsky AS, et al. Driving pressure and survival in the acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med 2015; 372:747&#x2013;755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assouline B, Combes A, Schmidt M. Setting and monitoring of mechanical ventilation during venovenous ECMO. Crit Care 2023; 27:95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonna JE, Abrams D, Brodie D, et al. Management of adult patients supported with venovenous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (VV ECMO): guideline from the extracorporeal life support organization (ELSO). ASAIO J 2021; 67:601&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa MLA, Menga LS, Schreiber A, et al. Individualized PEEP can improve both pulmonary hemodynamics and lung function in acute lung injury. Crit Care 2025; 29:107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali S, Ferguson ND. High-frequency oscillatory ventilation in ALI/ARDS. Crit Care Clin 2011; 27:487&#x2013;499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattinoni L, Collino F, Maiolo G, et al. Positive end-expiratory pressure: how to set it at the individual level. Ann Transl Med 2017; 5:288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattinoni L, Collino F, Camporota L. Assessing lung recruitability: does it help with PEEP settings? Intensive Care Med 2024; 50:749&#x2013;751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonkman AH, Alcala GC, Pavlovsky B, et al. Lung recruitment assessed by electrical impedance tomography (RECRUIT): a multicenter study of COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2023; 208:25&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiumello D, Arnal JM, Umbrello M, et al. Hysteresis and lung recruitment in acute respiratory distress syndrome patients: a CT scan study. Crit Care Med 2020; 48:1494&#x2013;1502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Del Sorbo L, Grieco DL, et al. Potential for lung recruitment estimated by the recruitment-to-inflation ratio in acute respiratory distress syndrome. a clinical trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2020; 201:178&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Del Sorbo L, Grieco DL, et al. Airway closure in acute respiratory distress syndrome: an underestimated and misinterpreted phenomenon. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2018; 197:132&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonkman AH, Telias I, Spinelli E, et al. The oesophageal balloon for respiratory monitoring in ventilated patients: updated clinical review and practical aspects. Eur Respir Rev 2023; 32:220186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham T, Telias I, Beitler JR. Esophageal manometry. Respir Care 2020; 65:772&#x2013;792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Amato MBP, Grieco DL, et al. Esophageal manometry and regional transpulmonary pressure in lung injury. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2018; 197:1018&#x2013;1026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli J, Santiago RRS, Teggia Droghi M, et al. Lung recruitment in obese patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Anesthesiology 2019; 130:791&#x2013;803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattinoni L, Giosa L, Bonifazi M, et al. Targeting transpulmonary pressure to prevent ventilator-induced lung injury. Expert Rev Respir Med 2019; 13:737&#x2013;746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goligher EC, Dres M, Patel BK, et al. Lung- and diaphragm-protective ventilation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2020; 202:950&#x2013;961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins PD, Giosa L, Camarda V, Camporota L. Physiological adaptations during weaning from veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Intensive Care Med Exp 2023; 11:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smits FE, Rietveld PJ, Snoep JWM, et al. P0.1 is an unreliable measure of effort in support mechanical ventilation in comparison with esophageal-derived measures of effort: a comparison study. Crit Care Med 2025; 53:e1650&#x2013;e1658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries HJ, Tuinman PR, Jonkman AH, et al. Performance of noninvasive airway occlusion maneuvers to assess lung stress and diaphragm effort in mechanically ventilated critically ill patients. Anesthesiology 2023; 138:274&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertoni M, Telias I, Urner M, et al. A novel noninvasive method to detect excessively high respiratory effort and dynamic transpulmonary driving pressure during mechanical ventilation. Crit Care 2019; 23:346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foti G, Cereda M, Banfi G, et al. End-inspiratory airway occlusion: a method to assess the pressure developed by inspiratory muscles in patients with acute lung injury undergoing pressure support. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 1997; 156 (Pt 1):1210&#x2013;1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellani G, Grassi A, Sosio S, et al. Driving pressure is associated with outcome during assisted ventilation in acute respiratory distress syndrome. Anesthesiology 2019; 131:594&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez J, Dorado JH, Accoce M, Plotnikow GA. Airway and transpulmonary driving pressure by end-inspiratory holds during pressure support ventilation. Respir Care 2023; 68:1483&#x2013;1492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Marec J, Hajage D, Decavele M, et al. High airway occlusion pressure is associated with dyspnea and increased mortality in critically ill mechanically ventilated patients. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2024; 210:201&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esnault P, Hraiech S, Bordes J, et al. Evaluation of almitrine infusion during veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for severe acute respiratory distress syndrome in adults. Anesth Analg 2019; 129:e48&#x2013;e51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ficial B, Vasques F, Zhang J, et al. Physiological basis of extracorporeal membrane oxygenation and extracorporeal carbon dioxide removal in respiratory failure. Membranes 2021; 11:225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomarchio E, Momigliano F, Giosa L, et al. The intricate physiology of veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation: an overview for clinicians. Perfusion 2024; 39 (1_suppl):49S&#x2013;65S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickstein ML. Extracorporeal CO(2) removal and the alveolar gas equation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2020; 202:1057&#x2013;1058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diehl JL, Mercat A, Pesenti A. Understanding hypoxemia on ECCO(2)R: back to the alveolar gas equation. Intensive Care Med 2019; 45:255&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nisar S, Gibson CD, Sokolovic M, Shah NS. Pulse oximetry is unreliable in patients on veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation caused by unrecognized carboxyhemoglobinemia. ASAIO J 2020; 66:1105&#x2013;1109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raimondi Cominesi D, Forcione M, Pozzi M, et al. Pulmonary shunt in critical care: a practical approach with clinical scenarios. J Anesth Analg Crit Care 2024; 4:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboab J, Louis B, Jonson B, Brochard L. Relation between PaO2/FIO2 ratio and FIO2: a mathematical description. Intensive Care Med 2006; 32:1494&#x2013;1497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams D, Bacchetta M, Brodie D. Recirculation in venovenous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. ASAIO J 2015; 61:115&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ch50_Physiology_of_the_Upper_Airways_and_Upper_1.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreit JW. Volume capnography in the intensive care unit: physiological principles, measurements, and calculations. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2019; 16:291&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez-Sipmann F, Villar J, Ferrando C, et al. Monitoring expired CO(2) kinetics to individualize lung-protective ventilation in patients with the acute respiratory distress syndrome. Front Physiol 2021; 12:785014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavayas YA, Munshi L, Del Sorbo L, Fan E. The early change in Pa(CO(2)) after extracorporeal membrane oxygenation initiation is associated with neurological complications. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2020; 201:1525&#x2013;1535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giani M, Lucchini A, Magni G, et al. How to avoid rapid carbon dioxide changes at the start of veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation: role of end-tidal CO2 monitoring. Perfusion 2022; 38:684&#x2013;688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supady A, Combes A, Barbaro RP, et al. Respiratory indications for ECMO: focus on COVID-19. Intensive Care Med 2022; 48:1326&#x2013;1337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams D, Agerstrand C, Beitler JR, et al. Risks and benefits of ultra-lung-protective invasive mechanical ventilation strategies with a focus on extracorporeal support. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2022; 205:873&#x2013;882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crotti S, Bottino N, Spinelli E. Spontaneous breathing during veno-venous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. J Thorac Dis 2018; 10 (Suppl 5):S661&#x2013;S669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauri T, Langer T, Zanella A, et al. Extremely high transpulmonary pressure in a spontaneously breathing patient with early severe ARDS on ECMO. Intensive Care Med 2016; 42:2101&#x2013;2103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauri T, Grasselli G, Suriano G, et al. Control of respiratory drive and effort in extracorporeal membrane oxygenation patients recovering from severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. Anesthesiology 2016; 125:159&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli B, Giani M, Bombino M, et al. Pressure support ventilation during extracorporeal membrane oxygenation support in patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome. ASAIO J 2025; 71:171&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartley EL, Sanderson B, Vasques F, et al. Prediction of readiness to decannulation from venovenous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Perfusion 2020; 35 (Suppl):57&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasques F, Romitti F, Gattinoni L, Camporota L. How I wean patients from veno-venous extra-corporeal membrane oxygenation. Crit Care 2019; 23:316.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41343674</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>122</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prostaglandin E<sub>2</sub>-EP2/EP4 signaling induces the tumor-infiltrating Treg phenotype for tumor growth.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2424251122</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2424251122</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2424251122</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Foxp3<sup>+</sup> regulatory T cells (Tregs) heavily infiltrate malignant tumors and restrict antitumor immunity. These tumor-infiltrating Tregs (TI-Tregs) adopt a distinct phenotype by expressing a unique set of genes. This TI-Treg gene expression signature is conserved in TI-Tregs across species and tumor types and stages, suggesting the presence of a common inducing mechanism in the tumor microenvironment (TME). However, identity of such a mechanism remains elusive. Here, we show that prostaglandin E<sub>2</sub> (PGE<sub>2</sub>) produced in TME directly acts on its receptor EP2/EP4 on Tregs to induce the TI-Treg phenotype. PGE<sub>2</sub> added to TCR-activated Tregs induces a set of genes, many of which are included in the TI-Treg signature, in both induced Tregs (iTregs) and naturally occurring Tregs (nTregs) via EP2/EP4- cAMP-PKA pathway. Concomitantly, PGE<sub>2</sub>-treated Tregs exhibit potent suppressive activity to CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells and strongly inhibit their proliferation in an EP4 dependent manner. Consistently, selective loss of EP2 and EP4 in mouse Tregs reduces expression of those genes in Tregs infiltrating Lewis lung carcinoma 1 (LLC1) mouse tumor and significantly delays the tumor progression. In human FOXP3<sup>+</sup>iTregs, PGE<sub>2</sub>-EP4 signaling upregulated the expression of Treg signature genes, FOXP3, CD25, and CTLA-4 as well as a typical TI-Treg signature gene, 4-1BB, and enhanced suppressive activity. Furthermore, analysis of single-cell RNA sequencing of nasopharyngeal cancer patients demonstrates preferential expression of the TI-Treg signature genes in Tregs infiltrating the <i>PTGS2<sup>hi</sup></i> tumor group compared to the <i>PTGS2<sup>lo</sup></i> tumor group. These findings suggest that PGE<sub>2</sub>-EP2/EP4 signaling is one of the core mechanisms inducing the TI-Treg phenotype in TME for tumor growth.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsuura</LastName><ForeName>Ryuma</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Drug Discovery Medicine, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto 606-8507, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Punyawatthananukool</LastName><ForeName>Siwakorn</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Drug Discovery Medicine, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto 606-8507, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawakami</LastName><ForeName>Ryoji</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2253-4559</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Pathology, Institute for Frontier Life and Medical Sciences, Kyoto University, Kyoto 606-8507, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Immunology, Immunology Frontier Research Center, Osaka University, Osaka 565-0871, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mikami</LastName><ForeName>Norihisa</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6360-5363</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Immunology, Immunology Frontier Research Center, Osaka University, Osaka 565-0871, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Shimon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8265-6094</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Pathology, Institute for Frontier Life and Medical Sciences, Kyoto University, Kyoto 606-8507, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Immunology, Immunology Frontier Research Center, Osaka University, Osaka 565-0871, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narumiya</LastName><ForeName>Shuh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Drug Discovery Medicine, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto 606-8507, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AMED-FORCE, Japan Agency for Medical Research and Development, Tokyo 100-0004, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foundation for Biomedical Research and Innovation at Kobe, Kobe 650-0047, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>20H00498</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology (MEXT)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21gm40100009h0002</GrantID><Agency>Japan Agency for Medical Research and Development (AMED)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058309">Receptors, Prostaglandin E, EP4 Subtype</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>K7Q1JQR04M</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015232">Dinoprostone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058307">Receptors, Prostaglandin E, EP2 Subtype</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C545651">Ptger4 protein, mouse</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058309" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptors, Prostaglandin E, EP4 Subtype</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015232" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dinoprostone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050378" MajorTopicYN="Y">T-Lymphocytes, Regulatory</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058307" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptors, Prostaglandin E, EP2 Subtype</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059016" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Microenvironment</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016246" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lymphocytes, Tumor-Infiltrating</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008810" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred C57BL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045744" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line, Tumor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EP4 receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prostaglandin E2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">regulatory T cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumor microenvironment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests statement:S.N. is a scientific advisor to Astellas Pharma Inc and Toray Co Ltd.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41343674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2424251122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41343669</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>122</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Asparagine endopeptidase prompts breast cancer-related pericardial calcification by regulating IGF2 and integrin &#x3b1;v&#x3b2;5.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2512936122</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2512936122</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2512936122</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiac calcification, often seen in age-related diseases, impairs heart function, yet its association with malignant tumors remains largely overlooked. Our study revealed that pericardial calcification (PC) occurs in up to 80% of breast cancer patients with pulmonary metastasis. We demonstrate a reciprocal relationship where breast cancer drives PC, which in turn accelerates cancer progression in humans and mice. Lung metastases increase monocyte-derived macrophage and mesenchymal stem cell (MSC)-derived osteoblast infiltration in the pericardial tissue, triggering inflammation and calcification. Mechanistically, metastatic cancer cells in the lungs highly express and secrete asparagine endopeptidase (AEP), which cleaves IGF2BP3 to free IGF2. AEP and IGF2 contribute to PC by promoting osteoblast differentiation in heart tissue through integrin &#x3b1;v&#x3b2;5 and IGF1R activation, respectively. Pharmacological blockade of integrin &#x3b1;v&#x3b2;5 and IGF1R, especially when combined, effectively inhibits ectopic osteogenesis and disrupts the feedback loop between PC and cancer progression. These findings elucidate the interplay between metastatic breast cancer and PC and suggest therapeutic strategies to hinder breast cancer progression.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xuefeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3613-6113</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Fourth Af&#xfb01;liated Hospital of Soochow University, Institutes for Translational Medicine of Soochow University, Suzhou 215123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese Academy of Sciences Key Laboratory of Tissue Microenvironment and Tumor, Shanghai Institute of Nutrition and Health, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 200031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Institute for Medical Engineering, Fuzhou University, Fuzhou 350108, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Obstetrics and Gynecology Hospital of Fudan University, Shanghai Key Lab of Reproduction and Development, Shanghai Key Lab of Female Reproductive Endocrine Related Diseases, Shanghai 200433, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lan</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2951-8087</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Chunyu</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Jiayi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Breast Surgery, Renji Hospital, School of Medicine, Shanghai Jiaotong University, Shanghai 200127, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Qiaoting</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Haili</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Jieyu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Xinyi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6735-1495</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Huabin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Menghui</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Qingdao University, Qingdao 266071, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Fangfang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Jiayin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese Academy of Sciences Key Laboratory of Tissue Microenvironment and Tumor, Shanghai Institute of Nutrition and Health, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 200031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Jingjie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese Academy of Sciences Key Laboratory of Tissue Microenvironment and Tumor, Shanghai Institute of Nutrition and Health, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 200031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lan</LastName><ForeName>Haokun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Institute for Medical Engineering, Fuzhou University, Fuzhou 350108, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ouyang</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jing</LastName><ForeName>Zihao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Libo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuo</LastName><ForeName>Weibin</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Commission Key Laboratory of Cancer Metabolism, Clinical Oncology School of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Cancer Hospital, Fuzhou 350014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiamen University-Fujian Cancer Hospital Research Center of Metabolism and Cancer, State Key Laboratory for Cellular Stress Biology, Xiamen University, Xiamen 361104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Jinsong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3874-9108</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Breast Surgery, Renji Hospital, School of Medicine, Shanghai Jiaotong University, Shanghai 200127, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Yufang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9716-2126</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Fourth Af&#xfb01;liated Hospital of Soochow University, Institutes for Translational Medicine of Soochow University, Suzhou 215123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese Academy of Sciences Key Laboratory of Tissue Microenvironment and Tumor, Shanghai Institute of Nutrition and Health, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 200031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese Academy of Sciences Key Laboratory of Tissue Microenvironment and Tumor, Shanghai Institute of Nutrition and Health, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai 200031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022YFA0807300</GrantID><Agency>National key R&amp;D Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>32000550</GrantID><Agency>NSF of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82425032</GrantID><Agency>NSF of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82430086</GrantID><Agency>NSF of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>67763-97-7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007335">Insulin-Like Growth Factor II</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019030">Receptors, Vitronectin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C064660">integrin alphaVbeta5</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.22.34</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C069586">asparaginylendopeptidase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.22.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003546">Cysteine Endopeptidases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C035170">IGF2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017526">Receptor, IGF Type 1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000597236">IGF1R protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007335" MajorTopicYN="Y">Insulin-Like Growth Factor II</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002114" MajorTopicYN="Y">Calcinosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019030" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptors, Vitronectin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003546" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cysteine Endopeptidases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000556" MajorTopicYN="N">secondary</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010006" MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoblasts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045744" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line, Tumor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017526" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptor, IGF Type 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">asparagine endopeptidase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin-like growth factor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">integrin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pericardial calcification</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests statement:The application of cilengitide in inhibiting pericardial calcification described in this paper have been filed for a patent application (CN 202510113055.1). Authors X.W. and B.L. are listed as inventors on this patent. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41343669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2512936122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41323796</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2162-2531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular therapy. Nucleic acids</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Ther Nucleic Acids</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SCAD: A modular platform for efficient delivery of duplex RNA to the CNS and beyond.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102757</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102757</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">102757</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.omtn.2025.102757</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Oligonucleotide therapeutics-including antisense oligonucleotides and duplex RNAs such as small interfering RNAs, small activating RNAs, and microRNAs-hold immense potential for treating both genetic and acquired diseases by modulating gene expression in a target-specific manner. However, effective delivery to extrahepatic tissues, particularly the central nervous system, remains a significant challenge. While <i>N</i>-Acetylgalactosamine conjugation has enabled liver-specific delivery of oligonucleotides leading to several approved siRNA drugs for hepatic indications, there remains a significant unmet need for effective treatment options in the CNS space. We have developed the smart chemistry-aided delivery platform that enables duplex RNA delivery by conjugating to an accessory oligonucleotide, which facilitates protein binding and promotes cellular uptake. Through extensive screening, we identified an optimal SCAD architecture that demonstrates enhanced cell-free protein binding and <i>in vitro</i> activity. In rodent models, local administration of SCAD-siRNA conjugates resulted in broad biodistribution throughout the CNS and sustained mRNA knockdown for over 5 months, with a favorable safety profile. The SCAD platform also exhibited efficient delivery to other extrahepatic tissues, including the eye, lung, and joint. The modular design of SCAD can be easily adapted to any duplex RNA, making it a powerful tool for advancing oligonucleotide therapeutics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Moorim</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yichen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Feifei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xiaojie</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Si</LastName><ForeName>Chunyan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Jianxiu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Jichao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schacht</LastName><ForeName>Ian</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gan</LastName><ForeName>Zubao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Vera</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Long-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>LC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ractigen Therapeutics, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Reproductive Medicine, School of Medicine, Nantong University, Nantong, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Ther Nucleic Acids</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581621</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2162-2531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CNS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MT: Oligonucleotides: Therapies and Applications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCAD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SOD1-ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">delivery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oligonucleotide therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">siRNA</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>L.-C.L. and M.K. hold shares in Ractigen Therapeutics and are inventors of patents related to SCAD technology assigned to Ractigen Therapeutics. All authors are current or former employees or consultants of Ractigen Therapeutics.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41323796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12663631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.omtn.2025.102757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2162-2531(25)00311-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ranasinghe P., Addison M.L., Dear J.W., Webb D.J. Small interfering RNA: Discovery, pharmacology and clinical development-An introductory review. Br. J. Pharmacol. 2023;180:2697&#x2013;2720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36250252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A., Andresen J.L., Manan R.S., Langer R. Nucleic acid delivery for therapeutic applications. Adv. Drug Deliv. Rev. 2021;178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34492233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Q., Khvorova A. RNAi-based drug design: considerations and future directions. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 2024;23:341&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11144061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38570694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Souza A., Nozohouri S., Bleier B.S., Amiji M.M. CNS Delivery of Nucleic Acid Therapeutics: Beyond the Blood-Brain Barrier and Towards Specific Cellular Targeting. Pharm. Res. 2023;40:77&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36380168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts T.C., Langer R., Wood M.J.A. Advances in oligonucleotide drug delivery. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 2020;19:673&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7419031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown K.M., Nair J.K., Janas M.M., Anglero-Rodriguez Y.I., Dang L.T.H., Peng H., Theile C.S., Castellanos-Rizaldos E., Brown C., Foster D., et al. Expanding RNAi therapeutics to extrahepatic tissues with lipophilic conjugates. Nat. Biotechnol. 2022;40:1500&#x2013;1508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35654979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickline S.A., Hou K.K., Pan H. Peptide-Based Nanoparticles for Systemic Extrahepatic Delivery of Therapeutic Nucleotides. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10253970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37298407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo T., Yanagihara K., Takei Y., Mihara K., Morita Y., Seyama T. Palmitic acid-conjugated 21-nucleotide siRNA enhances gene-silencing activity. Mol. Pharm. 2011;8:2193&#x2013;2203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21985606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorets A.G., Schwensen K.R., Francini N., Kjar A., Abdulrahman A.M., Shostak A., Katdare K.A., Schoch K.M., Cowell R.P., Park J.C., et al. Elucidating brain transport pathways and cell type-dependent gene silencing of a durable lipid-siRNA conjugate administered into cerebrospinal fluid. Nucleic Acids Res. 2025;53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12214009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40598893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss A., Gilbert J.W., Rivera Flores I.V., Belgrad J., Ferguson C., Dogan E.O., Wightman N., Mocarski K., Echeverria D., Harkins A.L., et al. RNAi-mediated silencing of SOD1 profoundly extends survival and functional outcomes in ALS mice. Mol. Ther. 2025;33:3917&#x2013;3938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12461636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40349108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker S.J., Thayer M.B., Kim C., Tatarakis D., Simon M.J., Dial R., Nilewski L., Wells R.C., Zhou Y., Afetian M., et al. Targeting the transferrin receptor to transport antisense oligonucleotides across the mammalian blood-brain barrier. Sci. Transl. Med. 2024;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39141703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couch J.A., Yu Y.J., Zhang Y., Tarrant J.M., Fuji R.N., Meilandt W.J., Solanoy H., Tong R.K., Hoyte K., Luk W., et al. Addressing safety liabilities of TfR bispecific antibodies that cross the blood-brain barrier. Sci. Transl. Med. 2013;5:183ra57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23636093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair H.A. Tofersen: First Approval. Drugs. 2023;83:1039&#x2013;1043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37316681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crooke S.T., Baker B.F., Crooke R.M., Liang X.H. Antisense technology: an overview and prospectus. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 2021;20:427&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33762737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill S.F., Meisler M.H. Antisense Oligonucleotide Therapy for Neurodevelopmental Disorders. Dev. Neurosci. 2021;43:247&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34412058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amanat M., Nemeth C.L., Fine A.S., Leung D.G., Fatemi A. Antisense Oligonucleotide Therapy for the Nervous System: From Bench to Bedside with Emphasis on Pediatric Neurology. Pharmaceutics. 2022;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9695718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36365206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein F. Phosphorothioates, essential components of therapeutic oligonucleotides. Nucleic Acid Ther. 2014;24:374&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25353652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crooke S.T., Wang S., Vickers T.A., Shen W., Liang X.H. Cellular uptake and trafficking of antisense oligonucleotides. Nat. Biotechnol. 2017;35:230&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28244996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A., Cole T., Wegener A.J., Tomassy G.S., Setnicka A., Farley B.J., Schoch K.M., Hoye M.L., Shabsovich M., Sun L., et al. Antisense oligonucleotides extend survival and reverse decrement in muscle response in ALS models. J. Clin. Investig. 2018;128:3558&#x2013;3567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6063493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30010620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crooke S.T., Vickers T.A., Liang X.H. Phosphorothioate modified oligonucleotide-protein interactions. Nucleic Acids Res. 2020;48:5235&#x2013;5253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32356888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croft L.V., Fisher M., Barbhuiya T.K., El-Kamand S., Beard S., Rajapakse A., Gamsjaeger R., Cubeddu L., Bolderson E., O'Byrne K., et al. Sequence- and Structure-Dependent Cytotoxicity of Phosphorothioate and 2'-O-Methyl Modified Single-Stranded Oligonucleotides. Nucleic Acid Ther. 2024;34:143&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38648015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahns H., Taneja N., Willoughby J.L.S., Akabane-Nakata M., Brown C.R., Nguyen T., Bisbe A., Matsuda S., Hettinger M., Manoharan R.M., et al. Chirality matters: stereo-defined phosphorothioate linkages at the termini of small interfering RNAs improve pharmacology in vivo. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;50:1221&#x2013;1240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8860597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan C., Kang M., Pan X., Gan Z., Huang V., Li G., Place R.F., Li L.C. Intrathecal administration of a novel siRNA modality extends survival and improves motor function in the SOD1(G93A) ALS mouse model. Mol. Ther. Nucleic Acids. 2024;35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10907209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38435120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan C., Kang M., Liu K., Gan Z., Li G., Chen J., Schacht I., Place R.F., Li L.-C. RAG-17: A Novel siRNA Conjugate Demonstrating Efficacy in Late-Stage Treatment of SOD1G93A ALS mice. bioRxiv. 2023 doi: 10.1101/2023.11.23.568255. Preprint at.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.11.23.568255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alterman J.F., Godinho B.M.D.C., Hassler M.R., Ferguson C.M., Echeverria D., Sapp E., Haraszti R.A., Coles A.H., Conroy F., Miller R., et al. A divalent siRNA chemical scaffold for potent and sustained modulation of gene expression throughout the central nervous system. Nat. Biotechnol. 2019;37:884&#x2013;894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6879195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31375812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belgrad J., Tang Q., Hildebrand S., Summers A., Sapp E., Echeverria D., O'Reilly D., Luu E., Bramato B., Allen S., et al. A programmable dual-targeting siRNA scaffold supports potent two-gene modulation in the central nervous system. Nucleic Acids Res. 2024;52:6099&#x2013;6113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11194107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38726879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathiasen J.R., Moser V.C. The Irwin Test and Functional Observational Battery (FOB) for Assessing the Effects of Compounds on Behavior, Physiology, and Safety Pharmacology in Rodents. Curr. Protoc. Pharmacol. 2018;83:e43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30179315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyes W.K., Dourson M.L., Patterson J., Tilson H.A., Sette W.F., MacPhail R.C., Li A.A., O'Donoghue J.L. EPA's neurotoxicity risk assessment guidelines. Fundam. Appl. Toxicol. 1997;40:175&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9441713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fakih H.H., Tang Q., Summers A., Shin M., Buchwald J.E., Gagnon R., Hariharan V.N., Echeverria D., Cooper D.A., Watts J.K., et al. Dendritic amphiphilic siRNA: Selective albumin binding, in vivo efficacy, and low toxicity. Mol. Ther. Nucleic Acids. 2023;34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10711485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38089931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahsen B.F., Gray E., Thompson A.G., Ansorge O., Anthony D.C., Cowley S.A., Talbot K., Turner M.R. Non-neuronal cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - from pathogenesis to biomarkers. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2021;17:333&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33927394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baird M.C., Likhite S.B., Vetter T.A., Caporale J.R., Girard H.B., Roussel F.S., Howard A.E., Schwartz M.K., Reed A.R., Kaleem A., et al. Combination AAV therapy with galectin-1 and SOD1 downregulation demonstrates superior therapeutic effect in a severe ALS mouse model. Mol. Ther. Methods Clin. Dev. 2024;32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11385756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39257530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou M., Cleveland D.W. The seeds of neurodegeneration: prion-like spreading in ALS. Cell. 2011;147:498&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3220614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22036560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillee S., Vande Velde C., Cleveland D.W. ALS: a disease of motor neurons and their nonneuronal neighbors. Neuron. 2006;52:39&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17015226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka K., Chun S.J., Boillee S., Fujimori-Tonou N., Yamashita H., Gutmann D.H., Takahashi R., Misawa H., Cleveland D.W. Astrocytes as determinants of disease progression in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Neurosci. 2008;11:251&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18246065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Giorgio F.P., Carrasco M.A., Siao M.C., Maniatis T., Eggan K. Non-cell autonomous effect of glia on motor neurons in an embryonic stem cell-based ALS model. Nat. Neurosci. 2007;10:608&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3139463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17435754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ALZFORUM: https://www.alzforum.org/therapeutics/mivelsiran.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye J., Jiang L., Wang L., Pan Y., Wang X., Qu H., Liao X., Zhou X., Zhang S., Kang M., et al. RAG-17, a Novel siRNA Therapy for SOD1-ALS: Safety and Preliminary Efficacy from a First-in-human Trial (S5.003) Neurology. 2025;104:5451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charni-Natan M., Goldstein I. Protocol for Primary Mouse Hepatocyte Isolation. STAR Protoc. 2020;1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7580103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33111119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz-Munoz G., Looney M.R. Non-invasive Intratracheal Instillation in Mice. Bio Protoc. 2015;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4933024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27390765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu K., Chang R.C., So K.F. Intravitreous injection for establishing ocular diseases model. J. Vis. Exp. 2007;313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2562493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18989417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adaes S., Mendonca M., Santos T.N., Castro-Lopes J.M., Ferreira-Gomes J., Neto F.L. Intra-articular injection of collagenase in the knee of rats as an alternative model to study nociception associated with osteoarthritis. Arthritis Res. Ther. 2014;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3979102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24423138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41323794</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2162-2531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular therapy. Nucleic acids</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Ther Nucleic Acids</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Systemic miR-26a deficiency attenuates pulmonary fibrosis via PTEN upregulation and downstream TIMP-1 suppression.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102765</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102765</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">102765</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.omtn.2025.102765</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Several microRNAs (miRNAs) have been implicated in the pathophysiology of pulmonary fibrosis; however, the detailed mechanisms remain unclear. miR-26a has demonstrated antifibrotic effects, particularly when its expression is suppressed in the airways. However, the effects of systemic miR-26a deficiency on pulmonary fibrosis have not been investigated. We found that miR-26a knockout (KO) mice exhibited reduced pulmonary fibrosis compared with wild-type (WT) mice. Whole-lung RNA sequencing analysis indicated that the mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 (MTORC1) signaling and phosphoinositide 3-kinase/protein kinase B (PI3K/AKT) signaling pathways were elevated in the WT group compared with the KO group. Loss of miR-26a increases <i>PTEN</i> expression, a target gene of miR-26a, resulting in the reduction of <i>Timp1</i> levels downstream of the PI3K/Akt-mTOR pathway, thereby attenuating fibrosis. Transfection with miR-26a significantly suppressed <i>Pten</i> expression and increased <i>Timp1</i> and <i>Acta2</i> expression in primary lung fibroblasts <i>in vitro</i>. These results are consistent with the <i>in vivo</i> findings, which suggest that miR-26a promotes fibrosis, contrary to previous reports indicating an antifibrotic role for miR-26a. Our findings suggest that local and systemic inhibition of miR-26a may exert opposing effects, highlighting the importance of careful interpretation of miR-26a-targeted therapeutic strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamada</LastName><ForeName>Arisa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimoji</LastName><ForeName>Kiyofumi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakashima</LastName><ForeName>Taku</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Kakuhiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakamoto</LastName><ForeName>Shinjiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horimasu</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masuda</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwamoto</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamada</LastName><ForeName>Hironobu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Analysis and Therapeutic Sciences, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yasuda</LastName><ForeName>Tomoharu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyaki</LastName><ForeName>Shigeru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Center for Translational and Clinical Research, Hiroshima University Hospital, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Histology and Molecular Cell Biology, Faculty of Medicine / Graduate School of Medicine, Kagawa University, Kagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hattori</LastName><ForeName>Noboru</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Internal Medicine, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Ther Nucleic Acids</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581621</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2162-2531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MT: Non-coding RNAs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PTEN</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TIMP-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">miR-26a</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microRNA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary fibrosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41323794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12663618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.omtn.2025.102765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2162-2531(25)00319-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li H., Zhao X., Shan H., Liang H. MicroRNAs in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: involvement in pathogenesis and potential use in diagnosis and therapeutics. Acta Pharm. Sin. B. 2016;6:531&#x2013;539. doi: 10.1016/j.apsb.2016.06.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsb.2016.06.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5071633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27818919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T., Wang J., Zhao J., Liu Y. Current and prospective applications of exosomal microRNAs in pulmonary fibrosis (Review) Int. J. Mol. Med. 2022;49:37. doi: 10.3892/ijmm.2022.5092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijmm.2022.5092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8815412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35088880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadena-Su&#xe1;rez A.R., Hern&#xe1;ndez-Hern&#xe1;ndez H.A., Alvarado-V&#xe1;squez N., Rangel-Escare&#xf1;o C., Sommer B., Negrete-Garc&#xed;a M.C. Role of MicroRNAs in Signaling Pathways Associated with the Pathogenesis of Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis: A Focus on Epithelial-Mesenchymal Transition. IJMS. 2022;23:6613. doi: 10.3390/ijms23126613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23126613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9224458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35743055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yano H., Hamanaka R., Zhang J.J., Yano M., Hida M., Matsuo N., Yoshioka H. MicroRNA-26 regulates the expression of CTGF after exposure to ionizing radiation. Radiat. Environ. Biophys. 2021;60:411&#x2013;419. doi: 10.1007/s00411-021-00915-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00411-021-00915-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33959794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang H., Xu C., Pan Z., Zhang Y., Xu Z., Chen Y., Li T., Li X., Liu Y., Huangfu L., et al. The Antifibrotic Effects and Mechanisms of MicroRNA-26a Action in Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis. Mol. Ther. 2014;22:1122&#x2013;1133. doi: 10.1038/mt.2014.42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mt.2014.42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4048895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24594795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.H., Jang J.H., Park J.H., Jang H.-J., Park C.S., Lee S., Kim S.-H., Kim J.Y., Kim H.K. The role of interleukin-6 as a prognostic biomarker for predicting acute exacerbation in interstitial lung diseases. PLoS One. 2021;16 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0255365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0255365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8315549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34314462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito F., Tasaka S., Inoue K.I., Miyamoto K., Nakano Y., Ogawa Y., Yamada W., Shiraishi Y., Hasegawa N., Fujishima S., et al. Role of Interleukin-6 in Bleomycin-Induced Lung Inflammatory Changes in Mice. Am. J. Respir. Cell Mol. Biol. 2008;38:566&#x2013;571. doi: 10.1165/rcmb.2007-0299OC.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1165/rcmb.2007-0299OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18096870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willis B.C., Liebler J.M., Luby-Phelps K., Nicholson A.G., Crandall E.D., Borok Z. Induction of epithelial-mesenchymal transition in alveolar epithelial cells by transforming growth factor-&#x3b2;1. Am. J. Pathol. 2005;166:1321&#x2013;1332. doi: 10.1016/s0002-9440(10)62351-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0002-9440(10)62351-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1606388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J., Shi W., Wang Y.-L., Chen H., Bringas P., Datto M.B., Frederick J.P., Wang X.-F., Warburton D. Smad3 deficiency attenuates bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis in mice. Am. J. Physiol. Lung Cell. Mol. Physiol. 2002;282:L585&#x2013;L593. doi: 10.1152/ajplung.00151.2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajplung.00151.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11839555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenbroucke R.E., Libert C. Is their new hope for therapeutic matrix metalloproteinase inhibition? Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 2014;13:904&#x2013;927. doi: 10.1038/nrd4390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrd4390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25376097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ries C. Cytokine functions of TIMP-1. Cell. Mol. Life Sci. 2014;71:659&#x2013;672. doi: 10.1007/s00018-013-1457-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00018-013-1457-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11113289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23982756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez B., Gonz&#xe1;lez A., D&#xed;ez J. Circulating Biomarkers of Collagen Metabolism in Cardiac Diseases. Circulation. 2010;121:1645&#x2013;1654. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.912774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.912774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20385961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abignano G., Blagojevic J., Bissell L.-A., Dumitru R.B., Eng S., Allanore Y., Avouac J., Bosello S., Denton C.P., Distler O., et al. European multicentre study validates enhanced liver fibrosis test as biomarker of fibrosis in systemic sclerosis. Rheumatology. 2019;58:254&#x2013;259. doi: 10.1093/rheumatology/key271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/key271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30239834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madtes D.K., Elston A.L., Kaback L.A., Clark J.G. Selective Induction of Tissue Inhibitor of Metalloproteinase-1 in Bleomycin-Induced Pulmonary Fibrosis. Am. J. Respir. Cell Mol. Biol. 2001;24:599&#x2013;607. doi: 10.1165/ajrcmb.24.5.4192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1165/ajrcmb.24.5.4192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11350830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manoury B., Caulet-Maugendre S., Gu&#xe9;non I., Lagente V., Boichot E. Timp-1 is a Key Factor of Fibrogenic Response to Bleomycin in Mouse Lung. Int. J. Immunopathol. Pharmacol. 2006;19:471&#x2013;487. doi: 10.1177/039463200601900303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/039463200601900303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17026855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd J.L., Vinisko R., Liu Y., Neely M.L., Overton R., Flaherty K.R., Noth I., Newby L.K., Lasky J.A., Olman M.A., et al. Circulating matrix metalloproteinases and tissue metalloproteinase inhibitors in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis in the multicenter IPF-PRO Registry cohort. BMC Pulm. Med. 2020;20:64. doi: 10.1186/s12890-020-1103-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-020-1103-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7071646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magaye R.R., Savira F., Hua Y., Xiong X., Huang L., Reid C., Flynn B.L., Kaye D., Liew D., Wang B.H. Attenuating PI3K/Akt- mTOR pathway reduces dihydrosphingosine 1 phosphate mediated collagen synthesis and hypertrophy in primary cardiac cells. Int. J. Biochem. Cell Biol. 2021;134 doi: 10.1016/j.biocel.2021.105952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocel.2021.105952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33609744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson K.T., Torr E.E., Bernau K., Leet J., Sherris D., Sandbo N. The Novel mTOR Complex 1/2 Inhibitor P529 Inhibits Human Lung Myofibroblast Differentiation. J. Cell. Biochem. 2017;118:2241&#x2013;2249. doi: 10.1002/jcb.25878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.25878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5568785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Sun H. miR-26a promotes neurite outgrowth by repressing PTEN expression. Mol. Med. Rep. 2013;8:676&#x2013;680. doi: 10.3892/mmr.2013.1534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/mmr.2013.1534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23783805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghafouri-Fard S., Abak A., Shoorei H., Mohaqiq M., Majidpoor J., Sayad A., Taheri M. Regulatory role of microRNAs on PTEN signaling. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2021;133 doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W., Tan C., Zhang J. Alveolar Epithelial Type 2 Cell Dysfunction in Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis. Lung. 2022;200:539&#x2013;547. doi: 10.1007/s00408-022-00571-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00408-022-00571-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36136136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyoshi K., Yanagi S., Kawahara K., Nishio M., Tsubouchi H., Imazu Y., Koshida R., Matsumoto N., Taguchi A., Yamashita S.i., et al. Epithelial Pten Controls Acute Lung Injury and Fibrosis by Regulating Alveolar Epithelial Cell Integrity. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2013;187:262&#x2013;275. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201205-0851OC.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201205-0851OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23239155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu T., Tian Y., Gao Y., Ma M., Li H., Liu X., Wu H., Zhang Y., Ding H., Cao M., et al. PTEN loss regulates alveolar epithelial cell senescence in pulmonary fibrosis depending on Akt activation. Aging. 2019;11:7492&#x2013;7509. doi: 10.18632/aging.102262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.102262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6781970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31527305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verrecchia F., Mauviel A. Transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; and fibrosis. WJG. 2007;13:3056&#x2013;3062. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v13.i22.3056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v13.i22.3056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4172611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17589920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumimoto Y., Harada Y., Yimiti D., Watanabe C., Miyaki S., Adachi N. MicroRNA-26a deficiency attenuates the severity of frozen shoulder in a mouse immobilization model. J. Orthop. Res. 2024;42:2623&#x2013;2633. doi: 10.1002/jor.25940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.25940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39037550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai B., Wang F., Nie X., Du H., Zhao Y., Yin Z., Li H., Fan J., Wen Z., Wang D.W., Chen C. The Cell Type&#x2013;Specific Functions of miR-21 in Cardiovascular Diseases. Front. Genet. 2020;11 doi: 10.3389/fgene.2020.563166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2020.563166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33329700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill M., Tran N. miRNA interplay: mechanisms and consequences in cancer. Dis. Model. Mech. 2021;14 doi: 10.1242/dmm.047662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/dmm.047662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8077553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33973623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diener C., Keller A., Meese E. The miRNA&#x2013;target interactions: An underestimated intricacy. Nucleic Acids Res. 2024;52:1544&#x2013;1557. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkad1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkad1142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10899768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38033323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern F., Aparicio-Puerta E., Li Y., Fehlmann T., Kehl T., Wagner V., Ray K., Ludwig N., Lenhof H.-P., Meese E., Keller A. miRTargetLink 2.0&#x2014;interactive miRNA target gene and target pathway networks. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49:W409&#x2013;W416. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkab297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkab297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34009375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor S.A., Schupp J.C., Poli S., Ayaub E.A., Nir N., Ahangari F., Chu S.G., Raby B.A., DeIuliis G., Januszyk M., et al. Single-cell RNA-seq reveals ectopic and aberrant lung-resident cell populations in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Sci. Adv. 2020;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7439502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32832599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi T., Tanaka K., Fujita T., Umezawa H., Amano H., Yoshioka K., Naito Y., Hatano M., Kimura S., Tatsumi K., Kasuya Y. Bidirectional role of IL-6 signal in pathogenesis of lung fibrosis. Respir. Res. 2015;16:99. doi: 10.1186/s12931-015-0261-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-015-0261-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4546032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26289430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyhan A.A. Trials and Tribulations of MicroRNA Therapeutics. IJMS. 2024;25:1469. doi: 10.3390/ijms25031469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25031469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10855871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38338746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mashiko D., Fujihara Y., Satouh Y., Miyata H., Isotani A., Ikawa M. Generation of mutant mice by pronuclear injection of circular plasmid expressing Cas9 and single guided RNA. Sci. Rep. 2013;3:3355. doi: 10.1038/srep03355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep03355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3842082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24284873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanada Y., Ikuta Y., Ding C., Yimiti D., Kato Y., Nakasa T., Mizuno S., Takahashi S., Huang W., Lotz M.K., et al. miR-26a deficiency is associated with bone loss and reduced muscle strength but does not affect severity of cartilage damage in osteoarthritis. Mech. Ageing Dev. 2023;212 doi: 10.1016/j.mad.2023.111806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mad.2023.111806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37003368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karhadkar T.R., Pilling D., Gomer R.H. Serum Amyloid P inhibits single stranded RNA-induced lung inflammation, lung damage, and cytokine storm in mice. PLoS One. 2021;16 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0245924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0245924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7822324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33481950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindelin J., Arganda-Carreras I., Frise E., Kaynig V., Longair M., Pietzsch T., Preibisch S., Rueden C., Saalfeld S., Schmid B., et al. Fiji: an open-source platform for biological-image analysis. Nat. Methods. 2012;9:676&#x2013;682. doi: 10.1038/nmeth.2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nmeth.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3855844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22743772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lianoglou S., Garg V., Yang J.L., Leslie C.S., Mayr C. Ubiquitously transcribed genes use alternative polyadenylation to achieve tissue-specific expression. Genes Dev. 2013;27:2380&#x2013;2396. doi: 10.1101/gad.229328.113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gad.229328.113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3828523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24145798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Steven X., Son E.W., Yao R. iDEP: an integrated web application for differential expression and pathway analysis of RNA-Seq data. BMC Bioinf. 2018;19:534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6299935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30567491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horimasu Y., Ishikawa N., Taniwaki M., Yamaguchi K., Hamai K., Iwamoto H., Ohshimo S., Hamada H., Hattori N., Okada M., et al. Gene expression profiling of idiopathic interstitial pneumonias (IIPs): identification of potential diagnostic markers and therapeutic targets. BMC Med. Genet. 2017;18:88. doi: 10.1186/s12881-017-0449-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12881-017-0449-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5562997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28821283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41255679</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2219-2808</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of clinical pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Clin Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dual-energy computed tomography in children: Technique and clinical applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108823</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108823</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">108823</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5409/wjcp.v14.i4.108823</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Dual-energy CT (DECT) is an advancement in CT technology that allows for the acquisition of images at two different energy levels. Two main post-processing tools, which form the backbone of DECT, include material decomposition and virtual monoenergetic images. Material decomposition helps in the generation of virtual nonenhanced, iodine, pulmonary lung blood volume, lung vessel, automated bone removal, and renal stone characterization images. DECT offers a broad spectrum of clinical applications in pediatric imaging, including vascular, neurological, thoracic, abdominal, skeletal, and oncologic assessments. Additionally, it contributes to shorter scan times and enables the use of lower contrast media volumes while maintaining diagnostic image quality. This technique provides unique qualitative and quantitative information about the composition of the tissue, allowing differentiation of materials, including iodinated contrast agents. The radiation dose of DECT is equivalent to or lower than that of a single-energy CT, adding to the advantages of DECT, especially in children who are more sensitive to the harmful effects of radiation. In this minireview we outlined the basic principles of the DECT technique and its post-processing techniques with emphasis on clinical applications in pediatric imaging.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saini</LastName><ForeName>Shubham</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radio Diagnosis and Imaging, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatia</LastName><ForeName>Anmol</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radio Diagnosis and Imaging, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bansal</LastName><ForeName>Aarushi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radio Diagnosis and Imaging, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saxena</LastName><ForeName>Akshay Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radio Diagnosis and Imaging, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sodhi</LastName><ForeName>Kushaljit Singh</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radio Diagnosis and Imaging, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh 160012, India. sodhiks@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Clin Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2219-2808</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Computed tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dual-energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41255679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12620815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5409/wjcp.v14.i4.108823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Weinman JP, Mirsky DM, Jensen AM, Stence NV. Dual energy head CT to maintain image quality while reducing dose in pediatric patients. Clin Imaging. 2019;55:83&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30769223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel MJ, Curtis WA, Ramirez-Giraldo JC. Effects of Dual-Energy Technique on Radiation Exposure and Image Quality in Pediatric Body CT. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2016;207:826&#x2013;835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27490819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostini A, Mari A, Lanza C, Schicchi N, Borgheresi A, Maggi S, Giovagnoni A. Trends in radiation dose and image quality for pediatric patients with a multidetector CT and a third-generation dual-source dual-energy CT. Radiol Med. 2019;124:745&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31004322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabari A, Gee MS, Singh R, Lim R, Nimkin K, Primak A, Schmidt B, Kalra MK. Reducing Radiation Dose and Contrast Medium Volume With Application of Dual-Energy CT in Children and Young Adults. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2020;214:1199&#x2013;1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel MJ, Mhlanga JC, Salter A, Ramirez-Giraldo JC. Comparison of radiation dose and image quality between contrast-enhanced single- and dual-energy abdominopelvic computed tomography in children as a function of patient size. Pediatr Radiol. 2021;51:2000&#x2013;2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34244847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodhi KS, Khandelwal N, Saxena AK, Singh M, Agarwal R, Bhatia A, Lee EY. Rapid lung MRI in children with pulmonary infections: Time to change our diagnostic algorithms. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2016;43:1196&#x2013;1206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26546472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon DZ, Ayalew B, Dellie ST, Admasie D. Justification and Optimization Principles of ALARA in Pediatric CT at a Teaching Hospital in Ethiopia. Ethiop J Health Sci. 2020;30:761&#x2013;766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8047270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33911838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora V, Kaur T, Singh K. The role of magnetic resonance imaging in acute abdominal pain in paediatric age group. Egypt J Radiol Nucl Med. 2022;53:36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson TR. Dual-energy CT: general principles. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2012;199:S3&#x2013;S8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23097165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odedra D, Narayanasamy S, Sabongui S, Priya S, Krishna S, Sheikh A. Dual Energy CT Physics-A Primer for the Emergency Radiologist. Front Radiol. 2022;2:820430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10364985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37492677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel MJ, Ramirez-Giraldo JC. Dual-Energy CT in Children: Imaging Algorithms and Clinical Applications. Radiology. 2019;291:286&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30912717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greffier J, Villani N, Defez D, Dabli D, Si-Mohamed S. Spectral CT imaging: Technical principles of dual-energy CT and multi-energy photon-counting CT. Diagn Interv Imaging. 2023;104:167&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36414506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo-Bernal S, Pe&#xf1;a-Trujillo V, Gee MS. Dual-energy computed tomography: pediatric considerations. Pediatr Radiol. 2024;54:2112&#x2013;2126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39470784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogbole GI. Radiation dose in paediatric computed tomography: risks and benefits. Ann Ib Postgrad Med. 2010;8:118&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4111023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25161479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng CKC. Artificial Intelligence for Radiation Dose Optimization in Pediatric Radiology: A Systematic Review. Children (Basel) 2022;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9320231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35884028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Duan X, Mahmood U, McKenney SE, Brady SL. An adult and pediatric size-based contrast administration reduction phantom study for single and dual-energy CT through preservation of contrast-to-noise ratio. J Appl Clin Med Phys. 2024;25:e14340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11087157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38605540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamps SE, Otjen JP, Stanescu AL, Mileto A, Lee EY, Phillips GS. Dual-Energy CT of Pediatric Abdominal Oncology Imaging: Private Tour of New Applications of CT Technology. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2020;214:967&#x2013;975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32130040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a-Trujillo V, Gallo-Bernal S, Tung EL, Gee MS. Pediatric Applications of Dual-Energy Computed Tomography. Radiol Clin North Am. 2023;61:1069&#x2013;1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37758357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie M, Wang H, Tang S, Chen M, Li T, He L. Application of dual-energy CT with prospective ECG-gating in cardiac CT angiography for children: Radiation and contrast agent dose. Eur J Radiol. 2024;170:111229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38056348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz B, Kuehling K, Kromen W, Siebenhandl P, Kerl MJ, Vogl TJ, Bauer R. Automatic bone removal technique in whole-body dual-energy CT angiography: performance and image quality. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2012;199:W646&#x2013;W650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23096210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SJ, Lim HK, Lee HY, Choi CG, Lee DH, Suh DC, Kim SM, Kim JK, Krauss B. Dual-energy CT in the evaluation of intracerebral hemorrhage of unknown origin: differentiation between tumor bleeding and pure hemorrhage. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2012;33:865&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7968790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22241388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi Y, Shin NY, Jang J, Ahn KJ, Kim BS. Dual-energy CT for differentiating acute intracranial hemorrhage from contrast staining or calcification: a meta-analysis. Neuroradiology. 2020;62:1617&#x2013;1626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32621024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Z, Zhang L, Sun X, Yang M, Makamure J, Wu H, Wang J. Dual-Layer Detector Head CT to Maintain Image Quality While Reducing the Radiation Dose in Pediatric Patients. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2023;44:1212&#x2013;1218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10549953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37735089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibney B, Redmond CE, Byrne D, Mathur S, Murray N. A Review of the Applications of Dual-Energy CT in Acute Neuroimaging. Can Assoc Radiol J. 2020;71:253&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32106693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdellatif W, Ebada MA, Alkanj S, Negida A, Murray N, Khosa F, Nicolaou S. Diagnostic Accuracy of Dual-Energy CT in Detection of Acute Pulmonary Embolism: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Can Assoc Radiol J. 2021;72:285&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32103682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapp JB, Biko DM, Siegel MJ. Dual-Energy CT for Pediatric Thoracic Imaging: A Review. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2023;221:526&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37195790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoey ET, Mirsadraee S, Pepke-Zaba J, Jenkins DP, Gopalan D, Screaton NJ. Dual-energy CT angiography for assessment of regional pulmonary perfusion in patients with chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension: initial experience. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2011;196:524&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21343493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goo HW. Initial experience of dual-energy lung perfusion CT using a dual-source CT system in children. Pediatr Radiol. 2010;40:1536&#x2013;1544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20596701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Suarez KI, Barrera CA, Otero HJ, Biko DM, States LJ, Servaes S, Zhu X, Davis JC, Piccione J, Rapp JB. Pilot study for comparative assessment of dual-energy computed tomography and single-photon emission computed tomography V/Q scanning for lung perfusion evaluation in infants. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2022;57:702&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34914194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel MJ, Bhalla S, Cullinane M. Dual-Energy CT Material Decomposition in Pediatric Thoracic Oncology. Radiol Imaging Cancer. 2021;3:e200097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7983800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33778757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Hur J, Kim YJ, Lee HJ, Hong YJ, Choi BW. Additional value of dual-energy CT to differentiate between benign and malignant mediastinal tumors: an initial experience. Eur J Radiol. 2013;82:2043&#x2013;2049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23820175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coursey CA, Nelson RC, Boll DT, Paulson EK, Ho LM, Neville AM, Marin D, Gupta RT, Schindera ST. Dual-energy multidetector CT: how does it work, what can it tell us, and when can we use it in abdominopelvic imaging? Radiographics. 2010;30:1037&#x2013;1055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20631367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbanna KY, Mohammed MF, Chahal T, Khosa F, Ali IT, Berger FH, Nicolaou S. Dual-Energy CT in Differentiating Nonperforated Gangrenous Appendicitis From Uncomplicated Appendicitis. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2018;211:776&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30063397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Rai R, Mroueh N, Kambadakone A. Role of Dual Energy Computed Tomography in Inflammatory Bowel Disease. Semin Ultrasound CT MR. 2022;43:320&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35738817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;a&#x11f;lar &#xd6;, Cesur E, Sade R, F&#x131;r&#x131;nc&#x131; B, Kara M, &#xc7;elikkaya ME, Oral A, Yi&#x11f;iter M, &#xd6;zmen S. Dual energy CT in necrotizing enterocolitis; a novel diagnostic approach. Turk J Med Sci. 2021;51:2575&#x2013;2583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8742483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34333905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidas G, Eliahou R, Duvdevani M, Coulon P, Lemaitre L, Gofrit ON, Pode D, Sosna J. Determination of renal stone composition with dual-energy CT: in vivo analysis and comparison with x-ray diffraction. Radiology. 2010;257:394&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu B, Jia J, Yu L, Li H, Wang D. Correlative investigation between routine clinical parameters of dual-energy computed tomography and the outcomes of extracorporeal shock wave lithotripsy in children with urolithiasis: a retrospective study. Abdom Radiol (NY) 2021;46:4881&#x2013;4887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34114086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Deng Z, Tan T, Li S, Qian F, He L, Tang S. Application value of split-bolus contrast injection combined with dual-energy CT scanning technology in pediatric CTU imaging. Eur J Radiol. 2025;184:111949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39874617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YJ, Cha JG, Kim H, Yi JS, Kim HJ. Dual-Energy and Iterative Metal Artifact Reduction for Reducing Artifacts Due to Metallic Hardware: A Loosening Hip Phantom Study. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2019;212:1106&#x2013;1111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30835522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer M, Hohenberger P, Apfaltrer P, Henzler T, Dinter DJ, Schoenberg SO, Fink C. CT-based response assessment of advanced gastrointestinal stromal tumor: dual energy CT provides a more predictive imaging biomarker of clinical benefit than RECIST or Choi criteria. Eur J Radiol. 2013;82:923&#x2013;928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23410905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrini S, Bagnacci G, Perrella A, Meglio ND, Sica C, Mazzei MA. Dual Energy CT in Oncology: Benefits for Both Patients and Radiologists From an Emerging Quantitative and Functional Diagnostic Technique. Semin Ultrasound CT MR. 2023;44:205&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37245885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortman JR, Sodickson AD. Pearls, Pitfalls, and Problems in Dual-Energy Computed Tomography Imaging of the Body. Radiol Clin North Am. 2018;56:625&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29936951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parakh A, Lennartz S, An C, Rajiah P, Yeh BM, Simeone FJ, Sahani DV, Kambadakone AR. Dual-Energy CT Images: Pearls and Pitfalls. Radiographics. 2021;41:98&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapp JB, Biko DM, White AM, Ramirez-Suarez KI, Otero HJ. Spectral imaging in the pediatric chest: past, present and future. Pediatr Radiol. 2022;52:1910&#x2013;1920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35726069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granata C, Sofia C, Francavilla M, Kardos M, Kasznia-Brown J, Nievelstein RA, Olteanu BS, Owens C, Salerno S, Sorantin E, Apine I. Let's talk about radiation dose and radiation protection in children. Pediatr Radiol. 2025;55:386&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39095613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Choi YH, Cho YJ, Lee SB, Cheon JE, Kim WS, Ahn CK, Kim JH. Noise reduction approach in pediatric abdominal CT combining deep learning and dual-energy technique. Eur Radiol. 2021;31:2218&#x2013;2226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33030573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41218239</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0852</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>231</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of cancer (Oxford, England : 1990)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incidence, prevalence and treatment of patients with Epithelioid Haemangioendothelioma (EHE) in Canada: A Canadian Sarcoma Research and Clinical Collaboration (CanSaRCC) and Multi-pronged Canadian Research in Epithelioid Haemangioendothelioma (PRO_CARE EHE) study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116100</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116100</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ejca.2025.116100</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0959-8049(25)00986-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Epithelioid Haemangioendothelioma (EHE) is an ultra-rare sarcoma characterized by WWTR1-CAMTA1 or YAP1-TFE3 gene fusions. Clinical behaviour ranges from indolent to aggressive. Due to its rarity, this study aims to describe the presentation, management, and outcomes of EHE patients in Canada.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data was collected and entered to the Canadian Sarcoma Research and Clinical Collaboration (CanSaRCC) database. Patients of all ages with a documented diagnosis of EHE from Nov 1993 to Jan 2024 were included. Patient demographics, disease characteristics and treatment details were collected using a case report form and summarized using descriptive statistics. Kaplan-Meier method was used to estimate overall survival and event free survival. Cox regression was used to estimate factors influencing survival outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In total, 198 patients were included of which 94 (45.7&#x202f;%) presented with metastatic disease. The diagnosis was incidental in 61 patients (31&#x202f;%). The most frequent primary sites were liver (n&#x202f;=&#x202f;56, 28.3&#x202f;%), extremities (n&#x202f;=&#x202f;31, 15.7&#x202f;%) and lungs (n&#x202f;=&#x202f;27, 13.6&#x202f;%). Fusion testing was performed and positive in 43 (22&#x202f;%) patients. At least one line of systemic therapy was used in 55 (27.8&#x202f;%) patients with most common agents including sirolimus, pazopanib and paclitaxel. The median EFS was 5.5 years (95&#x202f;% CI: 3.4-8.5), and the median OS was 8.6 years (95&#x202f;% CI: 5.4 - 16.5). Liver transplant was performed in seven patients. In multivariate analysis, older age, pleural effusion, ascites, primary lung disease and metastatic disease were associated with poor survival outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This is the largest series of EHE patients describing sequential systemic therapies. The role of systemic therapy in EHE in improving survival remains unclear and prospective studies with comparative arms are needed to add further insight into this chronic disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weadick</LastName><ForeName>Catherine S</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Division of Medical Oncology, Mount Sinai Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alshibany</LastName><ForeName>Aisha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Division of Medical Oncology, Mount Sinai Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michael</LastName><ForeName>Michelle Jude</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Division of Haematology/Oncology, Hospital for Sick Children, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holloway</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Radiation Oncology, BC Cancer, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arthur Child Comprehensive Cancer Centre, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lemieux</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service d'H&#xe9;mato-oncologie, CHU de Qu&#xe9;bec-Universit&#xe9; Laval, Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuleshov</LastName><ForeName>Nikol</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service d'H&#xe9;mato-oncologie, CHU de Qu&#xe9;bec-Universit&#xe9; Laval, Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russo</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Radiation Oncology, BC Cancer, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassim</LastName><ForeName>Yusra</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, The Ottawa Hospital, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Styves</LastName><ForeName>Hugo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Haematology, Oncology and Cellular Therapy, Department of Medicine, H&#xf4;pital Maisonneuve-Rosemont, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henning</LastName><ForeName>Evonne</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>McGill University Health Centre, Cedars Cancer Centre, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Werier</LastName><ForeName>Joel</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, The Ottawa Hospital, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saleh</LastName><ForeName>Ramy</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>McGill University Health Centre, Cedars Cancer Centre, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noujaim</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Haematology, Oncology and Cellular Therapy, Department of Medicine, H&#xf4;pital Maisonneuve-Rosemont, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Abha A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Division of Haematology/Oncology, Hospital for Sick Children, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soroka</LastName><ForeName>Hagit Peretz</ForeName><Initials>HP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Division of Haematology/Oncology, Hospital for Sick Children, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Razak</LastName><ForeName>Albiruni Abdul</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Princess Margaret Cancer Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Division of Medical Oncology, Mount Sinai Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada. Electronic address: Albiruni.Razak@uhn.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9005373</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-8049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007191">Indazoles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7RN5DR86CK</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C516667">pazopanib</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011743">Pyrimidines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013449">Sulfonamides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018323" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hemangioendothelioma, Epithelioid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002170" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Canada</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007191" MajorTopicYN="N">Indazoles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011743" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Pyrimidines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013449" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Sulfonamides</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epithelioid Haemangioendothelioma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultra-rare sarcoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular sarcoma</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Dr Albiruni Razak reports financial support was provided by Sarcoma Foundation of Canada. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41218239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2025.116100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0959-8049(25)00986-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41207180</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0852</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>231</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of cancer (Oxford, England : 1990)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Letter Re: Association of pre-surgical circulating tumor DNA detection, use of sublobar resection with risk of recurrence in stage I non-small cell lung cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>115518</StartPage><MedlinePgn>115518</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ejca.2025.115518</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0959-8049(25)00300-4</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Junmei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Northern Theater Command General Hospital, Shenyang, Liaoning 110016, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shuai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Northern Theater Command General Hospital, Shenyang, Liaoning 110016, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Tingting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Northern Theater Command General Hospital, Shenyang, Liaoning 110016, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xuefei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Northern Theater Command General Hospital, Shenyang, Liaoning 110016, China. Electronic address: feiliu6@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016422">Letter</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9005373</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-8049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41207180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2025.115518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0959-8049(25)00300-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41205256</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0852</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>231</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of cancer (Oxford, England : 1990)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular and Clinical characteristics of ROS1 Fusion Variants in ROS1-rearranged Cancers: A Defined Role of Fusion Partners and Breakpoints of ROS1.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116091</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116091</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ejca.2025.116091</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0959-8049(25)00977-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ROS1-targeted tyrosine kinase inhibitors (TKIs) are the standard treatment for ROS1-rearranged cancers. We here investigated the therapeutic significance of multiple fusion partners and variable ROS1 genomic breakpoints.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrieved 81 ROS1-rearranged cases from a clinical DNA-based next generation sequencing cohort and performed comprehensive analyses, including reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction, RNA sequencing and immunohistochemistry staining. The obtained data were correlated with the clinical responses to ROS1-TKIs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">ROS1 fusions with canonical and &#x223c;20 rare fusion partners were identified. ROS1 breaks occurred at rare 12 exon/intron regions together with major breakpoints. High ROS1 expression correlated significantly with major breakpoints and canonical partners and low expression associated with rare breakpoints and non-canonical partners (P&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.001). Cases with an intron 32 ROS1 breakpoint involved exclusion of exon 33 to generate an in-frame fusion, and canonical fusion partners showed a strong preference for an intron 33 to intron 32 breakpoint (P&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.001). Significantly better progression-free survival rates (PFSR) were observed among first-line TKI-treated NSCLC patients with ROS1 breakpoints in introns 33 and 34, compared with intron 32 and rare locations (80&#x202f;%, 33.3&#x202f;%, and 0&#x202f;%, respectively; P&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.001). Patients with at least one major breakpoint or canonical partner also showed significantly better PFSR compared to those with both rare partners and non-major breakpoints (50.4&#x202f;% vs 0&#x202f;%, P&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Canonical fusion partners with introns 33 and 34 of ROS1 may be the most optimal predictors for ROS1-TKI benefit. Precise characterization of the variants in terms of ROS1 breakpoints could be important for patient stratification in ROS1-rearranged cancers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeong</LastName><ForeName>Ji-Seon</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Pathology, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Yeokyeong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Shinkyo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Deokhoon</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Pathology, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sampson</LastName><ForeName>Josephina</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Astbury Centre for Structural Molecular Biology, Faculty of Biological Sciences, University of Leeds, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayliss</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Astbury Centre for Structural Molecular Biology, Faculty of Biological Sciences, University of Leeds, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Jene</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Pathology, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, South Korea. Electronic address: jenec@amc.seoul.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9005373</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-8049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C062333">ROS1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011518">Proto-Oncogene Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011505">Protein-Tyrosine Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015514">Oncogene Proteins, Fusion</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D047428">Protein Kinase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011518" MajorTopicYN="Y">Proto-Oncogene Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011505" MajorTopicYN="Y">Protein-Tyrosine Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015514" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oncogene Proteins, Fusion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015321" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gene Rearrangement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D047428" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Kinase Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056905" MajorTopicYN="N">Chromosome Breakpoints</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breakpoint</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fusion partner</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-small cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ROS1 fusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ROS1-TKI</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41205256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2025.116091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0959-8049(25)00977-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41192233</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0852</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>231</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of cancer (Oxford, England : 1990)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>EORTC 1417 - REACTION: A phase II study of etoposide and cis/carboplatin with or without pembrolizumab in untreated extensive small cell lung cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116059</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116059</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ejca.2025.116059</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0959-8049(25)00945-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Anti-PD-L1 antibodies with platinum-etoposide extend overall survival (OS) of extensive disease Small Cell Lung Cancer (ED-SCLC) patients. We evaluated the benefit of first-line pembrolizumab with platinum-etoposide in chemo-sensitive ED-SCLC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">REACTION is a multicenter, open-label, randomized phase II trial. Eligible patients (responders after 2 cycles of platinum-etoposide) were randomized 1:1 to experimental arm pembrolizumab in combination with 4 cycles of platinum-etoposide then pembrolizumab vs platinum-etoposide in the control arm. The primary endpoint was progression free survival (PFS). Circulating tumour cells (CTCs) were enumerated and their association with PFS and OS was investigated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Between Feb 7, 2018 and Oct 31, 2019, 125 patients were recruited (61 vs 64 experimental and control arms respectively) with 119 (58 vs 61) eligible and receiving at least one dose of treatment. Baseline characteristics were median age 65 vs 63.5 years, PS 1 (62 vs 60&#x202f;%), and brain metastases (8 vs 11&#x202f;%), in the experimental and control arms respectively. Amongst 124 patients who started treatment, 46 (37&#x202f;%) experienced adverse events grade &#x2265;&#x202f;3 for pembrolizumab arm vs 26&#x202f;% in the control arm. Response rate was 61&#x202f;% (67 vs 56&#x202f;%). Median PFS (95&#x202f;% CI) was 4.7 months (4.2, 5.6) vs 5.4 (4.7, 5.6), HR (80&#x202f;% CI) =&#x202f;0.84 (0.65, 1.09) and 1-sided p&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.194. Median OS (95&#x202f;% CI) was 12.3 months (8.9, 14.8) vs 10.4 (8.2, 12.2), HR (80&#x202f;% CI) =&#x202f;0.73 (0.54, 1.0) and 1-sided p&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.097. CTC count per 7.5&#x202f;ml blood at randomization was associated significantly with both PFS and OS regardless of treatment arms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Pembrolizumab added to platinum-etoposide did not improve PFS over platinum-etoposide alone in chemo-sensitive patients with ED.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menis</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospital of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greiller</LastName><ForeName>Laurent</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aix Marseille Univ, APHM, Marseille, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demontrond</LastName><ForeName>Pierre</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Francois Baclesse (CLCC), Caen, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monnet</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Hopitalier Intercommunal De Creteil, Creteil, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Novello</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universita Di Torino, Ospedale S. Luigi, Gonzaga, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Livi</LastName><ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florence, Careggi Hospital, Firenze, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Robin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weston Park Hospital, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Decroisette</LastName><ForeName>Chantal</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Hospitalier D'Annecy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cloarec</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Hospitalier d'Avignon, Avignon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robinet</LastName><ForeName>Gilles</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHU de Brest, Brest, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schott</LastName><ForeName>Roland</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut de Cancerologie (ICANS), Strasbourg, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fayette</LastName><ForeName>Jerome</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Leon Berard, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banna</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe Luigi</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ospedale Cannizzaro, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Marinis</LastName><ForeName>Filippo</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Institute of Oncology (IEO), IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Califano</LastName><ForeName>Raffaele</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Christie NHS Foundation Trust, University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duchemann</LastName><ForeName>Boris</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>APHP Hop Univ Paris Seine-Saint-Denis, Hop Avicenne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luciani</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ospedale San Paolo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colantonio</LastName><ForeName>Ida</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Santa Croce e Carle General Hospital, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fournier</LastName><ForeName>Beatrice</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>EORTC HQ, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pretzenbacher</LastName><ForeName>Yassin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>EORTC HQ, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caramella</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris-Saclay, CEA, CNRS, Inserm, BioMaps, Orsay, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Mario</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Parma, Parma, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berghmans</LastName><ForeName>Thierry</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Jules Bordet, Hopital Universitaire ULB, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dingemans</LastName><ForeName>Anne-Marie</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Erasmus MC, Rotterdam, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bironzo</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ospedale S. Luigi Gonzaga, University of Turin, Orbassano-Torino, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tugwood</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research UK National Biomarker Centre, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Cong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research UK National Biomarker Centre, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>Steven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research UK National Biomarker Centre, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bradbury</LastName><ForeName>Kieran</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research UK National Biomarker Centre, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morris</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research UK National Biomarker Centre, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kilgour</LastName><ForeName>Elaine</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research UK National Biomarker Centre, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dive</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research UK National Biomarker Centre, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blackhall</LastName><ForeName>Fiona</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research UK National Biomarker Centre, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Besse</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paris-Saclay University, Gustave Roussy, Villejuif, France. Electronic address: benjamin.besse@gustaveroussy.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017427">Clinical Trial, Phase II</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9005373</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-8049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>DPT0O3T46P</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C582435">pembrolizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>6PLQ3CP4P3</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005047">Etoposide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>BG3F62OND5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016190">Carboplatin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>Q20Q21Q62J</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002945">Cisplatin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055752" MajorTopicYN="Y">Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005047" MajorTopicYN="N">Etoposide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016190" MajorTopicYN="N">Carboplatin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002945" MajorTopicYN="N">Cisplatin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009360" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplastic Cells, Circulating</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">First line, CTCs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pembrolizumab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Small cell lung cancer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41192233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2025.116059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0959-8049(25)00945-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>