<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41247705</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5709</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of cancer prevention : the official journal of the European Cancer Prevention Organisation (ECP)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Cancer Prev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pancreatic findings in participants in a program of low-dose computed tomography screening for lung cancer.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CEJ.0000000000000997</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study investigates the frequency, progression, and clinical implications of pancreatic findings on chest low-dose computed tomography (LDCT) scans performed for lung cancer screening.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Analyzing data from the I-ELCAP cohort study (February 2010-June 2023), we identified participants with pancreatic findings on LDCT scans, recording demographics and outcomes. Radiologists reviewed baseline and latest LDCT scans.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Out of 9467 participants, 90 (0.9%) had pancreatic findings, mostly male (54.4%), median age 64.7, with smoking (92.2%), alcohol use (41.1%), and diabetes (22%). Of these, 60 (66.7%) were detected on baseline LDCT, primarily as calcifications (73.3%), atrophy/fatty infiltration (18.3%), and duct dilatation (5%). Of the 90 participants, 27 underwent only baseline LDCT. Among the remaining 63, 33 had pancreatic findings on baseline scans, 27 of whom (81.8%) showed consistent findings on follow-up, and 30 developed pancreatic findings during surveillance. Rereview of the baseline scans showed that 68 participants (75.6%) had findings, including eight missed earlier. More cases of atrophy/fatty infiltration and other findings were detected compared to the original report, with calcifications remaining predominant (50 participants). Similar patterns were observed during the rereview of the latest LDCT scans. Two participants with detected lesions underwent biopsy, diagnosing a serous cystadenoma and pancreatic adenocarcinoma. The latter succumbed to pancreatic cancer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Incidental pancreatic findings were uncommon (0.9%) and included calcifications, atrophy/fatty infiltration, cysts, ductal dilatation, and masses. These findings do not by themselves indicate pancreatic cancer but warrant documentation and, when suspicious, dedicated pancreatic imaging. Radiologist scrutiny could improve detection accuracy, indicating the potential of a LDCT lung cancer screening program for detecting and monitoring pancreatic lesions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gros</LastName><ForeName>Louis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic, Molecular, and Interventional Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois (CHUV), Lausanne University, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yip</LastName><ForeName>Rowena</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic, Molecular, and Interventional Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yeqing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic, Molecular, and Interventional Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Pengfei</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic, Molecular, and Interventional Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paksashvili</LastName><ForeName>Natela</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic, Molecular, and Interventional Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic, Molecular, and Interventional Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yankelevitz</LastName><ForeName>David F</ForeName><Initials>DF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic, Molecular, and Interventional Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henschke</LastName><ForeName>Claudia I</ForeName><Initials>CI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic, Molecular, and Interventional Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Cancer Prev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9300837</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-8278</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">early cancer detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung cancer screening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opportunistic findings</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pancreatic lesions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">screening cohort</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41247705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CEJ.0000000000000997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00008469-990000000-00247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aberle DR, Adams AM, Berg CD, Black WC, Clapp JD, Fagerstrom RM, et al.; National Lung Screening Trial Research Team (2011). Reduced lung-cancer mortality with low-dose computed tomographic screening. N Engl J Med 365:395&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PL, Madzak A, Olesen SS, Drewes AM, Fr&#xf8;kjaer JB (2018). Quantification of parenchymal calcifications in chronic pancreatitis: relation to atrophy, ductal changes, fibrosis and clinical parameters. Scand J Gastroenterol 53:218&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz H, Acher AW, Krishna SG, Cloyd JM, Pawlik TM (2022). Comparison of society guidelines for the management and surveillance of pancreatic cysts: a review. JAMA Surg 157:723&#x2013;730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caban M, Ma&#x142;ecka-Wojciesko E (2022). Pancreatic incidentaloma. J Clin Med 11:4648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao K, Xia Y, Yao J, Han X, Lambert L, Zhang T, et al. (2023). Large-scale pancreatic cancer detection via non-contrast CT and deep learning. Nat Med 29:3033&#x2013;3043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Yu Z, Wang J, Cui W, Cui C, Wang Y, et al. (2021). Opportunistic detection for pancreatic cystic lesions during chest multidetector CT scans for lung cancer screening. Cancer Manag Res 13:7559&#x2013;7568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang AL, Lee LS (2016). Clinical approach to incidental pancreatic cysts. World J Gastroenterol 22:1236&#x2013;1245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costache MI, Costache CA, Dumitrescu CI, Tica AA, Popescu M, Baluta EA, et al. (2017). Which is the best imaging method in pancreatic adenocarcinoma diagnosis and staging - CT, MRI or EUS? Curr Health Sci J 43:132&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dbouk M, Brewer Gutierrez OI, Lennon AM, Chuidian M, Shin EJ, Kamel IR, et al. (2021). Guidelines on management of pancreatic cysts detected in high-risk individuals: an evaluation of the 2017 Fukuoka guidelines and the 2020 International Cancer of the Pancreas Screening (CAPS) consortium statements. Pancreatology 21:613&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elta GH, Enestvedt BK, Sauer BG, Lennon AM (2018). ACG clinical guideline: diagnosis and management of pancreatic cysts. Am J Gastroenterol 113:464&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung CI, Bigam DL, Wong CKW, Hurrell C, Bird JR, Brahm GL, Kirkpatrick IDC (2022). Recommendations for the management of incidental pancreatic findings in adults by the Canadian Association of Radiologists Incidental Findings Working Group. Can Assoc Radiol J 73:312&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gros L, Yip R, Zhu Y, Li P, Paksashvili N, Sun Q, et al. (2024). GI cancer mortality in participants in low dose CT screening for lung cancer with a focus on pancreatic cancer. Sci Rep 14:29851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecht HS, Henschke C, Yankelevitz D, Fuster V, Narula J (2014). Combined detection of coronary artery disease and lung cancer. Eur Heart J 35:2792&#x2013;2796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henrikson NB, Aiello Bowles EJ, Blasi PR, Morrison CC, Nguyen M, Pillarisetty VG, Lin JS (2019). Screening for pancreatic cancer: updated evidence report and systematic review for the US Preventive Services Task Force. JAMA 322:445&#x2013;454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henschke CI, McCauley DI, Yankelevitz DF, Naidich DP, McGuinness G, Miettinen OS, et al. (1999). Early Lung Cancer Action Project: overall design and findings from baseline screening. Lancet 354:99&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henschke CI, Yip R, Shaham D, Markowitz S, Cervera Deval J, Zulueta JJ, et al.; International Early Lung Cancer Action Program Investigators (2023). A 20-year follow-up of the international early lung cancer action program (I-ELCAP). Radiology 309:e231988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hori M, Takahashi M, Hiraoka N, Yamaji T, Mutoh M, Ishigamori R, et al. (2014). Association of pancreatic fatty infiltration with pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Clin Transl Gastroenterol 5:e53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koiwai A, Hirota M, Matsuura T, Itoh T, Kin R, Katayama T, et al. (2023). Diffuse pancreatic parenchymal atrophy, an imaging finding predictive of the development of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma: a case-control study. JGH Open 7:445&#x2013;452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Koning HJ, van der Aalst CM, de Jong PA, Scholten ET, Nackaerts K, Heuvelmans MA, et al. (2020). Reduced lung-cancer mortality with volume CT screening in a randomized trial. N Engl J Med 382:503&#x2013;513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kromrey ML, B&#xfc;low R, H&#xfc;bner J, Paperlein C, Lerch MM, Ittermann T, et al. (2018). Prospective study on the incidence, prevalence and 5-year pancreatic-related mortality of pancreatic cysts in a population-based study. Gut 67:138&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesniak RJ, Hohenwalter MD, Taylor AJ (2002). Spectrum of causes of pancreatic calcifications. AJR Am J Roentgenol 178:79&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma S, Sokale IO, Thrift AP (2023). Trends and variations in pancreatic cancer mortality among us metro and nonmetro adults, 1999-2020. J Clin Gastroenterol 58:627&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolies LR, Salvatore M, Yip R, Tam K, Bertolini A, Henschke C, Yankelevitz D (2018). The chest radiologist's role in invasive breast cancer detection. Clin Imaging 50:13&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megibow AJ, Baker ME, Morgan DE, Kamel IR, Sahani DV, Newman E, et al. (2017). Management of incidental pancreatic cysts: a white paper of the ACR incidental findings committee. J Am Coll Radiol 14:911&#x2013;923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulshine JL, Avila RS, Silva M, Aldige C, Blum T, Cham M, et al. (2025). AI integrations with lung cancer screening: considerations in developing AI in a public health setting. Eur J Cancer 220:115345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulshine JL, Pyenson B, Healton C, Aldige C, Avila RS, Blum T, et al. (2025). Paradigm shift in early detection: lung cancer screening to comprehensive CT screening. Eur J Cancer 218:115264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owens DK, Davidson KW, Krist AH, Barry MJ, Cabana M, Caughey AB, et al.; US Preventive Services Task Force (2019). Screening for pancreatic cancer: US preventive services task force reaffirmation recommendation statement. JAMA 322:438&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HJ, Shin K, You MW, Kyung SG, Kim SY, Park SH, et al. (2023). Deep learning-based detection of solid and cystic pancreatic neoplasms at contrast-enhanced CT. Radiology 306:140&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweber AB, Agarunov E, Brooks C, Hur C, Gonda TA (2021). Prevalence, incidence, and risk of progression of asymptomatic pancreatic cysts in large sample real-world data. Pancreas 50:1287&#x2013;1292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith WC, Khatri G, Dunn SH, Zeidan N, Browning TG, Kubiliun N, et al. (2021). Facilitating surveillance of incidental findings using a novel reporting template: proof of concept in patients with pancreatic abnormalities. J Am Coll Radiol 18:1246&#x2013;1257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiger D, Siddiqi MF, Yip R, Yankelevitz DF, Henschke CI; I-ELCAP investigators (2021). The importance of low-dose CT screening to identify emphysema in asymptomatic participants with and without a prior diagnosis of COPD. Clin Imaging 78:136&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugawara H, Yoshikawa T, Kunimatsu A, Akai H, Yasaka K, Abe O (2021). Detectability of pancreatic lesions by low-dose unenhanced computed tomography using iterative reconstruction. Eur J Radiol 141:109776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirkes T, Shah ZK, Takahashi N, Grajo JR, Chang ST, Venkatesh SK, et al.; Consortium for the Study of Chronic Pancreatitis, Diabetes, and Pancreatic Cancer (2019). Reporting standards for chronic pancreatitis by using CT, MRI, and MR cholangiopancreatography: the consortium for the study of chronic pancreatitis, diabetes, and pancreatic cancer. Radiology 290:207&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomita Y, Azuma K, Nonaka Y, Kamada Y, Tomoeda M, Kishida M, et al. (2014). Pancreatic fatty degeneration and fibrosis as predisposing factors for the development of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Pancreas 43:1032&#x2013;1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittram R, Kreis L, K&#xf6;nig HH, Brettschneider C (2025). Economic evaluations of early detection strategies for pancreatic cancer: a systematic review. Eur J Health Econ [Epub ahead of print]. doi:10.1007/s10198-025-01793-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10198-025-01793-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip R, Jirapatnakul A, Hu M, Chen X, Han D, Ma T, et al. (2021). Added benefits of early detection of other diseases on low-dose CT screening. Transl Lung Cancer Res 10:1141&#x2013;1153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Cao Y, Ren S, Guo K, Zhang Y, Lin T, et al. (2023). Threshold of main pancreatic duct diameter in identifying malignant intraductal papillary mucinous neoplasm by magnetic resonance imaging. Technol Cancer Res Treat 22:15330338231170942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Triphuridet N, Yip R, Becker BJ, Wang Y, Yankelevitz DF, Henschke CI (2021). Opportunistic CT screening of osteoporosis on thoracic and lumbar spine: a meta-analysis. Clin Imaging 80:382&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41247704</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5709</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of cancer prevention : the official journal of the European Cancer Prevention Organisation (ECP)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Cancer Prev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Microplastics and cancer.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CEJ.0000000000000999</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The pervasive spread of microplastics (MPs) in the environment (including air, water, and food) has raised concerns regarding human health. These pollutants have been detected in various human tissues such as lungs, colon, blood, placenta, tumors, and body fluids. MPs may act as vectors for toxic and carcinogenic substances, including heavy metals and persistent organic pollutants. They can induce oxidative stress, inflammation, and genotoxicity, thereby altering cellular and metabolic processes, mechanisms implicated in cancer pathogenesis. Recent studies highlight the presence of MPs in human tumor tissues, often at higher concentrations than in adjacent healthy tissues. A relation between MPs exposure and increased risk of colorectal cancer has been observed, where MPs may promote lipid absorption and suppress pyroptosis, contributing to chemoresistance. In the lung, metal-microplastic complexes have been associated with reduced overall survival and disease-specific survival in patients with lung adenocarcinoma. MPs may influence tumor progression, metastasis, and drug resistance. While oncogenic mechanisms are biologically plausible and supported by experimental studies, no clinical nor epidemiological evidence supporting the causal association between MPs and cancer is available.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogani</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Gynecologic Oncologic Unit, Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Nazionale dei Tumori, Milano.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trimarchi</LastName><ForeName>Erica</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Gynecologic Oncologic Unit, Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Nazionale dei Tumori, Milano.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiappa</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Gynecologic Oncologic Unit, Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Nazionale dei Tumori, Milano.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vizzielli</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Area (DAME), University of Udine, Clinic of Obstetrics and Gynecology, 'Santa Maria Della Misericordia' University Hospital, Azienda Sanitaria Universitaria Friuli Centrale, Udine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raspagliesi</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Gynecologic Oncologic Unit, Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Nazionale dei Tumori, Milano.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>La Vecchia</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences and Community Health, University of Milan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corso</LastName><ForeName>Giovanni</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Breast Surgery, European Institute of Oncology, IRCCS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology and Hemato-Oncology, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Cancer Prev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9300837</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-8278</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemoresistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microplastics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41247704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CEJ.0000000000000999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00008469-990000000-00248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baspakova A, Zare A, Suleimenova R, Berdygaliev AB, Karimsakova B, Tussupkaliyeva K, et al. (2025). An updated systematic review about various effects of microplastics on cancer: a pharmacological and in-silico based analysis. Mol Aspects Med 101:101336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernhardt SM, House CD (2025). Bisphenol A and DDT disrupt adipocyte function in the mammary gland: implications for breast cancer risk and progression. Front Oncol 15:1490898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocker R, Silva EK (2025). Microplastics in our diet: a growing concern for human health. Sci Total Environ 968:178882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty S, Banerjee M, Jayaraman G, Rajeswari VD (2024). Evaluation of the health impacts and deregulation of signaling pathways in humans induced by microplastics. Chemosphere 369:143881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chartres N, Cooper CB, Bland G, Pelch KE, Gandhi SA, BakenRa A, Woodruff TJ (2024). Effects of microplastic exposure on human digestive, reproductive, and respiratory health: a rapid systematic review. Environ Sci Technol 58:22843&#x2013;22864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Zhang Z, Ji K, Zhang Q, Qian L, Yang C (2025). Role of microplastics in the tumor microenvironment (Review). Oncol Lett 29:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y, Yang Y, Bai L, Cui J (2024). Microplastics: an often-overlooked issue in the transition from chronic inflammation to cancer. J Transl Med 22:959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citarella A, Besharat ZM, Coppola L, Sabato C, Autilio TM, Vicentini E, et al. (2025). Bisphenol A drives nuclear factor-kappa B signaling activation and enhanced motility in non-transformed breast cells. Environ Pollut 376:126422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das A (2023). The emerging role of microplastics in systemic toxicity: involvement of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Sci Total Environ 895:165076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva VH, Murphy F, Amigo JM, Stedmon C, Strand J (2020). Classification and quantification of microplastics (&lt;100 &#x3bc;m) using a focal plane array&#x2013;Fourier transform infrared imaging system and machine learning. Anal Chem 92:13724&#x2013;13733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng X, Gui Y, Zhao L (2025). The micro(nano)plastics perspective: exploring cancer development and therapy. Mol Cancer 24:30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira RB, Pelepenko LE, Masaro DA, Lustosa GMMM, De Oliveira MC, Roza NAV, et al. (2024). Effects of microplastics on the kidneys: a narrative review. Kidney Int 106:400&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derkaczew M, Zglejc-Waszak K, Dabrowski L, Kocik J, Zdaniukiewicz A, Thoene M, et al. (2025). An analysis of the role of bisphenol A in breast and reproductive-system cancers. J Clin Med 14:4706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dokl M, Copot A, Krajnc D, Fan YV, Vujanovi&#x107; A, Aviso KB, et al. (2024). Global projections of plastic use, end-of-life fate and potential changes in consumption, reduction, recycling and replacement with bioplastics to 2050. Sustain Prod Consum 51:498&#x2013;518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong C, Xu H, Lin Y, Zhang B, Yu Z, Xie Y, et al. (2024). Microplastics detected in three types of female reproductive organs using micro-Raman spectroscopy. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf 285:117099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong C, Xu H, Zhang B, Lin Y, Song J, Yu J, Ma D (2025). Microplastic accumulation in endometrial cancer tissues and its metabolic impact. Environ Pollut 384:127005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du F, Cai H, Zhang Q, Chen Q, Shi H (2020). Microplastics in take-out food containers. J Hazard Mater 399:122969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enyoh CE, Shafea L, Verla AW, Verla EN, Qingyue W, Chowdhury T, Paredes M (2020). Microplastics exposure routes and toxicity studies to ecosystems: an overview. Environ Anal Health Toxicol 35:e2020004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fackelmann G, Sommer S (2019). Microplastics and the gut microbiome: how chronically exposed species may suffer from gut dysbiosis. Mar Pollut Bull 143:193&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ga&#x142;&#x119;ziewska J, Gromek P, Kruczkowska W, Grabowska K, J&#x119;ckowski M, Capuano F, et al. (2025). Evaluating the relationship between microplastics and nanoplastics contamination and diverse cancer types development. Environ Pollut 385:127052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gecegelen E, Ucdal M, Dogu BB (2025). A novel risk factor for dementia: chronic microplastic exposure. Front Neurol 16:1581109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goswami S, Adhikary S, Bhattacharya S, Agarwal R, Ganguly A, Nanda S, Rajak P (2024). The alarming link between environmental microplastics and health hazards with special emphasis on cancer. Life Sci 355:122937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang HG, Nguyen NSH, Zhang T, Tran HT, Mukherjee S, Naidu R (2025). A review of microplastic pollution and human health risk assessment: current knowledge and future outlook. Front Environ Sci 13:1606332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu L, Zhao Y, Xu H (2022). Trojan horse in the intestine: a review on the biotoxicity of microplastics combined environmental contaminants. J Hazard Mater 439:129652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu D, Liu H, Guo Y, Zhang H, Qiu M, Yang Z, et al. 2025a). Microplastics promote chemoresistance by mediating lipid metabolism and suppressing pyroptosis in colorectal cancer. Apoptosis 30:2287&#x2013;2300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Song Z, Li J, Yang F, Li L (2025b). Microplastics and gynecological tumors: an emerging environmental health concern. Reprod Toxicol 137:109018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Lei P, Yu H, Du J, Wu B, Wang H, et al. (2024). Micro/nano plastics in the urinary system: pathways, mechanisms, and health risks. Environ Int 193:109109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadac-Czapska K, Knez E, Grembecka M (2024). Food and human safety: the impact of microplastics. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 64:3502&#x2013;3521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedzierski M, Lechat B, Sire O, Le Maguer G, Le Tilly V, Bruzaud S (2020). Microplastic contamination of packaged meat: occurrence and associated risks. Food Packag Shelf Life 24:100489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kek HY, Tan H, Othman MHD, Nyakuma BB, Ho WS, Sheng DDCV, et al. (2024). Critical review on airborne microplastics: an indoor air contaminant of emerging concern. Environ Res 245:118055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R, Manna C, Padha S, Verma A, Sharma P, Dhar A, et al. (2022). Micro(nano)plastics pollution and human health: how plastics can induce carcinogenesis to humans? Chemosphere 298:134267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N, Lamba M, Pachar AK, Yadav S, Acharya A (2024). Microplastics &#x2013; A growing concern as carcinogens in cancer etiology: emphasis on biochemical and molecular mechanisms. Cell Biochem Biophys 82:3109&#x2013;3121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Porta E, Exacoustos O, Lugani F, Angeletti A, Chiarenza DS, Bigatti C, et al. (2023). Microplastics and kidneys: an update on the evidence for deposition of plastic microparticles in human organs, tissues and fluids and renal toxicity concern. Int J Mol Sci 24:14391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Chen L, Zhou N, Chen Y, Ling Z, Xiang P (2024). Microplastics in the human body: a comprehensive review of exposure, distribution, migration mechanisms, and toxicity. Sci Total Environ 946:174215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Liu X, Guo J, Yang R, Wang H, Sun Y, et al. (2023). The association between microplastics and microbiota in placentas and meconium: the first evidence in humans. Environ Sci Technol 57:17774&#x2013;17785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wang L, Liu X, Yu P, Diao Y, Chen T, et al. (2025). Microplastics, plastics, and their products exposures and cancer: a pooled analysis. Int J Surg 111:5593&#x2013;5605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mashayekhi-Sardoo H, Ghoreshi ZAS, Askarpour H, Arefinia N, Ali-Hassanzadeh M (2025). The clinical relevance of microplastic exposure on colorectal cancer: a systematic review. Cancer Epidemiol 97:102840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayanathara Thathsarani Pilapitiya PGC, Ratnayake AS (2024). The world of plastic waste: a review. Clean Mater 11:100220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihart AJ, Garcia MA, El Hayek E, Liu R, Olewine M, Kingston JD, et al. (2025). Bioaccumulation of microplastics in decedent human brains. Nat Med 31:1114&#x2013;1119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida A, Andoh A (2025). The role of inflammation in cancer: mechanisms of tumor initiation, progression, and metastasis. Cells 14:488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Callaghan L, Olsen M, Tajouri L, Beaver D, Hudson C, Alghafri R, et al. (2025). Plastic induced urinary tract disease and dysfunction: a scoping review. J Expo Sci Environ Epidemiol 35:770&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan W, Han Y, Zhang M, Zhu K, Yang Z, Qiu M, et al. (2025). Effects of microplastics on chemo-resistance and tumorigenesis of colorectal cancer. Apoptosis 30:1005&#x2013;1020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Hong S, Kim OH, Kim CH, Kim J, Kim JW, et al. (2023). Polypropylene microplastics promote metastatic features in human breast cancer. Sci Rep 13:6252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pironti C, Ricciardi M, Motta O, Miele Y, Proto A, Montano L (2021). Microplastics in the environment: intake through the food web, human exposure and toxicological effects. Toxics 9:224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prata JC, Da Costa JP, Lopes I, Duarte AC, Rocha-Santos T (2020). Environmental exposure to microplastics: an overview on possible human health effects. Sci Total Environ 702:134455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragusa A, Svelato A, Santacroce C, Catalano P, Notarstefano V, Carnevali O, et al. (2021). Plasticenta: first evidence of microplastics in human placenta. Environ Int 146:106274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roslan NS, Lee YY, Ibrahim YS, Tuan Anuar S, Yusof KMKK, Lai LA, Brentnall T (2024). Detection of microplastics in human tissues and organs: a scoping review. J Glob Health 14:04179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santizo KY, Mangold HS, Mirzaei Z, Park H, Kolan RR, Sarau G, et al. (2025). Microplastic materials for inhalation studies: preparation by solvent precipitation and comprehensive characterization. Small 21:e2405555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos AL, Rodrigues CC, Oliveira M, Rocha TL (2022). Microbiome: a forgotten target of environmental micro(nano)plastics? Sci Total Environ 822:153628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnee M, Sieler M, D&#xf6;rnen J, Dittmar T (2024). Effects of polystyrene nano- and microplastics on human breast epithelial cells and human breast cancer cells. Heliyon 10:e38686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shruti VC, P&#xe9;rez-Guevara F, Elizalde-Mart&#xed;nez I, Kutralam-Muniasamy G (2021). Toward a unified framework for investigating micro(nano)plastics in packaged beverages intended for human consumption. Environ Pollut 268:115811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Sui M, Wang T, Teng X, Sun J, Chen M (2024). Detection and quantification of various microplastics in human endometrium based on laser direct infrared spectroscopy. Sci Total Environ 906:167760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Z, Ding B, Guo Y, Zhou J, Jiang S, Lu J, et al. (2025). Microplastics accumulated in breast cancer patients lead to mitophagy via ANXA2-mediated endocytosis and IL-17 signaling pathway. Environ Pollut 364:125321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdivia S, Riquelme C, Carrasco MC, Weisser P, A&#xf1;azco C, Alarc&#xf3;n A, Alarc&#xf3;n S (2025). Polyethylene microplastics and human cells: a critical review. Toxics 13:756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen J, Lin Y (2025). Invisible invaders: unveiling the carcinogenic threat of microplastics and nanoplastics in colorectal cancer-a systematic review. Front Public Health 13:1653245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolff CM, Singer D, Schmidt A, Bekeschus S (2023). Immune and inflammatory responses of human macrophages, dendritic cells, and T-cells in presence of micro- and nanoplastic of different types and sizes. J Hazard Mater 459:132194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Dong C, Yu Z, Ozaki Y, Hu Z, Zhang B, et al. (2024). Detection and analysis of microplastics in tissues and blood of human cervical cancer patients. Environ Res 259:119498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Qu J, Jin H, Mao W (2025a). Associations between microplastics in human feces and colorectal cancer risk. J Hazard Mater 495:139099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Dong C, Zhang B, Jin Y, Cheng J, Yu Z, et al. 2025b). The role of microplastics in elevated risk and tissues metabolic alterations in uterine fibroid of female patients. Environ Pollut 374:126251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin YC, Zhang W, He J, He CX, Xu P (2025). Polyethylene terephthalate microplastics induce immune evasion and malignant remodeling in breast cancer through multi-omics-identified immune checkpoints. Food Chem Toxicol 206:115725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Wei C, Liu X, Zhang Z, Wu Y, Zeng B, et al. (2025). Revealing the role of bisphenol A on prostate cancer progression and identifying potential targets: a comprehensive analysis from population cohort to molecular mechanism. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf 296:118209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuri G, Karanasiou A, Lacorte S (2023). Microplastics: human exposure assessment through air, water, and food. Environ Int 179:108150.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41246950</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-0237</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of thoracic imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Thorac Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leveraging Artificial Intelligence to Transform Thoracic Radiology for Lung Nodules and Lung Cancer: Applications, Challenges, and Future Directions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000866</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This review traces the historical path of artificial intelligence (AI) methods that have been applied to medical image interpretation. Early AI approaches, which were based on clinical expertise and domain-specific medical knowledge, established the basis for data-driven methods, initiating the radiomics era and leading to the widespread use of deep learning in medical imaging. More recently, transformer architectures-originally developed for natural language processing-have been adapted for medical image analysis. In the first section, we explore the literature on the use of AI, specifically addressing lung nodules and lung cancer. AI has been effective in detecting lung nodules, evaluating their characteristics, and predicting cancer risk, while also addressing technical issues like kernel conversion. In lung cancer, AI has been applied to various clinical needs, including prognosis evaluation, mutation identification, treatment response analysis, operability prediction, treatment-related pneumonitis, and clinical information extraction. In the following section, we explore foundation models, multimodal AI, and a multiomic approach in the field of lung nodules and lung cancer. Finally, as AI models continue to evolve, so too must the approaches for evaluating their real-world utility; thus, we outline relevant methods for evaluating the performance and application of AI in thoracic radiology.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Geewon</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Center for Imaging Science, Samsung Medical Center, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Medical Research Institute, Pusan National University Hospital, Pusan National University School of Medicine, Busan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Hwan-Ho</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics Engineering, Incheon National University, Incheon, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeong</LastName><ForeName>Dong Young</ForeName><Initials>DY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Center for Imaging Science, Samsung Medical Center, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jong Hoon</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Technology, Samsung Advanced Institute for Health Sciences and Technology, Sungkyunkwan University, Seoul.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>You Jin</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Technology, Samsung Advanced Institute for Health Sciences and Technology, Sungkyunkwan University, Seoul.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Sung Goo</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Center for Imaging Science, Samsung Medical Center, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Ho Yun</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Center for Imaging Science, Samsung Medical Center, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Technology, Samsung Advanced Institute for Health Sciences and Technology, Sungkyunkwan University, Seoul.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No.NRF-2022R1A2C1003999</GrantID><Agency>Korea government</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>#SMO1250061</GrantID><Agency>Samsung Medical Center</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No.RS-2021-II212068, Artificial Intelligence Innovation Hub</GrantID><Agency>Korea government</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Thorac Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8606160</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0883-5993</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung nodule</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41246950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005382-990000000-00203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kim B, Koopmanschap I, Mehrizi MHR, et al. How does the radiology community discuss the benefits and limitations of artificial intelligence for their work? A systematic discourse analysis. Eur J Radiol. 2021;136:109566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciompi F, Chung K, van Riel SJ, et al. Towards automatic pulmonary nodule management in lung cancer screening with deep learning. Sci Rep. 2017;7:46479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui S, Ming S, Lin Y, et al. Development and clinical application of deep learning model for lung nodules screening on CT images. Sci Rep. 2020;10:13657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Lv W, Zhou C, et al. Discrimination between transient and persistent subsolid pulmonary nodules on baseline CT using deep transfer learning. Eur Radiol. 2020;30:6913&#x2013;6923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosny A, Parmar C, Coroller TP, et al. Deep learning for lung cancer prognostication: a retrospective multi-cohort radiomics study. PLoS Med. 2018;15:e1002711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park C, Jeong DY, Choi Y, et al. Tumor-infiltrating lymphocyte enrichment predicted by CT radiomics analysis is associated with clinical outcomes of non-small cell lung cancer patients receiving immune checkpoint inhibitors. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1038089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi K. Computer-aided diagnosis in medical imaging: historical review, current status and future potential. Comput Med Imaging Graph. 2007;31:198&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurland BF, Gerstner ER, Mountz JM, et al. Promise and pitfalls of quantitative imaging in oncology clinical trials. Magn Reson Imaging. 2012;30:1301&#x2013;1312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckler AJ, Bresolin L, Dunnick NR, et al. Quantitative imaging test approval and biomarker qualification: interrelated but distinct activities. Radiology. 2011;259:875&#x2013;884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aerts HJ, Velazquez ER, Leijenaar RT, et al. Decoding tumour phenotype by noninvasive imaging using a quantitative radiomics approach. Nat Commun. 2014;5:4006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haralick RM, Shanmugam K, Dinstein I. Textural features for image classification. IEEE T Syst Man Cyb. 1973;Smc3:610&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip SS, Aerts HJ. Applications and limitations of radiomics. Phys Med Biol. 2016;61:R150&#x2013;R166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criminisi A. Machine learning for medical images analysis. Med Image Anal. 2016;33:91&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen D, Wu G, Suk HI. Deep learning in medical image analysis. Annu Rev Biomed Eng. 2017;19:221&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeCun Y, Bengio Y, Hinton G. Deep learning. Nature. 2015;521:436&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu JX, Wang ZH, Kuen J, et al. Recent advances in convolutional neural networks. Pattern Recogn. 2018;77:354&#x2013;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani A, Shazeer N, Parmar N, et al. Attention is all you need. Adv Neur In. 2017;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Lin YT, Cao Y, et al. Swin Transformer: Hierarchical Vision Transformer using Shifted Windows. 2021 Ieee/Cvf International Conference on Computer Vision (Iccv 2021) 2021:9992-10002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford A, Kim JW, Hallacy C, et al. Learning transferable visual models from natural language supervision. Pr Mach Learn Res. 2021;139:8748&#x2013;8763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu HT, Li CY, Wu QY, et al. Visual Instruction Tuning. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 36 (Neurips 2023) 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JW, Lee SM. Radiomics in oncological PET/CT: clinical applications. Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2018;52:170&#x2013;189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang B, Sollee J, Luo YH, et al. Prediction of lung malignancy progression and survival with machine learning based on pre-treatment FDG-PET/CT. EBioMedicine. 2022;82:104127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavelli G, Giampalma E. Sensitivity and specificity of chest X-ray screening for lung cancer: review article. Cancer. 2000;89:2453&#x2013;2456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quekel LG, Kessels AG, Goei R, et al. Miss rate of lung cancer on the chest radiograph in clinical practice. Chest. 1999;115:720&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam JG, Park S, Hwang EJ, et al. Development and validation of deep learning-based automatic detection algorithm for malignant pulmonary nodules on chest radiographs. Radiology. 2019;290:218&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo H, Kim KH, Singh R, et al. Validation of a deep learning algorithm for the detection of malignant pulmonary nodules in chest radiographs. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e2017135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majkowska A, Mittal S, Steiner DF, et al. Chest radiograph interpretation with deep learning models: assessment with radiologist-adjudicated reference standards and population-adjusted evaluation. Radiology. 2020;294:421&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam JG, Hwang EJ, Kim J, et al. AI improves nodule detection on chest radiographs in a health screening population: a randomized controlled trial. Radiology. 2023;307:e221894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geppert J, Asgharzadeh A, Brown A, et al. Software using artificial intelligence for nodule and cancer detection in CT lung cancer screening: systematic review of test accuracy studies. Thorax. 2024;79:1040&#x2013;1049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu HH, Ko KH, Chou YC, et al. Performance and reading time of lung nodule identification on multidetector CT with or without an artificial intelligence-powered computer-aided detection system. Clin Radiol. 2021;76:626 e623&#x2013;626 e632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Riel SJ, Sanchez CI, Bankier AA, et al. Observer variability for classification of pulmonary nodules on low-dose ct images and its effect on nodule management. Radiology. 2015;277:863&#x2013;871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrix W, Hendrix N, Scholten ET, et al. Deep learning for the detection of benign and malignant pulmonary nodules in non-screening chest CT scans. Commun Med (Lond). 2023;3:156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Causey JL, Zhang J, Ma S, et al. Highly accurate model for prediction of lung nodule malignancy with CT scans. Sci Rep. 2018;8:9286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikhael PG, Wohlwend J, Yala A, et al. Sybil: a validated deep learning model to predict future lung cancer risk from a single low-dose chest computed tomography. J Clin Oncol. 2023;41:2191&#x2013;2200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balagurunathan Y, Schabath MB, Wang H, et al. Quantitative imaging features improve discrimination of malignancy in pulmonary nodules. Sci Rep. 2019;9:8528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang P, Lin CT, Li Y, et al. Prediction of lung cancer risk at follow-up screening with low-dose CT: a training and validation study of a deep learning method. Lancet Digit Health. 2019;1:e353&#x2013;e362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang HJ, Kim H, Seo JB, et al. Generative adversarial network-based image conversion among different computed tomography protocols and vendors: effects on accuracy and variability in quantifying regional disease patterns of interstitial lung disease. Korean J Radiol. 2023;24:807&#x2013;820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang MH, Kang S, Lee JW, et al. Deep learning-based reconstruction algorithm with lung enhancement filter for chest CT: effect on image quality and ground glass nodule sharpness. Korean J Radiol. 2024;25:833&#x2013;842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo SJ, Park YS, Choi H, et al. Prospective evaluation of deep learning image reconstruction for Lung-RADS and automatic nodule volumetry on ultralow-dose chest CT. PLoS One. 2024;19:e0297390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan T, Zeng F, Yi Z, et al. ICNoduleNet: enhancing pulmonary nodule detection performance on sharp kernel CT imaging. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. 2024;28:4751&#x2013;4760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choe J, Lee SM, Do KH, et al. Deep learning-based image conversion of CT reconstruction kernels improves radiomics reproducibility for pulmonary nodules or masses. Radiology. 2019;292:365&#x2013;373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho HH, Lee HY, Kim E, et al. Radiomics-guided deep neural networks stratify lung adenocarcinoma prognosis from CT scans. Commun Biol. 2021;4:1286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Goo JM, Lee KH, et al. Preoperative CT-based deep learning model for predicting disease-free survival in patients with lung adenocarcinomas. Radiology. 2020;296:216&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Y, She Y, Deng J, et al. Deep learning for prediction of N2 metastasis and survival for clinical stage i non-small cell lung cancer. Radiology. 2022;302:200&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Hosny A, Zeleznik R, et al. Deep learning predicts lung cancer treatment response from serial medical imaging. Clin Cancer Res. 2019;25:3266&#x2013;3275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Huang X, Wang K, et al. Habitat-based radiomics from contrast-enhanced CT and clinical data to predict lymph node metastasis in clinical N0 peripheral lung adenocarcinoma &lt;/= 3 cm. Sci Rep. 2025;15:17085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Shi J, Ye Z, et al. Predicting EGFR mutation status in lung adenocarcinoma on computed tomography image using deep learning. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1800986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon HJ, Choi J, Kim E, et al. Deep learning analysis to predict EGFR mutation status in lung adenocarcinoma manifesting as pure ground-glass opacity nodules on CT. Front Oncol. 2022;12:951575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batra U, Nathany S, Nath SK, et al. AI-based pipeline for early screening of lung cancer: integrating radiology, clinical, and genomics data. Lancet Reg Health Southeast Asia. 2024;24:100352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da-Ano R, Andrade-Miranda G, Tankyevych O, et al. Automated PD-L1 status prediction in lung cancer with multi-modal PET/CT fusion. Sci Rep. 2024;14:16720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang M, Sun D, Guo Y, et al. Assessing PD-L1 expression level by radiomic features from PET/CT in nonsmall cell lung cancer patients: an initial result. Acad Radiol. 2020;27:171&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee G, Moon SH, Kim JH, et al. Multimodal imaging approach for tumor treatment response evaluation in the era of immunotherapy. Invest Radiol. 2025;60:11&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Luo X, Yang L, et al. Progression-free survival prediction model based on AI-enhanced dynamic radiomics for personalized EGFR-TKI treatment monitoring patients with lung adenocarcinoma. Thorac Cancer. 2025;16:e70010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye G, Wu G, Qi Y, et al. Non-invasive multimodal CT deep learning biomarker to predict pathological complete response of non-small cell lung cancer following neoadjuvant immunochemotherapy: a multicenter study. J Immunother Cancer. 2024;12:e009348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbour KC, Luu AT, Luo J, et al. Deep learning to estimate RECIST in patients with NSCLC treated with PD-1 blockade. Cancer Discov. 2021;11:59&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin W, Tian Y, Xuzhang W, et al. Non-linear modifications enhance prediction of pathological response to pre-operative PD-1 blockade in lung cancer: a longitudinal hybrid radiological model. Pharmacol Res. 2023;198:106992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Kim J, Jeong U, et al. Robust imaging approach for precise prediction of postoperative lung function in lung cancer patients prior to curative operation. Thorac Cancer. 2024;15:35&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topalovic M, Das N, Burgel PR, et al. Artificial intelligence outperforms pulmonologists in the interpretation of pulmonary function tests. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1801660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Xu H, Qi Q, et al. AI-based chest CT semantic segmentation algorithm enables semi-automated lung cancer surgery planning by recognizing anatomical variants of pulmonary vessels. Front Oncol. 2022;12:1021084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng SC, Lee HY, Nishino M. Imaging of drug-related pneumonitis in oncology. Semin Respir Crit Care Med. 2022;43:887&#x2013;898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan P, Huang W, Wang L, et al. Deep learning predicts immune checkpoint inhibitor-related pneumonitis from pretreatment computed tomography images. Front Physiol. 2022;13:978222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su W, Cheng D, Ni W, et al. Multi-omics deep learning for radiation pneumonitis prediction in lung cancer patients underwent volumetric modulated arc therapy. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2024;254:108295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhayana R, Alwahbi O, Ladak AM, et al. Leveraging large language models to generate clinical histories for oncologic imaging requisitions. Radiology. 2025;314:e242134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paschali M, Chen Z, Blankemeier L, et al. Foundation models in radiology: what, how, why, and why not. Radiology. 2025;314:e240597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai S, Bontempi D, Hadzic I, et al. Foundation model for cancer imaging biomarkers. Nat Mach Intell. 2024;6:354&#x2013;367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta JN, Falcone GJ, Rajpurkar P, et al. Multimodal biomedical AI. Nat Med. 2022;28:1773&#x2013;1784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Xu Y, Usuyama N, et al. Biomedclip: a multimodal biomedical foundation model pretrained from fifteen million scientific image-text pairs. arXiv preprint arXiv:230300915 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CY, Wong C, Zhang S, et al. LLaVA-Med: training a large language-and-vision assistant for biomedicine in one day. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 36 (Neurips 2023) 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Naqa I, Karolak A, Luo Y, et al. Translation of AI into oncology clinical practice. Oncogene. 2023;42:3089&#x2013;3097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bos-Liedke A, Cegla P, Matuszewski K, et al. Differences among [(18)F]FDG PET-derived parameters in lung cancer produced by three software packages. Sci Rep. 2021;11:13942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nai YH, Schaefferkoetter J, Fakhry-Darian D, et al. Validation of low-dose lung cancer PET-CT protocol and PET image improvement using machine learning. Phys Med. 2021;81:285&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwanenburg A, Vallieres M, Abdalah MA, et al. The image biomarker standardization initiative: standardized quantitative radiomics for high-throughput image-based phenotyping. Radiology. 2020;295:328&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor S, Ponzini M, Wilson M, et al. Comparison of imputation and imputation-free methods for statistical analysis of mass spectrometry data with missing data. Brief Bioinform. 2022;23:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanguri RS, Luo J, Aukerman AT, et al. Multimodal integration of radiology, pathology and genomics for prediction of response to PD-(L)1 blockade in patients with non-small cell lung cancer. Nat Cancer. 2022;3:1151&#x2013;1164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen RJ, Lu MY, Wang J, et al. Pathomic fusion: an integrated framework for fusing histopathology and genomic features for cancer diagnosis and prognosis. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2022;41:757&#x2013;770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SH, Han K, Lee JG. Conceptual review of outcome metrics and measures used in clinical evaluation of artificial intelligence in radiology. Radiol Med. 2024;129:1644&#x2013;1655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SH, Han K, Jang HY, et al. Methods for clinical evaluation of artificial intelligence algorithms for medical diagnosis. Radiology. 2023;306:20&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha AA, Hanbury A. Metrics for evaluating 3D medical image segmentation: analysis, selection, and tool. BMC Med Imaging. 2015;15:29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Yoon HJ, Lee E, et al. Validation of deep-learning image reconstruction for low-dose chest computed tomography scan: emphasis on image quality and noise. Korean J Radiol. 2021;22:131&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Moon JT, Purkayastha S, et al. Ethics of large language models in medicine and medical research. Lancet Digit Health. 2023;5:e333&#x2013;e335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavie A, Denkowski MJ. The METEOR metric for automatic evaluation of machine translation. Mach Transl. 2009;23:105&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C-Y. Rouge: a package for automatic evaluation of summaries. Text Summarization Branches Out: Proceedings of the ACL Workshop; 2004:74&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papineni K, Roukos S, Ward T, et al. BLEU: a method for automatic evaluation of machine translation. 40th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Proceedings of the Conference 2002:311&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Kishore V, Wu F, et al. Bertscore: Evaluating text generation with Bert. arXiv preprint arXiv:190409675 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Wang Y, Wang Q, et al. Impact of human and artificial intelligence collaboration on workload reduction in medical image interpretation. NPJ Digit Med. 2024;7:349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallifant J, Afshar M, Ameen S, et al. The TRIPOD-LLM reporting guideline for studies using large language models. Nat Med. 2025;31:60&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim H, Liu X, Rivera SC, et al. Reporting guidelines for clinical trials of artificial intelligence interventions: the SPIRIT-AI and CONSORT-AI guidelines. Trials. 2021;22:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejani AS, Klontzas ME, Gatti AA, et al. Checklist for artificial intelligence in medical imaging (CLAIM): 2024 update. Radiol Artif Intell. 2024;6:e240300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross JL, Choma MA, Onofrey JA. Bias in medical AI: implications for clinical decision-making. PLOS Digit Health. 2024;3:e0000651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes M, Meier R, Pereira S, et al. On the interpretability of artificial intelligence in radiology: challenges and opportunities. Radiol Artif Intell. 2020;2:e190043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Velden BHM, Kuijf HJ, Gilhuijs KGA, et al. Explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) in deep learning-based medical image analysis. Med Image Anal. 2022;79:102470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borys K, Schmitt YA, Nauta M, et al. Explainable AI in medical imaging: an overview for clinical practitioners - beyond saliency-based XAI approaches. Eur J Radiol. 2023;162:110786.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41243882</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-453X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of clinical oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Heart Disease Mortality After Primary Cancer Surgery in the United States.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/COC.0000000000001261</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Patients with cancer may be at higher risk of heart disease from anticancer therapies. However, there is limited data on the risks of heart disease mortality after primary cancer site surgery. This study sought to evaluate the incidence, timing, and risk factors of heart disease mortality after primary cancer site surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) database was used to perform a retrospective population-based study of cancer patients who underwent primary surgical resection from 2000 to 2020. The incidence of heart disease mortality after primary cancer site surgery was described by standardized mortality ratios (SMRs) and the timing of heart disease mortality after surgery was characterized. Risk factors were identified using Fine and Gray competing risk analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among the 1,390,585 cancer patients who underwent primary surgical resection from 2000 to 2020, 178,303 (12.8%) died of heart disease. The SMR of heart disease death after surgery was 6.85 (95% CI: 6.82-6.88, P&lt;0.001). SMRs were highest in cancers of the brain and other nervous system, esophagus, liver and intrahepatic bile duct, pancreas, and lung and bronchus. Approximately 50% of all heart disease deaths occurred within the first 5 years after surgery for all cancers. Risk factors included older age, male sex, Black race, unmarried status, and rurality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The incidence of death from heart disease was significantly elevated in patients who underwent primary cancer site surgery compared with the general US population. These findings can be used to guide surgical planning and follow-up strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Jessica J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3001-5575</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, University Hospitals Seidman Cancer Center, Case Western Reserve School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mani</LastName><ForeName>Kyle A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montefiore Einstein College of Medicine, Bronx, New York, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Daxuan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Sciences, Penn State College of Medicine, Hershey, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rothermel</LastName><ForeName>Luke</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, University Hospitals Seidman Cancer Center, Case Western Reserve School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoag</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University Hospitals Seidman Cancer Center Case Western Reserve School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spratt</LastName><ForeName>Daniel E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, University Hospitals Seidman Cancer Center, Case Western Reserve School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population and Quantitative Health Sciences, Case Western Reserve University School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaorsky</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas G</ForeName><Initials>NG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4932-1986</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, University Hospitals Seidman Cancer Center, Case Western Reserve School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8207754</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-3732</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">comorbidity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41243882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/COC.0000000000001261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000421-990000000-00342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Perera SK, Jacob S, Wilson BE, et al. Global demand for cancer surgery and an estimate of the optimal surgical and anaesthesia workforce between 2018 and 2040: a population-based modelling study. Lancet Oncol. 2021;22:182&#x2013;189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soerjomataram I, Bray F. Planning for tomorrow: global cancer incidence and the role of prevention 2020&#x2013;2070. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2021;18:663&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masters GA, Krilov L, Bailey HH, et al. Clinical cancer advances 2015: annual report on progress against cancer from the American Society of Clinical Oncology. J Clin Oncol Off J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2015;33:786&#x2013;809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaorsky NG, Churilla TM, Egleston BL, et al. Causes of death among cancer patients. Ann Oncol Off J Eur Soc Med Oncol. 2017;28:400&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onitilo AA, Engel JM, Stankowski RV. Cardiovascular toxicity associated with adjuvant trastuzumab therapy: prevalence, patient characteristics, and risk factors. Ther Adv Drug Saf. 2014;5:154&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular Effects of Androgen Deprivation Therapy in Prostate Cancer: Contemporary Meta-Analyses | Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology. doi: 10.1161/ATVBAHA.119.313046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk of Ischemic Heart Disease in Women after Radiotherapy for Breast Cancer | NEJM. doi: 10.1056/nejmoa1209825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkova M, Russell R. Anthracycline cardiotoxicity: prevalence, pathogenesis and treatment. Curr Cardiol Rev. 2011;7:214&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon DW, Shin DW, Cho JH, et al. Increased risk of coronary heart disease and stroke in lung cancer survivors: a Korean nationwide study of 20,458 patients. Lung Cancer. 2019;136:115&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo CY, Tai BC, Chan DKH, et al. Chemotherapy and adverse cardiovascular events in colorectal cancer patients undergoing surgical resection. World J Surg Oncol. 2021;19:21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degett TH, Moustsen-Helms IR, Larsen SB, et al. Cardiovascular events after elective colorectal cancer surgery in patients with stage I-III disease with no previous cardiovascular disease. Acta Oncol Stockh Swed, 2023;62: 728&#x2013;736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagele P, Rao LK, Penta M, et al. Postoperative myocardial injury after major head and neck cancer surgery. Head Neck. 2011;33:1085&#x2013;1091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>2019 ACC/AHA Guideline on the Primary Prevention of Cardiovascular Disease: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines | Circulation. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilchrist SC, Barac A, Ades PA, et al. Cardio-oncology rehabilitation to manage cardiovascular outcomes in cancer patients and survivors: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2019;139:e997&#x2013;e1012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoltzfus KC, Zhang Y, Sturgeon K, et al. Fatal heart disease among cancer patients. Nat Commun. 2020;11:2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agha A, Wang X, Wang M, et al. Long-term risk of death from heart disease among breast cancer patients. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:784409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelburne N, Adhikari B, Brell J, et al. Cancer treatment&#x2013;related cardiotoxicity: current state of knowledge and future research priorities. JNCI J Natl Cancer Inst. 2014;106:dju232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curigliano G, Cardinale D, Dent S, et al. Cardiotoxicity of anticancer treatments: epidemiology, detection, and management. CA Cancer J Clin. 2016;66:309&#x2013;325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sazgary L, Puelacher C, Lurati Buse G, et al. Incidence of major adverse cardiac events following non-cardiac surgery. Eur Heart J Acute Cardiovasc Care. 2021;10:550&#x2013;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botto F, Alonso-Coello P, Chan MTV, et al. Myocardial injury after noncardiac surgery: a large, international, prospective cohort study establishing diagnostic criteria, characteristics, predictors, and 30-day outcomes. Anesthesiology, 2014;120:564&#x2013;578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangano DT, Browner WS, Hollenberg M, et al. Long-term cardiac prognosis following noncardiac surgery. The Study of Perioperative Ischemia Research Group. JAMA. 1992;268:233&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devereaux PJ, Goldman L, Cook DJ, et al. Perioperative cardiac events in patients undergoing noncardiac surgery: a review of the magnitude of the problem, the pathophysiology of the events and methods to estimate and communicate risk. CMAJ. 2005;173:627&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinale D, Colombo A, Lamantia G, et al. Cardio-oncology: a new medical issue. Ecancermedicalscience. 2008;2:126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SEER Cancer Statistics Review, 1975-2018. SEER.https://seer.cancer.gov/csr/1975_2018/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SEER RESEARCH DATA RECORD DESCRIPTION 2018. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Miller KD, Fuchs HE, et al. Cancer Statistics, 2021. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71:7&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawaguchi ES, Shen JI, Li G, et al. A fast and scalable implementation method for competing risks data with the R Package fastcmprsk. R J. 2020;12:163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An Update on Cancer Deaths in the United States. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2022. https://www.cdc.gov/cancer/dcpc/research/update-on-cancer-deaths/index.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturgeon KM, Deng L, Bluethmann SM, et al. A population-based study of cardiovascular disease mortality risk in US cancer patients. Eur Heart J. 2019;40:3889&#x2013;3897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyriakakis N, Giannoudi M, Kumar SS, et al. Evaluation of cardiovascular risk factors in long-term survivors of adult- and childhood-onset brain tumours: a pilot study. Endocr Connect, 2023:12:e220491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin K, Brennan PM, Poon MTC, et al. Raised cardiovascular disease mortality after central nervous system tumor diagnosis: analysis of 171,926 patients from UK and USA. Neuro-Oncol Adv. 2021;3:vdab136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carballo-Folgoso L, &#xc1;lvarez-Velasco R, Lorca R, et al. Evaluation of cardiovascular events in patients with hepatocellular carcinoma treated with sorafenib in the clinical practice. The CARDIO-SOR study. Liver Int. 2021;41:2200&#x2013;2211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh M, Anvekar P, Baraskar B, et al. Prospective of pancreatic cancer diagnosis using cardiac sensing. J Imaging. 2023;9:149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunnery S, Bottinor W, Das S. Cardiac masses in a patient with pancreatic adenocarcinoma and a history of breast carcinoma. JAMA Oncol. 2020;6:917&#x2013;918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Y, Lin M, Huang J, et al. Cardiovascular disease related death among patients with esophagus cancer: a population-based competing risk analysis. Front Oncol, 2022;12: 976711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eads JR. Cardiovascular concerns in the management of esophageal cancer patients. JACC CardioOncol. 2021;3:722&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mani K, Deng D, Lin C, et al. Causes of death among people living with metastatic cancer. Nat Commun. 2024;15:1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward KK, Shah NR, Saenz CC, et al. Cardiovascular disease is the leading cause of death among endometrial cancer patients. Gynecol Oncol. 2012;126:176&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh ETH, Tong AT, Lenihan DJ, et al. Cardiovascular complications of cancer therapy: diagnosis, pathogenesis, and management. Circulation. 2004;109:3122&#x2013;3131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen SD, Knuuti J, Saraste A, et al. 2014 ESC/ESA Guidelines on non-cardiac surgery: cardiovascular assessment and management: The Joint Task Force on non-cardiac surgery: cardiovascular assessment and management of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European Society of Anaesthesiology (ESA). Eur Heart J. 2014;35:2383&#x2013;2431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakatta EG. Age-associated cardiovascular changes in health: impact on cardiovascular disease in older persons. Heart Fail Rev. 2002;7:29&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jousilahti P, Vartiainen E, Tuomilehto J, et al. Sex, age, cardiovascular risk factors, and coronary heart disease. Circulation. 1999;99:1165&#x2013;1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carnethon MR, Pu J, Howard G, et al. Cardiovascular Health in African Americans: a Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2017;136:e393&#x2013;e423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross SH, Mehra MR, Bhatt DL, et al. Rural-urban differences in cardiovascular mortality in the US, 1999-2017. JAMA. 2020;323:1852&#x2013;1854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrington RA, Califf RM, Balamurugan A, et al. Call to action: rural health: a presidential advisory from the American Heart Association and American Stroke Association. Circulation. 2020;141:e615&#x2013;e644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz WM, Hayek SS, Samman Tahhan A, et al. Marital status and outcomes in patients with cardiovascular disease. J Am Heart Assoc, 2017;6:e005890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamorano JL, Lancellotti P, Rodriguez Mu&#xf1;oz D, et al. 2016 ESC Position Paper on cancer treatments and cardiovascular toxicity developed under the auspices of the ESC Committee for Practice Guidelines: the Task Force for cancer treatments and cardiovascular toxicity of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J. 2016;37:2768&#x2013;2801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caine GJ, Stonelake PS, Lip GYH, et al. The hypercoagulable state of malignancy: pathogenesis and current debate. Neoplasia NYN. 2002;4:465&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Ayanian JZ, Zaslavsky AM. Patient characteristics and hospital quality for colorectal cancer surgery. Int J Qual Health Care J Int Soc Qual Health Care. 2007;19:11&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen-Heijnen MLG, Houterman S, Lemmens VEPP, et al. Prognostic impact of increasing age and co-morbidity in cancer patients: a population-based approach. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2005;55:231&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HS, Lloyd S, Decker RH, et al. Overview of the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database: evolution, data variables, and quality assurance. Curr Probl Cancer. 2012;36:183&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HS, Lloyd S, Decker RH, et al. Limitations and biases of the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database. Curr Probl Cancer. 2012;36:216&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaorsky NG, Wang X, Lehrer EJ, et al. Retrospective comparative effectiveness research: Will changing the analytical methods change the results? Int J Cancer. 2022;150:1933&#x2013;1940.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41243491</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2194-802X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diagnosis (Berlin, Germany)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diagnosis (Berl)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Performance of pulmonary physical exam skills by internal medicine interns.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/dx-2025-0118</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the pulmonary physical examination (PE) skills of internal medicine residents using real patients to inform pulmonary PE educational initiatives.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">First year medicine residents (interns) from two large academic medical centers in Maryland examined the&#xa0;same patient with interstitial lung disease (ILD) as part of the Assessment of Physical Examination and Communication Skills (APECS). Interns were evaluated on five clinical domains: PE technique, identifying physical signs, generating a differential diagnosis, clinical judgment, and maintaining patient welfare. Spearman's correlation test described associations between clinical domains. Preceptor comments were examined to identify errors in PE technique and identifying physical&#xa0;signs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">One-hundred and fifty-five interns examined the same patient with ILD across 33 APECS sessions. 111 interns (71.6&#x202f;%) correctly identified the presence of crackles; 96 interns (61.9&#x202f;%) included ILD on their differential diagnosis. There was a significant and positive correlation between PE&#xa0;technique and identification of PE findings (r=0.48, p&lt;0.0001). PE technique (r=0.19, p=0.016) and identifying signs (r=0.42, p&lt;0.0001) were both significantly associated with generating an appropriate differential diagnosis, which in turn was significantly associated with appropriate clinical management (r=0.46, p&lt;0.0001). Common errors were not auscultating the entire lung (55 interns, 35.5&#x202f;%), auscultating through the gown (20 interns, 12.9&#x202f;%), not percussing the chest (15 interns, 9.7&#x202f;%), and using incorrect technique for percussion (37 interns, 23.9&#x202f;%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Medicine interns had variable skills in performing the pulmonary PE. Improving PE skills would lead to increased identification of relevant pulmonary findings, inform clinical decision making, and improve overall patient&#xa0;care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Walter de Gruyter GmbH, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chou</LastName><ForeName>Shawn Y</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Nanjing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bertram</LastName><ForeName>Amanda K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Internal Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stein</LastName><ForeName>Ariella A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Internal Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niessen</LastName><ForeName>Timothy M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hospital Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murphy</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hospital Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics/Division of Hospital Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garibaldi</LastName><ForeName>Brian T</ForeName><Initials>BT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8632-5567</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Bedside Medicine, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Diagnosis (Berl)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101654734</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2194-802X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical skills assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">direct observation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical exam</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary exam</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41243491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/dx-2025-0118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">dx-2025-0118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Block, L, Habicht, R, Wu, A, Desai, S, Wang, K, Silva, K, et al.. In the wake of the 2003 and 2011 duty hours regulations, how do internal medicine interns spend their time? J&#xa0;Gen Int Med 2013;28:1042&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11606-013-2376-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-013-2376-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, MA, Bertram, AK, Tung, M, Desai, SV, Garibaldi, BT. Use of a real-time locating system to assess internal medicine resident location and movement in the hospital. JAMA Netw Open 2022;5:e2215885. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.15885 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.15885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai, SV, Asch, DA, Bellini, LM, Chaiyachati, KH, Liu, M, Sternberg, AL, et al.. Education outcomes in a duty-hour flexibility trial in internal medicine. N&#xa0;Engl J Med 2018;378:1494&#x2013;508. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1800965 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejmoa1800965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elder, A, Chi, J, Ozdalga, E, Kugler, J, Verghese, A. The road back to the bedside. JAMA: J Am Med Assoc 2013;310:799&#x2013;800. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2013.227195 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.227195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vukanovic-Criley, JM, Hovanesyan, A, Criley, SR, Ryan, TJ, Plotnick, G, Mankowitz, K, et al.. Confidential testing of cardiac examination competency in cardiology and noncardiology faculty and trainees: a multicenter study. Clin Cardiol 2010;33:738&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1002/clc.20851 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/clc.20851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verghese, A, Charlton, B, Kassirer, JP, Ramsey, M, Ioannidis, JPA. Inadequacies of physical examination as a cause of medical errors and adverse events: a collection of vignettes. Am J Med 2015;128:1322&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2015.06.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2015.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, H, Meyer, AND, Thomas, EJ. The frequency of diagnostic errors in outpatient care: estimations from three large observational studies involving US adult populations. BMJ Qual Saf 2014;23:727. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjqs-2013-002627 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2013-002627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costanzo, C, Verghese, A. The physical examination as ritual: social sciences and embodiment in the context of the physical examination. Med Clin North Am 2018;102:425&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcna.2017.12.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcna.2017.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein, RM. Assessment in medical education. N&#xa0;Engl J Med 2007;356:387&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmra054784 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejmra054784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmboe, ES, Hawkins, RE, Huot, SJ. Effects of training in direct observation of medical residents&#x2019; clinical competence: a randomized trial. Ann Intern Med 2004;140:874&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-140-11-200406010-00008 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-140-11-200406010-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elder, A. Clinical skills assessment in the twenty-first century. Med Clin 2018;102:545&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcna.2017.12.014 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcna.2017.12.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott, K, Roemer, M. Most frequent principal diagnoses for inpatient stays in U.S. hospitals, 2018. 2021 [277]. [Available from: https://hcup-us.ahrq.gov/reports/statbriefs/sb277-Top-Reasons-Hospital-Stays-2018.jsp .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss, AJHJ. Most frequent reasons for emergency department visits, 2018. 2021 [287]. [Available from: https://hcup-us.ahrq.gov/reports/statbriefs/sb286-ED-Frequent-Conditions-2018.jsp .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee, S. Palpation and percussion of the chest. In: Mcgee, S, editor. Evidence-based physical diagnosis , 5 ed. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier; 2022:245&#x2013;54 pp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee, S. Inspection of the chest. In: McGee, S, editor. Evidence-based physical diagnosis , 5 ed. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier; 2022:235&#x2013;43 pp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee, S. Auscultation of the lungs. In: McGee, S, editor. Evidence-based physical diagnosis , 5 ed. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier; 2022:255&#x2013;68 pp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elder, AT, McManus, IC, Patrick, A, Nair, K, Vaughan, L, Dacre, J. The value of the physical examination in clinical practice: an international survey. Clin Med 2017;17:490&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmedicine.17-6-490 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7861/clinmedicine.17-6-490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangione, S, Nieman, LZ. Pulmonary auscultatory skills during training in internal medicine and family practice. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 1999;159:1119&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1164/ajrccm.159.4.9806083 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/ajrccm.159.4.9806083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, BW, Niessen, T, Apfel, A, Luckin, J, Lee, YZJ, Desai, SV, et al.. Relationship of physical examination technique to associated clinical skills: results from a direct observation assessment. Am J Med 2022;135:775&#x2013;82.e10. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2021.11.021 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2021.11.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee, S. Evidence-based physical diagnosis , 5 ed. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garibaldi, BT, Russell, SW. Strategies to improve bedside clinical skills teaching. Chest 2021;160:9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chest.2021.06.055 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2021.06.055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knaus, WDE, Wagner, D, Zimmerman, J. APACHE II: a severity of disease classification system. Crit Care Med 1985;13:12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, CL, Holroyd-Leduc, J, Straus, SE. Does this patient have a pleural effusion? JAMA 2009;301:309&#x2013;17. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2008.937 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2008.937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaki, HA, Albaroudi, B, Shaban, EE, Shaban, A, Elgassim, M, Almarri, ND, et al.. Advancement in pleura effusion diagnosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of point-of-care ultrasound versus radiographic thoracic imaging. Ultrasound J 2024;16:3. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13089-023-00356-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13089-023-00356-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohadana, A, Izbicki, G, Kraman, SS. Fundamentals of lung auscultation. N&#xa0;Engl J Med 2014;370:744&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmra1302901 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejmra1302901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran-Mendoza, O, Ritchie, T, Aldhaheri, S. Fine crackles on chest auscultation in the early diagnosis of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: a prospective cohort study. BMJ Open Respir Res 2021;8. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjresp-2020-000815 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjresp-2020-000815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang, K, Chew, C, De La Rosa, M, Bertram, AK, Sharma, A, Niessen, TM, et al.. Performance of cardiovascular physical exam skills by internal medicine residents. Am J Med 2024;137:1001&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2024.04.039 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2024.04.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gips, JR, Stein, AA, Luckin, J, Garibaldi, BT. Internal medicine intern performance on the gastrointestinal physical exam. Diagnosis 2023;10:412&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1515/dx-2023-0051 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/dx-2023-0051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyman, P. The disappearance of the primary care physical examination&#x2014;losing touch. JAMA Intern Med 2020;180:1417&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.3546 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.3546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamamoto Filho, PT, Cecilio-Fernandes, D, Norcia, LF, Sandars, J, Anderson, MB, Bicudo, AM. Reduction in final year medical students&#x2019; knowledge during the COVID-19 pandemic: insights from an interinstitutional progress test. Front Educ 2022;7. https://doi.org/10.3389/feduc.2022.1033732 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feduc.2022.1033732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saad, S, Richmond, C, King, D, Jones, C, Malau-Aduli, B. The impact of pandemic disruptions on clinical skills learning for pre-clinical medical students: implications for future educational designs. BMC Med Educ 2023;23:364. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12909-023-04351-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-023-04351-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, L, Binks, S, Heal, C. The effect of COVID-19 on medical student clinical skill practice and self-perceived proficiency. MedEdPublish (2016) 2023;13:10. https://doi.org/10.12688/mep.19478.2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/mep.19478.2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paley, L, Zornitzki, T, Cohen, J, Friedman, J, Kozak, N, Schattner, A. Utility of clinical examination in the diagnosis of emergency department patients admitted to the department of medicine of an academic hospital. JAMA Intern Med 2011;171:1393&#x2013;400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benbassat, J, Baumal, R. Narrative review: should teaching of the respiratory physical examination be restricted only to signs with&#xa0;proven reliability and validity? J&#xa0;Gen Intern Med 2010;25:865&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11606-010-1327-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-010-1327-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garibaldi, BT, Olson, APJ. The hypothesis-driven physical examination. Med Clin 2018;102:433&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcna.2017.12.005 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcna.2017.12.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, SH, Kim, YS, Yeo, MK, Mahmood, M, Zavanelli, N, Chung, C, et al.. Fully portable continuous real-time auscultation with a soft wearable stethoscope designed for automated disease diagnosis. Sci Adv 2022;8:eabo5867. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abo5867 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abo5867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb, ER, Aliotta, JM, Tammaro, D. Comparison of analogue and electronic stethoscopes for pulmonary auscultation by internal medicine residents. Postgrad Med J 2018;94:700&#x2013;3. https://doi.org/10.1136/postgradmedj-2018-136052 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/postgradmedj-2018-136052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beshara, M, Bittner, EA, Goffi, A, Berra, L, Chang, MG. Nuts and bolts of lung ultrasound: utility, scanning techniques, protocols, and findings in common pathologies. Crit Care 2024;28:328. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-024-05102-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-024-05102-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew, C, Lang, K, Rosa, M, Bertram, AK, Stein, AA, Sharma, A, et al.. Performance of the cardiovascular point of care ultrasound (POCUS) exam by internal medicine residents. Pocus J 2025;10:38&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.24908/pocusj.v10i01.17791 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24908/pocusj.v10i01.17791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garibaldi, BT, Russell, SW. Teaching the physical examination at the bedside. In: APK, CR, editor. Teaching and coaching in the hospital . Philadelphia, PA: American College of Physicians;&#xa0;2025.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41176784</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5741</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Anti-cancer drugs</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anticancer Drugs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Initial stage analysis of tislelizumab in combination with chemotherapy for patients with advanced HIV-positive non-small-cell lung cancer: a comparative clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CAD.0000000000001784</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) are a standard treatment for advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC), but limited data exist regarding their use in patients with HIV-positive. This study evaluated the efficacy and safety of ICI-based therapy in this population. In this single-center, comparative study, 18 patients with treatment-naive advanced NSCLC with HIV (experimental group) and 40 HIV-negative controls (control group) received 4-6 cycles of tislelizumab plus platinum-based chemotherapy, followed by tislelizumab maintenance until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. A higher incidence of tuberculosis was observed in the experimental group compared with the control group (33.3 vs. 20.0%). The objective response rate was 77.8% [95% confidence interval (CI): 56.5-99.1] in the experimental group and 77.5% (95% CI: 64-91) in the control group ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.981). The 6-month progression-free survival rate was 83.3% (95% CI: 64.3-99.9) for the experimental group and 82.5% (95% CI: 70.2-94.8) for the control group ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.227). The 6-month overall survival rate was 88.9% (95% CI: 72.8-99.9) in the experimental group and 97.5% (95% CI: 92.4-99.9) in the control group ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.192). The incidences of grade 3 or higher adverse events were 38.9 and 32.5% in the experimental and control groups, respectively. One patient in the experimental group died due to a serious opportunistic infection. Immunotherapy combined with chemotherapy showed comparable efficacy and safety in patients with advanced NSCLC irrespective of HIV status. Patients with HIV-positive had a higher tendency for opportunistic infections, including tuberculosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quan</LastName><ForeName>Yaping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Guiyang Public Health Clinical Center, Guiyang, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Zhengjie</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>004[2023]</GrantID><Agency>Guizhou Provincial Anti-Cancer Association Science and Technology Program Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Anticancer Drugs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9100823</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-4973</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIV-positive non-small-cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tislelizumab</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41176784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CAD.0000000000001784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001813-990000000-00440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Calkins KL, Chander G, Joshu CE, Visvanathan K, Fojo AT, Lesko CR, et al. Immune status and associated mortality after cancer treatment among individuals with HIV in the antiretroviral therapy era. JAMA Oncol 2020; 6:227&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka T, Oshima K, Kawano K, Tashiro M, Kakiuchi S, Tanaka A, et al. Nationwide longitudinal annual survey of HIV/AIDS referral hospitals in Japan From 1999 to 2021: trend in non-AIDS-defining cancers among individuals infected with HIV-1. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr 2024; 96:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinidis I, Crothers K, Kunisaki KM, Drummond MB, Benfield T, Zar HJ, et al. HIV-associated lung disease. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2023; 9:39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhikoo R, Allwood BW, Irusen EM, Koegelenberg CFN. Lung cancer presents at a younger age and is less likely to be curable in people living with HIV. Respiration 2024; 103:47&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hysell K, Yusuf R, Barakat L, Virata M, Gan G, Deng Y, et al. Decreased overall survival in HIV-associated non-small-cell lung cancer. Clin Lung Cancer 2021; 22:e498&#x2013;e505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reck M, Remon J, Hellmann MD. First-line immunotherapy for non-small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol 2022; 40:586&#x2013;597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riely GJ, Wood DE, Ettinger DS, Aisner DL, Akerley W, Bauman JR, et al. Non-small cell lung cancer, version 4.2024, NCCN clinical practice guidelines in oncology. J Natl Compr Canc Netw 2024; 22:249&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Qiu T, Ren S. Updates to the 2024 CSCO advanced non-small cell lung cancer guidelines. Cancer Biol Med 2025; 22:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertin L, Canellas A, Abbar B, Veyri M, Spano J-P, Cadranel J, Lavol&#xe9; A. Brief report of anti-programmed cell death protein-1 in human immunodeficiency virus setting: relevant and breaking results in first-line NSCLC therapy. JTO Clin Res Rep 2021; 2:100247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assoumou L, Balde R, Katlama C, Abbar B, Delobel P, Allegre T, et al. Safety and tolerability of immune checkpoint inhibitors in people with HIV infection and cancer: insights from the national prospective real-world OncoVIHAC ANRS CO24 cohort study. J ImmunoTher Cancer 2024; 12:e009728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender Ignacio R, Ddungu H, Uldrick TS. Untangling the effects of chemotherapy and HIV on CD4 counts-implications for immunotherapy in HIV and cancer. JAMA Oncol 2020; 6:235&#x2013;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spano JP, Veyri M, Gobert A, Guihot A, Perr&#xe9; P, Kerjouan M, et al. Immunotherapy for cancer in people living with HIV: safety with an efficacy signal from the series in real life experience. AIDS 2019; 33:F13&#x2013;F19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostios-garcia L, Faig J, Leonardi GC, Adeni AE, Subegdjo SJ, Lydon CA, et al. Safety and efficacy of PD-1 inhibitors among HIV-positive patients with non-small cell lung cancer. J Thorac Oncol 2018; 13:1037&#x2013;1042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah NJ, Al-shbool G, Blackburn M, Cook M, Belouali A, Liu SV, et al. Safety and efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) in cancer patients with HIV, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C viral infection. J ImmunoTher Cancer 2019; 7:353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavole A, Mazieres J, Schneider S, Brosseau S, Kiakouama L, Greillier L, et al.; On behalf the French Cooperative Thoracic Intergroup (IFCT). Assessment of nivolumab in HIV-infected patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer after prior chemotherapy. The IFCT-1602 CHIVA2 phase 2 clinical trial. Lung Cancer 2021; 158:146&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trickey A, Sabin CA, Burkholder G, Crane H, d'Arminio Monforte A, Egger M, et al. Life expectancy after 2015 of adults with HIV on long-term antiretroviral therapy in Europe and North America: a collaborative analysis of cohort studies. Lancet HIV 2023; 10:e295&#x2013;e307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smiley CL, Rebeiro PF, Cesar C, Belaunzaran-Zamudio PF, Crabtree-Ramirez B, Padgett D, et al.; Caribbean, Central and South America Network for HIV Epidemiology (CCASAnet). Estimated life expectancy gains with antiretroviral therapy among adults with HIV in Latin America and the Caribbean: a multisite retrospective cohort study. Lancet HIV 2021; 8:e266&#x2013;e273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Cao M, Mor&#xe1;n T, Dalmau J, Garcia-Corbacho J, Bracht JWP, Bernabe R, et al. Assessment of the feasibility and safety of durvalumab for treatment of solid tumors in patients with HIV-1 infection: the phase 2 DURVAST study. JAMA Oncol 2020; 6:1063&#x2013;1067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook MR, Kim C. Safety and efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy in patients with HIV infection and advanced-stage cancer: a systematic review. JAMA Oncol 2019; 5:1049&#x2013;1054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odeny TA, Lurain K, Strauss J, Fling SP, Sharon E, Wright A, et al. Effect of CD4+ T cell count on treatment-emergent adverse events among patients with and without HIV receiving immunotherapy for advanced cancer. J ImmunoTher Cancer 2022; 10:e005128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron M, Soulie C, Lavole A, Assoumou L, Abbar B, Fouquet B, et al.; The Anrs Co OncoVIHAC Study Group. Impact of anti PD-1 immunotherapy on HIV reservoir and anti-viral immune responses in people living with HIV and cancer. Cells 2022; 11:1015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Lu S, Yu X, Hu Y, Zhao J, Sun M, et al. Tislelizumab plus chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone as first-line treatment for advanced squamous non-small-cell lung cancer: final analysis of the randomized, phase III RATIONALE-307 trial. ESMO Open 2024; 9:103727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Wang J, Yu Y, Yu X, Hu Y, Ai X, et al. Tislelizumab plus chemotherapy as first-line treatment for locally advanced or metastatic nonsquamous NSCLC (RATIONALE 304): a randomized phase 3 trial. J Thorac Oncol 2021; 16:1512&#x2013;1522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang E, Sabichi AL, Kramer JR, Hartman C, Royse KE, White DL, et al. Nivolumab treatment for cancers in the HIV-infected population. J Immunother 2018; 41:379&#x2013;383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uldrick TS, Goncalves PH, Abdul-hay M, Claeys AJ, Emu B, Ernstoff MS, et al.; Cancer Immunotherapy Trials Network (CITN)-12 Study Team. Assessment of the safety of pembrolizumab in patients with HIV and advanced cancer-a phase 1 study. JAMA Oncol 2019; 5:1332&#x2013;1339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang W, Wang M, Jiang L, Su Z, Lin S. The peripheral CD4(+) T cells predict efficacy in non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients with the anti-PD-1 treatment. Transl Cancer Res 2024; 13:4052&#x2013;4061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng QM, Li YY, Wang YP, Li G-X, Sun Z-G, Zhang M. Prognostic significance of CD4+ tumour infiltrating lymphocytes in patients with non-small cell lung cancer receiving PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitors therapy. J Coll Physicians Surg Pak 2025; 35:341&#x2013;350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao D, Liu L, Liu J, Liu J. Predictive response and outcome of peripheral CD4(+) T cell subpopulations to combined immunotherapy and chemotherapy in advanced gastric cancer patients. Int Immunopharmacol 2024; 129:111663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wondmeneh TG, Mekonnen AT. The incidence rate of tuberculosis and its associated factors among HIV-positive persons in Sub-Saharan Africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis 2023; 23:613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraef C, Roen A, Podlekareva D, Bakowska E, Nemeth J, Knappik M, et al.; the RESPOND Study Group. Incident tuberculosis in people with HIV across Europe from 2012-2022: incidence rates, risk factors, and regional differences in a multicentre cohort study. Eur Respir J 2025; 65:2401904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraef C, Tusch E, Singh S, &#xd8;stergaard L, F&#xe4;tkenheuer G, Castagna A, et al.; EuroSIDA Study Group. All-cause and AIDS-related mortality among people with HIV across Europe from 2001 to 2020: impact of antiretroviral therapy, tuberculosis and regional differences in a multicentre cohort study. Lancet Reg Health Eur 2024; 44:100989.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>