<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41175036</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6971</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in pulmonary medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Peripheral bronchoscopy: back to basics.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCP.0000000000001229</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Peripheral bronchoscopy is increasingly practiced to gain access to peripheral pulmonary lesions (PPLs). Lung cancer screening with low-dose computed tomography (CT) is fuelling the need for superior navigational tools such as robot-assisted bronchoscopy to target screen-detected pulmonary nodules which may be as small as 6&#x200a;mm.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">It is an opportune moment to return to the basics of performing peripheral bronchoscopy through revising airway mapping with CT imaging. Virtual bronchoscopy, electromagnetic navigation bronchoscopy (ENB) and robot-assisted bronchoscopy (RAB) have yet to supplant the accuracy of manual airway mapping achieved simply by CT reading. The technique of airway mapping should be consistently utilised for airway navigation as it is complementary to technologies such as virtual bronchoscopy, ENB or RAB. In this review, we share the technique of performing airway mapping with a case illustration, and our approach to peripheral bronchoscopy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Airway mapping is a foundational skill that must be preserved, practiced and perfected in our bronchoscopic approach to a PPL. In the absence of advanced navigational tools, peripheral bronchoscopy can be performed in combination with readily available tools to obtain a high diagnostic yield.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quah</LastName><ForeName>Pipetius</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Medicine, Intensive Care Medicine, Woodlands Health.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Pyng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, National University Hospital, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pulm Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9503765</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1070-5287</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">airway mapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peripheral bronchoscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radial endobronchial ultrasonography</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41175036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCP.0000000000001229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00063198-990000000-00287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>de Koning HJ, van der Aalst CM, de Jong PA, et al. Reduced lung-cancer mortality with volume CT screening in a randomized trial. N Engl J Med 2020; 382:503&#x2013;513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aberle DR, Adams AM, Berg CD, et al. National Lung Screening Trial Research T. Reduced lung-cancer mortality with low-dose computed tomographic screening. N Engl J Med 2011; 365:395&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McWilliams A, Tammemagi MC, Mayo JR, et al. Probability of cancer in pulmonary nodules detected on first screening CT. N Engl J Med 2013; 369:910&#x2013;919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lentz RJ, Frederick-Dyer K, Planz VB, et al. Navigational bronchoscopy or transthoracic needle biopsy for lung nodules. N Engl J Med 2025; 392:2100&#x2013;2112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyarali FF, Hakami-Majd N, Sabbahi W, Chaux G. Robotic-assisted navigation bronchoscopy: a meta-analysis of diagnostic yield and complications. J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol 2024; 31:70&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurimoto N, Morita K. Bronchial branch tracing. Springer Verlag, Singapore; 2020. XII, 161 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuboi E, Ikeda S, Tajima M, et al. Transbronchial biopsy smear for diagnosis of peripheral pulmonary carcinomas. Cancer 1967; 20:687&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imabayashi T, Matsumoto Y, Uchimura K, et al. Computed tomography bronchus sign subclassification during radial endobronchial ultrasound-guided transbronchial biopsy: a retrospective analysis. Diagnostics (Basel) 2023; 13:1064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali MS, Sethi J, Taneja A, et al. Computed tomography bronchus sign and the diagnostic yield of guided bronchoscopy for peripheral pulmonary lesions. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2018; 15:978&#x2013;987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takata S, Miyake K, Kumanogoh A. The superiority of manual over automated methods in identifying bronchial trees on identical CT images. Sci Rep 2022; 12:5416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kho SS, Nyanti LE, Chai CS, et al. Feasibility of manual bronchial branch reading technique in navigating conventional rEBUS bronchoscopy in the evaluation of peripheral pulmonary lesion. Clin Respir J 2021; 15:595&#x2013;603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kho SS, Tan SH, Chan SK, et al. Bronchial branch tracing navigation in ultrathin bronchoscopy-guided radial endobronchial ultrasound for peripheral pulmonary nodule. BMC Pulm Med 2024; 24:466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kho SS, Tan SH, Chai CS, et al. Performance of radial endobronchial ultrasound for peripheral pulmonary lesions without automation technology in tuberculous endemic region: real-world experience in a single institution over 6&#x200a;years. J Thorac Dis 2023; 15:6072&#x2013;6083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan M, Hu Y, Wang L, et al. Diagnostic outcomes of radial endobronchial ultrasound bronchoscopy guided by manual navigation in the evaluation of peripheral pulmonary lesions: an observational study. Clin Respir J 2024; 18:e13768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadoughi A, Synn S, Chan C, et al. Ultrathin bronchoscopy without virtual navigation for diagnosis of peripheral lung lesions. Lung 2024; 202:601&#x2013;613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oki M, Saka H, Ando M, et al. Ultrathin bronchoscopy with multimodal devices for peripheral pulmonary lesions. A randomized trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2015; 192:468&#x2013;476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasselbring F, Herth FJF, Kriegsmann M, et al. Transbronchial cryobiopsy using the Ultrathin 1.1-mm Cryoprobe with Ultrathin bronchoscopy under radial endobronchial ultrasound guidance for diagnosis of peripheral pulmonary lesions. Respiration 2024; 103:268&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Yang Z, Zou H, et al. Ultrathin bronchoscopy versus conventional bronchoscopy in the diagnosis of peripheral pulmonary lesions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Expert Rev Respir Med 2025; 19:461&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurimoto N, Miyazawa T, Okimasa S, et al. Endobronchial ultrasonography using a guide sheath increases the ability to diagnose peripheral pulmonary lesions endoscopically. Chest 2004; 126:959&#x2013;965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oki M, Saka H, Imabayashi T, et al. Guide sheath versus nonguide sheath method for endobronchial ultrasound-guided biopsy of peripheral pulmonary lesions: a multicentre randomised trial. Eur Respir J 2022; 59:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH, Chung HS, Kim J, et al. Development of the Korean Association for Lung Cancer Clinical Practice Guidelines: recommendations on radial probe endobronchial ultrasound for diagnosing lung cancer - an updated meta-analysis. Cancer Res Treat 2024; 56:464&#x2013;483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Song JU. Diagnostic yield of radial probe endobronchial ultrasonography-guided transbronchial biopsy without fluoroscopy in peripheral pulmonary lesions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Thorac Cancer 2023; 14:195&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oki M, Saka H, Kitagawa C, et al. Randomized study of endobronchial ultrasound-guided transbronchial biopsy: thin bronchoscopic method versus guide sheath method. J Thorac Oncol 2012; 7:535&#x2013;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almadani A, Ping MNY, Deenadayalu A, et al. The effect of using different types of forceps in the efficacy of transbronchial lung biopsy. Lung 2019; 197:61&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herth FJ, Eberhardt R, Sterman D, et al. Bronchoscopic transparenchymal nodule access (BTPNA): first in human trial of a novel procedure for sampling solitary pulmonary nodules. Thorax 2015; 70:326&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou L, Huang X, Tu J, Xu Z. Endobronchial ultrasound-guided transbronchial needle aspiration in peripheral pulmonary lesions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Exp Metastasis 2023; 40:45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondoni M, Sotgiu G, Bonifazi M, et al. Transbronchial needle aspiration in peripheral pulmonary lesions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Respir J 2016; 48:196&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito T, Nishida K, Iwano S, et al. Diagnostic value and safety of addition of transbronchial needle aspiration to transbronchial biopsy through endobronchial ultrasonography using a Guide Sheath under virtual bronchoscopic navigation for the diagnosis of peripheral pulmonary lesions. J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol 2024; 31:e0984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D, Chae G, Kim JH, et al. Diagnostic utility of adding needle aspiration (using PeriView FLEX needle) to radial endobronchial ultrasound guide sheath transbronchial lung biopsy: a single center retrospective study. J Thorac Dis 2024; 16:3818&#x2013;3827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olive GN, Leong SC, Marshall HM, et al. Transbronchial needle aspiration via Ultrathin bronchoscope improves diagnostic yield for peripheral lung lesions: randomized sequencing trial. J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol 2025; 32:e0996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kho SS, Tan SH, Nyanti LE, et al. Feasibility of Cryobiopsy specimen retrieval through standard Guide Sheath for peripheral pulmonary lesions without bronchoscope removal. J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol 2024; 31:e0982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung C, Kim Y, Lee JE, et al. Diagnostic value of transbronchial lung cryobiopsy using an Ultrathin Cryoprobe and Guide Sheath for peripheral pulmonary lesions. J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol 2024; 31:13&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odeh T, Pitts L, Reid M, et al. Robotic-assisted bronchoscopy-guided transbronchial cryobiopsy versus transbronchial needle aspiration in peripheral pulmonary lesions. J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol 2025; 32:e1014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumner ET, Chang J, Patel PR, et al. State of the art: peripheral diagnostic bronchoscopy. J Thorac Dis 2024; 16:5409&#x2013;5421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy-Chowdhuri S, Dacic S, Ghofrani M, et al. Collection and handling of thoracic small biopsy and cytology specimens for ancillary studies: guideline from the College of American Pathologists in Collaboration With the American College of Chest Physicians, Association for Molecular Pathology, American Society of Cytopathology, American Thoracic Society, Pulmonary Pathology Society, Papanicolaou Society of Cytopathology, Society of Interventional Radiology, and Society of Thoracic Radiology. Arch Pathol Lab Med 2020; 144:933&#x2013;958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kops SEP, van der Burgt LJW, Vos S, et al. Rapid on-site evaluation of touch imprint cytology in navigation bronchoscopy for small peripheral pulmonary nodules. Cancer Cytopathol 2024; 132:233&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muto Y, Uchimura K, Imabayashi T, et al. Clinical utility of rapid on-site evaluation of Touch Imprint Cytology during cryobiopsy for peripheral pulmonary lesions. Cancers (Basel) 2022; 14:4493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C, Liu W, Wang W, et al. Diagnostic value of endobronchial ultrasound combined with rapid on-site evaluation of transbronchial lung biopsy for peripheral pulmonary lesions. Diagn Cytopathol 2021; 49:706&#x2013;710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan S, Li Y, Pan L, et al. The application of artificial intelligence for Rapid On-Site Evaluation during flexible bronchoscopy. Front Oncol 2024; 14:1360831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manley CJ, Kramer T, Kumar R, et al. Robotic bronchoscopic needle-based confocal laser endomicroscopy to diagnose peripheral lung nodules. Respirology 2023; 28:475&#x2013;483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer T, Wijmans L, de Bruin M, et al. Bronchoscopic needle-based confocal laser endomicroscopy (nCLE) as a real-time detection tool for peripheral lung cancer. Thorax 2022; 77:370&#x2013;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitlinger J, Stasiak F, Streit A, et al. Assessment of needle-based confocal laser endomicroscopy (nCLE) as a tool for real-time diagnosis of nonsmall cell lung cancer. J Thorac Dis 2024; 16:4986&#x2013;4993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuno T, Kurimoto N, Tanino A, et al. Usefulness of endocytoscopy in evaluating transbronchial biopsy specimens. Thorac Cancer 2023; 14:186&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takemura M, Kurimoto N, Hoshikawa M, et al. Probe-based confocal laser endomicroscopy for rapid on-site evaluation of transbronchial biopsy specimens. Thorac Cancer 2019; 10:1441&#x2013;1447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Heumen S, Kramer T, Korevaar DA, et al. Bronchoscopy with and without needle-based confocal laser endomicroscopy for peripheral lung nodule diagnosis: protocol for a multicentre randomised controlled trial (CLEVER trial). BMJ Open 2024; 14:e081148.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41150618</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2327-2228</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>108</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Rhode Island medical journal (2013)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>R I Med J (2013)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Emerging Pathogenicity of Purpureocillium lilacinum: A Rare Case of Cavitary Lung Disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7</StartPage><EndPage>9</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Purpureocillium lilacinum is an emerging opportunistic pathogen that can cause a variety of infections, including pulmonary disease, particularly in immunocompromised individuals. Its rare pulmonary involvement presents significant diagnostic challenges due to nonspecific symptoms and imaging findings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION" NlmCategory="METHODS">We present the case of a 60-year-old male with a history of severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), diabetes mellitus, and smoking, who presented with chronic cough and weight loss. Imaging revealed a cavitary lesion in the left lung apex. Despite initial antibiotic treatment, his symptoms persisted, prompting further investigation. Bronchoscopy and bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) led to the identification of Purpureocillium lilacinum infection. The patient was treated with oral voriconazole 200 mg twice daily for four weeks, with notable clinical and radiographic improvement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Purpureocillium lilacinum should be considered as a potential cause of cavitary lung disease in patients with persistent respiratory symptoms, particularly those with predisposing factors. Early diagnosis and antifungal therapy, such as voriconazole, are crucial for effective treatment and improved outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Surana</LastName><ForeName>Arihant</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Saint Vincent Hospital, Worcester, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhattacharya</LastName><ForeName>Riya</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Saint Vincent Hospital, Worcester, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banga</LastName><ForeName>Akshat</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Mount Auburn Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Cambridge, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tasch</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, Saint Vincent Hospital, Worcester, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>R I Med J (2013)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605827</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000935">Antifungal Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>JFU09I87TR</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D065819">Voriconazole</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000670243">Purpureocillium lilacinum</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000935" MajorTopicYN="N">Antifungal Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065819" MajorTopicYN="N">Voriconazole</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Diseases, Fungal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006999" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypocreales</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029424" MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016867" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunocompromised Host</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001999" MajorTopicYN="N">Bronchoscopy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Purpureocillium lilacinum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cavitary lung disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opportunistic pathogen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">voriconazole</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41150618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>