<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41251393</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-453X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of clinical oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prognostic Value of Multiparameter Biomarkers in Pleural Effusion of Patients With Non-small Cell Lung Cancer for Predicting Survival Outcomes: A Prospective Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/COC.0000000000001269</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Pleural effusion is a frequent and clinically significant complication in patients with non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), frequently causing debilitating respiratory symptoms, most notably dyspnea. The development of MPE is strongly correlated with unfavorable prognosis in NSCLC patients. This study aims to evaluate the prognostic value of multiparameter biomarkers (including CA125, CEA, CYFRA21-1, NSE, and LDH) in patients with NSCLC complicated by pleural effusion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective cohort study, we included 119 patients diagnosed with NSCLC and pleural effusion. We systematically assessed the levels of these biomarkers in pleural effusion and their relationship with overall survival. Univariate and multivariate Cox regression analyses were used to explore the association between these biomarkers and patient prognosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study found that levels of CA125, CYFRA21-1, and LDH in pleural effusion were significantly correlated with overall survival, with higher levels associated with shorter survival times. In addition, as the volume of pleural effusion increased, the levels of these biomarkers also significantly rose. Multivariate Cox regression analysis indicated that age, larger pleural effusion volume, and elevated levels of CA125, CYFRA21-1, and LDH were independent risk factors for overall survival.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings of this study suggest that CA125, CYFRA21-1, and LDH in pleural effusion may be potential biomarkers for assessing prognosis in patients with NSCLC and pleural effusion. While these results offer valuable insights into their potential role in clinical practice, further validation through larger, multicenter studies is needed to confirm their prognostic significance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Bao-Hong</ForeName><Initials>BH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hui-Yan</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhi-Ran</ForeName><Initials>ZR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Management, Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital, Harbin, Heilongjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ming-Yan</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Management, Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital, Harbin, Heilongjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8207754</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-3732</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-small cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pleural effusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognostic value</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41251393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/COC.0000000000001269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000421-990000000-00345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Miller KD, Wagle NS, et al. Cancer statistics, 2023. CA Cancer J Clin. 2023;73:17&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global Cancer Statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN Estimates of Incidence and Mortality Worldwide for 36 Cancers in 185 Countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71:209&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Zheng R, Baade PD, et al. Cancer statistics in China, 2015. CA Cancer J Clin. 2016;66:115&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gayen S. Malignant pleural effusion: presentation, diagnosis, and management. Am J Med. 2022;135:1188&#x2013;1192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feller-Kopman DJ, Reddy CB, DeCamp MM, et al. Management of malignant pleural effusions. An Official ATS/STS/STR Clinical Practice Guideline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;198:839&#x2013;849.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ascoli V, Minelli G, Cozzi I, et al. Pathology reporting of malignant pleural mesothelioma first diagnosis: a population-based approach. Pathol Res Pract. 2016;212:886&#x2013;892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Z, Li H, Qiang F, et al. Regulation of inflammation by Chaihu-Shugan-San: targeting the IL-17/NF-&#x3ba;B pathway to combat breast cancer-related depression. Phytomedicine. 2025;143:156836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bing Y, Zou X, Yang X, et al. Mechanism elucidation and biochemometric-based screening of substances in Schisandra chinensis leaves for alcoholic liver injury. Phytomedicine. 2025;142:156757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherpereel A, Opitz I, Berghmans T, et al. ERS/ESTS/EACTS/ESTRO guidelines for the management of malignant pleural mesothelioma. Eur Respir J. 2020;55:1900953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh N, Baby D, Rajguru JP, et al. Inflammation and cancer. Ann Afr Med. 2019;18:121&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brundage MD, Davies D, Mackillop WJ. Prognostic factors in non-small cell lung cancer: a decade of progress. Chest. 2002;122:1037&#x2013;1057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DC, Guinigundo AS. The role of biomarkers in guiding clinical decision-making in oncology. J Adv Pract Oncol. 2023;14:15&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulas A, Turkoz FP, Silay K, et al. A laboratory prognostic index model for patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer. PLoS One. 2014;9:e114471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedr&#xe9;s S, Nu&#xf1;ez I, Longo M, et al. Serum tumor markers CEA, CYFRA21-1, and CA-125 are associated with worse prognosis in advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Clin Lung Cancer. 2011;12:172&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pujol JL, Molinier O, Ebert W, et al. CYFRA 21-1 is a prognostic determinant in non-small-cell lung cancer: results of a meta-analysis in 2063 patients. Br J Cancer. 2004;90:2097&#x2013;2105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Fu F, Zhao Y, et al. The prognostic value of preoperative serum tumor markers in non-small cell lung cancer varies with radiological features and histological types. Front Oncol. 2021;11:645159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng P, Yang Y, Du J, et al. Prognostic biomarkers of malignant patients with pleural effusion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cancer Cell Int. 2022;22:99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao P, Sheng S, Sun X, et al. Lactate dehydrogenase A in cancer: a promising target for diagnosis and therapy. IUBMB Life. 2013;65:904&#x2013;910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crosbie PA, Shah R, Summers Y, et al. Prognostic and predictive biomarkers in early stage NSCLC: CTCs and serum/plasma markers. Transl Lung Cancer Res. 2013;2:382&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall SA, Huang Y, Keiter A, et al. Integration of a geriatric assessment with intervention in the care of older adults with hematologic malignancies. Front Oncol. 2021;11:775050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardessus Otero A, Rafecas-Codern A, Porcel JM, et al. Malignant pleural effusion: a multidisciplinary approach. Open Respiratory Archives. 2024;6:100349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan AC. Targeting the PI3K/Akt/mTOR pathway in non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Thorac Cancer. 2020;11:511&#x2013;518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo Q, Xu C, Shao Y, et al. Free CA125 promotes ovarian cancer cell migration and tumor metastasis by binding Mesothelin to reduce DKK1 expression and activate the SGK3/FOXO3 pathway. Int J Biol Sci. 2021;17:574&#x2013;588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda Y, Enomoto T, Kimura T, et al. Serum biomarkers for early detection of gynecologic cancers. Cancers (Basel). 2010;2:1312&#x2013;1327.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>