<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41176784</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5741</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Anti-cancer drugs</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anticancer Drugs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Initial stage analysis of tislelizumab in combination with chemotherapy for patients with advanced HIV-positive non-small-cell lung cancer: a comparative clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CAD.0000000000001784</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) are a standard treatment for advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC), but limited data exist regarding their use in patients with HIV-positive. This study evaluated the efficacy and safety of ICI-based therapy in this population. In this single-center, comparative study, 18 patients with treatment-naive advanced NSCLC with HIV (experimental group) and 40 HIV-negative controls (control group) received 4-6 cycles of tislelizumab plus platinum-based chemotherapy, followed by tislelizumab maintenance until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. A higher incidence of tuberculosis was observed in the experimental group compared with the control group (33.3 vs. 20.0%). The objective response rate was 77.8% [95% confidence interval (CI): 56.5-99.1] in the experimental group and 77.5% (95% CI: 64-91) in the control group ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.981). The 6-month progression-free survival rate was 83.3% (95% CI: 64.3-99.9) for the experimental group and 82.5% (95% CI: 70.2-94.8) for the control group ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.227). The 6-month overall survival rate was 88.9% (95% CI: 72.8-99.9) in the experimental group and 97.5% (95% CI: 92.4-99.9) in the control group ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.192). The incidences of grade 3 or higher adverse events were 38.9 and 32.5% in the experimental and control groups, respectively. One patient in the experimental group died due to a serious opportunistic infection. Immunotherapy combined with chemotherapy showed comparable efficacy and safety in patients with advanced NSCLC irrespective of HIV status. Patients with HIV-positive had a higher tendency for opportunistic infections, including tuberculosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quan</LastName><ForeName>Yaping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Guiyang Public Health Clinical Center, Guiyang, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Zhengjie</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>004[2023]</GrantID><Agency>Guizhou Provincial Anti-Cancer Association Science and Technology Program Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Anticancer Drugs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9100823</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0959-4973</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIV-positive non-small-cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tislelizumab</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41176784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CAD.0000000000001784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001813-990000000-00440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Calkins KL, Chander G, Joshu CE, Visvanathan K, Fojo AT, Lesko CR, et al. Immune status and associated mortality after cancer treatment among individuals with HIV in the antiretroviral therapy era. JAMA Oncol 2020; 6:227&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka T, Oshima K, Kawano K, Tashiro M, Kakiuchi S, Tanaka A, et al. Nationwide longitudinal annual survey of HIV/AIDS referral hospitals in Japan From 1999 to 2021: trend in non-AIDS-defining cancers among individuals infected with HIV-1. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr 2024; 96:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinidis I, Crothers K, Kunisaki KM, Drummond MB, Benfield T, Zar HJ, et al. HIV-associated lung disease. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2023; 9:39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhikoo R, Allwood BW, Irusen EM, Koegelenberg CFN. Lung cancer presents at a younger age and is less likely to be curable in people living with HIV. Respiration 2024; 103:47&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hysell K, Yusuf R, Barakat L, Virata M, Gan G, Deng Y, et al. Decreased overall survival in HIV-associated non-small-cell lung cancer. Clin Lung Cancer 2021; 22:e498&#x2013;e505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reck M, Remon J, Hellmann MD. First-line immunotherapy for non-small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol 2022; 40:586&#x2013;597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riely GJ, Wood DE, Ettinger DS, Aisner DL, Akerley W, Bauman JR, et al. Non-small cell lung cancer, version 4.2024, NCCN clinical practice guidelines in oncology. J Natl Compr Canc Netw 2024; 22:249&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Qiu T, Ren S. Updates to the 2024 CSCO advanced non-small cell lung cancer guidelines. Cancer Biol Med 2025; 22:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertin L, Canellas A, Abbar B, Veyri M, Spano J-P, Cadranel J, Lavol&#xe9; A. Brief report of anti-programmed cell death protein-1 in human immunodeficiency virus setting: relevant and breaking results in first-line NSCLC therapy. JTO Clin Res Rep 2021; 2:100247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assoumou L, Balde R, Katlama C, Abbar B, Delobel P, Allegre T, et al. Safety and tolerability of immune checkpoint inhibitors in people with HIV infection and cancer: insights from the national prospective real-world OncoVIHAC ANRS CO24 cohort study. J ImmunoTher Cancer 2024; 12:e009728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender Ignacio R, Ddungu H, Uldrick TS. Untangling the effects of chemotherapy and HIV on CD4 counts-implications for immunotherapy in HIV and cancer. JAMA Oncol 2020; 6:235&#x2013;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spano JP, Veyri M, Gobert A, Guihot A, Perr&#xe9; P, Kerjouan M, et al. Immunotherapy for cancer in people living with HIV: safety with an efficacy signal from the series in real life experience. AIDS 2019; 33:F13&#x2013;F19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostios-garcia L, Faig J, Leonardi GC, Adeni AE, Subegdjo SJ, Lydon CA, et al. Safety and efficacy of PD-1 inhibitors among HIV-positive patients with non-small cell lung cancer. J Thorac Oncol 2018; 13:1037&#x2013;1042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah NJ, Al-shbool G, Blackburn M, Cook M, Belouali A, Liu SV, et al. Safety and efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) in cancer patients with HIV, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C viral infection. J ImmunoTher Cancer 2019; 7:353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavole A, Mazieres J, Schneider S, Brosseau S, Kiakouama L, Greillier L, et al.; On behalf the French Cooperative Thoracic Intergroup (IFCT). Assessment of nivolumab in HIV-infected patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer after prior chemotherapy. The IFCT-1602 CHIVA2 phase 2 clinical trial. Lung Cancer 2021; 158:146&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trickey A, Sabin CA, Burkholder G, Crane H, d'Arminio Monforte A, Egger M, et al. Life expectancy after 2015 of adults with HIV on long-term antiretroviral therapy in Europe and North America: a collaborative analysis of cohort studies. Lancet HIV 2023; 10:e295&#x2013;e307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smiley CL, Rebeiro PF, Cesar C, Belaunzaran-Zamudio PF, Crabtree-Ramirez B, Padgett D, et al.; Caribbean, Central and South America Network for HIV Epidemiology (CCASAnet). Estimated life expectancy gains with antiretroviral therapy among adults with HIV in Latin America and the Caribbean: a multisite retrospective cohort study. Lancet HIV 2021; 8:e266&#x2013;e273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Cao M, Mor&#xe1;n T, Dalmau J, Garcia-Corbacho J, Bracht JWP, Bernabe R, et al. Assessment of the feasibility and safety of durvalumab for treatment of solid tumors in patients with HIV-1 infection: the phase 2 DURVAST study. JAMA Oncol 2020; 6:1063&#x2013;1067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook MR, Kim C. Safety and efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy in patients with HIV infection and advanced-stage cancer: a systematic review. JAMA Oncol 2019; 5:1049&#x2013;1054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odeny TA, Lurain K, Strauss J, Fling SP, Sharon E, Wright A, et al. Effect of CD4+ T cell count on treatment-emergent adverse events among patients with and without HIV receiving immunotherapy for advanced cancer. J ImmunoTher Cancer 2022; 10:e005128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron M, Soulie C, Lavole A, Assoumou L, Abbar B, Fouquet B, et al.; The Anrs Co OncoVIHAC Study Group. Impact of anti PD-1 immunotherapy on HIV reservoir and anti-viral immune responses in people living with HIV and cancer. Cells 2022; 11:1015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Lu S, Yu X, Hu Y, Zhao J, Sun M, et al. Tislelizumab plus chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone as first-line treatment for advanced squamous non-small-cell lung cancer: final analysis of the randomized, phase III RATIONALE-307 trial. ESMO Open 2024; 9:103727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Wang J, Yu Y, Yu X, Hu Y, Ai X, et al. Tislelizumab plus chemotherapy as first-line treatment for locally advanced or metastatic nonsquamous NSCLC (RATIONALE 304): a randomized phase 3 trial. J Thorac Oncol 2021; 16:1512&#x2013;1522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang E, Sabichi AL, Kramer JR, Hartman C, Royse KE, White DL, et al. Nivolumab treatment for cancers in the HIV-infected population. J Immunother 2018; 41:379&#x2013;383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uldrick TS, Goncalves PH, Abdul-hay M, Claeys AJ, Emu B, Ernstoff MS, et al.; Cancer Immunotherapy Trials Network (CITN)-12 Study Team. Assessment of the safety of pembrolizumab in patients with HIV and advanced cancer-a phase 1 study. JAMA Oncol 2019; 5:1332&#x2013;1339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang W, Wang M, Jiang L, Su Z, Lin S. The peripheral CD4(+) T cells predict efficacy in non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients with the anti-PD-1 treatment. Transl Cancer Res 2024; 13:4052&#x2013;4061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng QM, Li YY, Wang YP, Li G-X, Sun Z-G, Zhang M. Prognostic significance of CD4+ tumour infiltrating lymphocytes in patients with non-small cell lung cancer receiving PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitors therapy. J Coll Physicians Surg Pak 2025; 35:341&#x2013;350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao D, Liu L, Liu J, Liu J. Predictive response and outcome of peripheral CD4(+) T cell subpopulations to combined immunotherapy and chemotherapy in advanced gastric cancer patients. Int Immunopharmacol 2024; 129:111663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wondmeneh TG, Mekonnen AT. The incidence rate of tuberculosis and its associated factors among HIV-positive persons in Sub-Saharan Africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis 2023; 23:613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraef C, Roen A, Podlekareva D, Bakowska E, Nemeth J, Knappik M, et al.; the RESPOND Study Group. Incident tuberculosis in people with HIV across Europe from 2012-2022: incidence rates, risk factors, and regional differences in a multicentre cohort study. Eur Respir J 2025; 65:2401904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraef C, Tusch E, Singh S, &#xd8;stergaard L, F&#xe4;tkenheuer G, Castagna A, et al.; EuroSIDA Study Group. All-cause and AIDS-related mortality among people with HIV across Europe from 2001 to 2020: impact of antiretroviral therapy, tuberculosis and regional differences in a multicentre cohort study. Lancet Reg Health Eur 2024; 44:100989.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41104928</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4406</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>393</Volume><Issue>18</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The New England journal of medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>N Engl J Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sevabertinib in Advanced <i>HER2</i>-Mutant Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1819</StartPage><EndPage>1832</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1819-1832</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1056/NEJMoa2511065</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND"><i>HER2</i> gene mutations occur in 2 to 4% of patients with non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Sevabertinib is an oral, reversible tyrosine kinase inhibitor that has shown anti-HER2 activity in preclinical models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted an open-label, multicenter, multicohort, phase 1-2 study to evaluate sevabertinib at a twice-daily dose of 20 mg in patients with locally advanced or metastatic <i>HER2</i>-mutant NSCLC. Three cohorts were defined according to previous therapy: cohort D comprised previously treated patients who had not received HER2-targeted therapy; cohort E, patients who had previously received HER2-directed antibody-drug conjugates; and cohort F, patients who had not previously received treatment. The primary end point was an objective response, as assessed by blinded independent central review. Secondary end points were duration of response and progression-free survival.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 209 patients received sevabertinib (as of June 27, 2025, the data-cutoff date); the median duration of follow-up was 13.8 months in cohort D, 11.7 months in cohort E, and 9.9 months in cohort F. Among 81 patients in cohort D, an objective response was observed in 64% (95% confidence interval [CI], 53 to 75); the median duration of response was 9.2 months (95% CI, 6.3 to 13.5), and the median progression-free survival was 8.3 months (95% CI, 6.9 to 12.3). Among 55 patients in cohort E, an objective response was observed in 38% (95% CI, 25 to 52); the median duration of response was 8.5 months, and the median progression-free survival was 5.5 months. Among 73 patients in cohort F, an objective response was observed in 71% (95% CI, 59 to 81), and the median duration of response was 11.0 months; data on progression-free survival were immature. Grade 3 or higher drug-related adverse events occurred in 31% of the patients. The most common adverse event was diarrhea (in 84 to 91%), with diarrhea of grade 3 or higher occurring in 5 to 23%. Treatment was discontinued by 3% of the patients owing to drug-related adverse events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Sevabertinib showed antitumor activity in patients with locally advanced or metastatic <i>HER2</i>-mutant NSCLC. Diarrhea was the most common adverse event. (Funded by Bayer; SOHO-01 ClinicalTrials.gov number, NCT05099172.).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Massachusetts Medical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le</LastName><ForeName>Xiuning</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center, Houston.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Tae Min</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6145-4426</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loong</LastName><ForeName>Herbert H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6607-1106</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phase 1 Clinical Trial Center, Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prelaj</LastName><ForeName>Arsela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncologia Medica Toracica Dipartimento, Fondazione IRCCS-Istituto Nazionale dei Tumori, Milan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goh</LastName><ForeName>Boon Cher</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology-Oncology, National University Cancer Institute, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Science Institute of Singapore, National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Beijing Hospital, Beijing.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center of Gerontology, Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Shun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Xiaorong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Union Hospital of Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medical Oncology, Hunan Cancer Hospital, Affiliated Cancer Hospital of Xiangya School of Medicine, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shinno</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Cancer Center Hospital, Tokyo.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daniele</LastName><ForeName>Gennaro</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5360-1895</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phase 1 Unit, Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Agostino Gemelli IRCCS, Rome.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Tsung-Ying</ForeName><Initials>TY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chest Medicine, Taichung Veterans General Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hye Ryun</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Department of Internal Medicine, Yonsei Cancer Center, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Medical Science, Brain Korea 21 Project, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruiter</LastName><ForeName>Gerrina</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Clinical Pharmacology and Thoracic Oncology, Netherlands Cancer Institute, Amsterdam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Carcinogenesis and Translational Research, Ministry of Education, Department I of Thoracic Oncology, Peking University Cancer Hospital and Institute, Beijing.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Novello</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Azienda Ospedaliero-Universitaria San Luigi Gonzaga, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miao</LastName><ForeName>Liyun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School, Nanjing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J&#xe4;nne</LastName><ForeName>Pasi A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lowe Center for Thoracic Oncology, Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, Boston.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goto</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Cancer Center Hospital East, Kashiwa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R&#xfc;ttinger</LastName><ForeName>Dominik</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer, Berlin.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Descamps</LastName><ForeName>Tine</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer, Reading, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brase</LastName><ForeName>Jan Christoph</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer Consumer Care, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bao</LastName><ForeName>Weichao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer HealthCare Pharmaceuticals, Whippany, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer HealthCare Pharmaceuticals, Whippany, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brega</LastName><ForeName>Nicoletta</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer Consumer Care, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grassi</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer, Milan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girard</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Curie, Paris.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Daniel Shao-Weng</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Cancer Center Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Duke-National University of Singapore Medical School, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>SOHO-01 Investigators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05099172</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017426">Clinical Trial, Phase I</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017427">Clinical Trial, Phase II</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>N Engl J Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0255562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-4793</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018719">Receptor, ErbB-2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C508053">ERBB2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D047428">Protein Kinase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000970">Antineoplastic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018719" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptor, ErbB-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077982" MajorTopicYN="N">Progression-Free Survival</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D047428" MajorTopicYN="Y">Protein Kinase Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000970" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antineoplastic Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demedts</LastName><ForeName>Ingel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dooms</LastName><ForeName>Christophe</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Batista de Almeida Rego</LastName><ForeName>Joilda</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matias</LastName><ForeName>Danielli</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Xiaorong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Cheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Lian</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Shun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Dongqing</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miao</LastName><ForeName>Liyun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yong Sheng</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yiping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cousin</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girard</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P&#xe9;rol</LastName><ForeName>Maurice</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Planchard</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pons-Tostivint</LastName><ForeName>Elvire</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raimbourg</LastName><ForeName>Judith</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loong</LastName><ForeName>Herbert</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bar</LastName><ForeName>Jair</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moskovitz</LastName><ForeName>Mor</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bearz</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belli</LastName><ForeName>Carmen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daniele</LastName><ForeName>Gennaro</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Novello</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pilotto</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prelaj</LastName><ForeName>Arsela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santoro</LastName><ForeName>Armando</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tiseo</LastName><ForeName>Marcello</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goto</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ichihara</LastName><ForeName>Eiki</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katakura</LastName><ForeName>Seigo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kato</LastName><ForeName>Yuka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murakami</LastName><ForeName>Haruyasu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishino</LastName><ForeName>Kazumi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakakibara</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakamoto</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shinno</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Teppei</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dingemans</LastName><ForeName>Anne-Marie</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruiter</LastName><ForeName>Gerrina</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soares</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Dae Ho</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Ki Hyeong</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hye Ryun</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Tae Min</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Yu Jung</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shim</LastName><ForeName>Byoung Yong</ForeName><Initials>BY</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Jong Mu</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goh</LastName><ForeName>Boon-Cher</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Daniel Shao-Weng</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toh</LastName><ForeName>Chee Keong</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aguilar Hern&#xe1;ndez</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;s</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Felip</LastName><ForeName>Enriqueta</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Juan-Vidal</LastName><ForeName>Oscar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soto</LastName><ForeName>Juan Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Miguel Luken</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moreno</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruffinelli</LastName><ForeName>Jose Carlos</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Chun-Hui</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Yao</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Ta</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Chih Hsin</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Tsung-Ying</ForeName><Initials>TY</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gadgeel</LastName><ForeName>Shirish</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J&#xe4;nne</LastName><ForeName>Pasi A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le</LastName><ForeName>Xiuning</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leal</LastName><ForeName>Ticiana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Massarelli</LastName><ForeName>Erminia</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Jiaxin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spira</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41104928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2511065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>