<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40483602</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2473-4209</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical physics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Phys</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dose to circulating blood in intensity-modulated total body irradiation, total marrow irradiation, and total marrow and lymphoid irradiation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mp.17913</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Multi-isocentric intensity-modulated (IM) total body irradiation (TBI), total marrow irradiation (TMI), and total marrow and lymphoid irradiation (TMLI) are gaining popularity. A question arises on the impact of the interplay between blood circulation and dynamic delivery on blood dose.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study answers the question by introducing a new whole-body blood circulation modeling technique.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A whole-body CT with intravenous contrast was used to develop the blood circulation model. Fifteen organs and tissues, heart chambers, and great vessels were segmented using a deep-learning-based auto-contouring software. The main blood vessels were segmented using an in-house algorithm. Blood density, velocity, time-to-heart, and perfusion distributions were derived for systole, diastole, and portal circulations and used to simulate trajectories of blood particles during delivery. With the same prescription of 12&#xa0;Gy in 8 fractions, doses to circulating blood were calculated for three plans: (1) an IM-TBI plan prescribing uniform dose to the whole body while reducing lung and kidney doses; (2) a TMI plan treating all bones; and (3) a TMLI plan treating all bones, major lymph nodes, and spleen; TMI and TMLI plans were optimized to reduce doses to non-target tissue.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Circulating blood received 1.57&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.43&#xa0;Gy, 1.04&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.32&#xa0;Gy, and 1.09&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.32&#xa0;Gy in one fraction and 12.60&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;1.21&#xa0;Gy, 8.34&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.88&#xa0;Gy, and 8.71&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.92&#xa0;Gy in 8 fractions in IM-TBI, TMI, and TMLI, respectively. The interplay effect of blood motion with IM delivery did not change the mean dose, but changed the dose heterogeneity of the circulating blood. Fractionation reduced the blood dose heterogeneity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A novel whole-body blood circulating model was developed based on patient-specific anatomy and realistic blood dynamics, concentration, and perfusion. Using the blood circulation model, we developed a dosimetry tool for circulating blood in IM-TBI, TMI, and TMLI.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 American Association of Physicists in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Bingqi</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cherian</LastName><ForeName>Sheen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murphy</LastName><ForeName>Erin S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sauter</LastName><ForeName>Craig S</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology Oncology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sobecks</LastName><ForeName>Ronald M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology Oncology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rotz</LastName><ForeName>Seth</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Peds Hemonc and Blood and Marrow Transplantation, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanna</LastName><ForeName>Rabi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Peds Hemonc and Blood and Marrow Transplantation, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scott</LastName><ForeName>Jacob G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Ping</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Phys</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0425746</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0094-2405</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood circulation model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total body irradiation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total marrow and lymphoid irradiation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40483602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mp.17913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Thomas ED, Storb R, Buckner CD. Total&#x2010;body irradiation in preparation for marrow engraftment. Transplant Proc. 1976;8(4):591&#x2010;593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JYC, Filippi AR, Dabaja BS, Yahalom J, Specht L. Total body irradiation: guidelines from the International Lymphoma Radiation Oncology Group (ILROG). Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2018;101(3):521&#x2010;529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolden SL, Rabinovitch RA, Bittner NH, et&#xa0;al. American College of Radiology (ACR) and American Society for Radiation Oncology (ASTRO) practice guideline for the performance of total body irradiation (TBI). Am J Clin Oncol. 2013;36(1):97&#x2010;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clift RA, Buckner CD, Appelbaum FR, Sullivan KM, Storb R, Thomas ED. Long&#x2010;term follow&#x2010;Up of a randomized trial of two irradiation regimens for patients receiving allogeneic marrow transplants during first remission of acute myeloid leukemia. Blood. 1998;92(4):1455&#x2010;1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springer A, Hammer J, Winkler E, et&#xa0;al. Total body irradiation with volumetric modulated arc therapy: dosimetric data and first clinical experience. Radiat Oncol. 2016;11:46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang L, Folkerts M, Zhang Y, et&#xa0;al. Volumetric modulated arc therapy based total body irradiation: workflow and clinical experience with an indexed rotational immobilization system. Phys Imag Radiat Onc. 2017;4:22&#x2010;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tas B, Durmus IF, Okumus A, et&#xa0;al. Total&#x2010;body irradiation using linac&#x2010;based volumetric modulated arc therapy: its clinical accuracy, feasibility and reliability. Radiother Oncol. 2018;129(3):527&#x2010;533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo B, Sheen C, Murphy E, et&#xa0;al. Image&#x2010;guided volumetric&#x2010;modulated arc therapy of total body irradiation: an efficient workflow from simulation to delivery. J Appl Clin Med Phys. 2021;22(10):169&#x2010;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovalchuk N, Simiele E, Skinner L, et&#xa0;al. The Stanford volumetric modulated arc therapy total body irradiation technique. Pract Radiat Oncol. 2022;12(3):245&#x2010;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang&#x2010;Velten ER, Parsons D, Lee P, et&#xa0;al. Volumetric Modulated Arc Therapy Enabled Total Body Irradiation (VMAT&#x2010;TBI): six&#x2010;year clinical experience and treatment outcomes. Transplant Cell Ther. 2022;28(2):113.e111&#x2010;113.e118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dyk J, Galvin JM, Glasgow GP, Podgorsak EB. The Physical Aspect of Total and Half Body Photon Irradation. AAPM Report No. 17. American Association of Physicists in Medicine; 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobyzeva D, Shelikhova L, Loginova A, et&#xa0;al. Optimized conformal total body irradiation among recipients of TCRalphabeta/CD19&#x2010;depleted grafts in pediatric patients with hematologic malignancies: single&#x2010;center experience. Front Oncol. 2021;11:785916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui C, Simiele E, Lozko Y, et&#xa0;al. Volumetric modulated arc therapy total body irradiation improves toxicity outcomes compared to 2D total body irradiation. Front Oncol. 2024;14:1459287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JYC, Liu A, Schultheiss T, et&#xa0;al. Targeted total marrow irradiation using three&#x2010;dimensional image&#x2010;guided tomographic intensity&#x2010;modulated radiation therapy: an alternative to standard total body irradiation. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2006;12(3):306&#x2010;315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydogan B, Yeginer M, Kavak GO, Fan J, Radosevich JA, Gwe&#x2010;Ya K. Total marrow irradiation with RapidArc volumetric arc therapy. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2011;81(2):592&#x2010;599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corv&#xf2; R, Zeverino M, Vagge S, et&#xa0;al. Helical tomotherapy targeting total bone marrow after total body irradiation for patients with relapsed acute leukemia undergoing an allogeneic stem cell transplant. Radiother Oncol. 2011;98(3):382&#x2010;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haraldsson A, Wichert S, Engstr&#xf6;m PE, et&#xa0;al. Organ sparing total marrow irradiation compared to total body irradiation prior to allogeneic stem cell transplantation. Eur J Haematol. 2021;107(4):393&#x2010;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladbury C, Han C, Liu A, Wong JYC. Volumetric modulated arc therapy based total marrow and lymphoid irradiation: workflow and clinical experience. Front Oncol. 2023;12:1042652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JYC, Filippi AR, Scorsetti M, Hui S, Muren LP, Mancosu P. Total marrow and total lymphoid irradiation in bone marrow transplantation for acute leukaemia. Lancet Oncol. 2020;21(10):e477&#x2010;e487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Malki MM, Palmer J, Tsai NC, et&#xa0;al. Total marrow and lymphoid irradiation as conditioning in haploidentical transplant with posttransplant cyclophosphamide. Blood Adv. 2022;6(14):4098&#x2010;4106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa H, Konishi T, Najima Y, et&#xa0;al. Phase I trial of myeloablative conditioning with 3&#x2010;day total marrow and lymphoid irradiation for leukemia. Cancer Sci. 2023;114(2):596&#x2010;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han C, Liu A, Wong JYC. Target coverage and normal organ sparing in dose&#x2010;escalated total marrow and lymphatic irradiation: a single&#x2010;institution experience. Front Oncol. 2022;12:946725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui S, Brunstein C, Takahashi Y, et&#xa0;al. Dose escalation of total marrow irradiation in high&#x2010;risk patients undergoing allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2017;23(7):1110&#x2010;1116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong J, Forman S, Rosenthal J, et&#xa0;al. Phase I dose escalation trials of total marrow irradiation (TMI) using helical TomoTherapy (HT) with concurrent full&#x2010;intensity chemotherapy in patients with advanced acute leukemia undergoing allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation (HCT). Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2011;81(2 (Supplement)):S20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JYC, Forman S, Somlo G, et&#xa0;al. Dose escalation of total marrow irradiation with concurrent chemotherapy in patients with advanced acute leukemia undergoing allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2013;85(1):148&#x2010;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JYC, Liu A, Han C, et&#xa0;al. Total marrow irradiation (TMI): addressing an unmet need in hematopoietic cell transplantation&#x2014;a single institution experience review. Front Oncol. 2022;12:1003908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molloy JA, Statistical analysis of dose heterogeneity in circulating blood: implications for sequential methods of total body irradiation. Med Phys. 2010;37(11):5568&#x2010;5578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erturk SM, Ichikawa T, Sou H, Tsukamoto T, Motosugi U, Araki T. Effect of duration of contrast material injection on peak enhancement times and values of the aorta, main portal vein, and liver at dynamic MDCT with the dose of contrast medium tailored to patient weight. Clin Radiol. 2008;63(3):263&#x2010;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae KT. Intravenous contrast medium administration and scan timing at CT: considerations and approaches. Radiology. 2010;256(1):32&#x2010;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kletting P, Kull T, Bunjes D, et&#xa0;al. Radioimmunotherapy with anti&#x2010;CD66 antibody: improving the biodistribution using a physiologically based pharmacokinetic model. J Nucl Med. 2010;51(3):484&#x2010;491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberlein U, Broer JH, Vandevoorde C, et&#xa0;al. Biokinetics and dosimetry of commonly used radiopharmaceuticals in diagnostic nuclear medicine&#x2014;a review. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2011;38(12):2269&#x2010;2281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green MA, Mathias CJ, Smith NJ, Cheng M, Hutchins GD. In vivo quantitative whole&#x2010;body perfusion imaging using radiolabeled Copper(II) Bis(Thiosemicarbazone) complexes and positron emission tomography (PET). Methods Mol Biol. 2022;2393:751&#x2010;771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beekman C, Withrow JD, Correa Alfonso CM, et&#xa0;al. A stochastic model of blood flow to calculate blood dose during radiotherapy. Phys Med Biol. 2023;68(22).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesulu BP, Mallick S, Lin SH, Krishnan S. A systematic review of the influence of radiation&#x2010;induced lymphopenia on survival outcomes in solid tumors. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2018;123:42&#x2010;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing S, Shin J, Pursley J, et&#xa0;al. A dynamic blood flow model to compute absorbed dose to circulating blood and lymphocytes in liver external beam radiotherapy. Phys Med Biol. 2022;67(4):045010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammi A. 4D dosimetric&#x2010;blood flow model: impact of prolonged fraction delivery times of IMRT on the dose to the circulating lymphocytes. Phys Med Biol. 2023;68(14):145017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J, Xing S, McCullum L, et&#xa0;al. HEDOS&#x2010;a computational tool to assess radiation dose to circulating blood cells during external beam radiotherapy based on whole&#x2010;body blood flow simulations. Phys Med Biol. 2021;66(16):164001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Kermenguy F, Benzazon N, Maury P, et&#xa0;al. LymphoDose: a lymphocyte dose estimation framework&#x2010;application to brain radiotherapy. Phys Med Biol. 2024;69(10):105009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colen J, Nguyen C, Liyanage SW, et&#xa0;al. Predicting radiation&#x2010;induced immune suppression in lung cancer patients treated with stereotactic body radiation therapy. Med Phys. 2024, 51, 6485&#x2010;6500. doi:10.1002/mp.17181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leggett RW, Williams LR. A proposed blood circulation model for Reference Man. Health Phys. 1995;69(2):187&#x2010;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabe IT, Gault JH, Ross J Jr, et&#xa0;al. Measurement of instantaneous blood flow velocity and pressure in conscious man with a catheter&#x2010;tip velocity probe. Circulation. 1969;40(5):603&#x2010;614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Volpe A, Ferreri AJ, Annaloro C, et&#xa0;al. Lethal pulmonary complications significantly correlate with individually assessed mean lung dose in patients with hematologic malignancies treated with total body irradiation. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2002;52(2):483&#x2010;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelsey CR, Horwitz ME, Chino JP, et&#xa0;al. Severe pulmonary toxicity after myeloablative conditioning using total body irradiation: an assessment of risk factors. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2011;81(3):812&#x2010;818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel J, Hui S, Hua CH, et&#xa0;al. Pulmonary toxicity after total body irradiation&#x2014;critical review of the literature and recommendations for toxicity reporting. Front Oncol. 2021;11:708906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esiashvili N, Lu X, Ulin K, et&#xa0;al. Higher reported lung dose received during total body irradiation for allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation in children with acute lymphoblastic leukemia is associated with inferior survival: a report from the Children's Oncology Group. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2019;104(3):513&#x2010;521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons D, Lim TY, Teruel JR, et&#xa0;al. Considerations for intensity modulated total body or total marrow and lymphoid irradiation. Clin Transl Radiat Oncol. 2023;43:100674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Losert C, Shpani R, Kie&#xdf;ling R, et&#xa0;al. Novel rotatable tabletop for total&#x2010;body irradiation using a linac&#x2010;based VMAT technique. Radiat Oncol. 2019;14(1):244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abugideiri M, Nanda RH, Butker C, et&#xa0;al. Factors influencing pulmonary toxicity in children undergoing allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation in the setting of total body irradiation&#x2010;based myeloablative conditioning. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2016;94(2):349&#x2010;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pino y Torres JL, Bross DS, Lam WC, Wharam MD, Santos GW, Order SE. Risk factors in interstitial pneumonitis following allogenic bone marrow transplantation. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 1982;8(8):1301&#x2010;1307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers SA, Wallington MM. Total body irradiation and pneumonitis risk: a review of outcomes. Br J Cancer. 2004;90(11):2080&#x2010;2084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oya N, Sasai K, Tachiiri S, et&#xa0;al. Influence of radiation dose rate and lung dose on interstitial pneumonitis after fractionated total body irradiation: acute parotitis may predict interstitial pneumonitis. Int J Hematol. 2006;83(1):86&#x2010;91.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40483574</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-2452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition in clinical practice : official publication of the American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Clin Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ECMO patient energy requirements: A descriptive, retrospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ncp.11330</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Indirect calorimetry (IC) in patients receiving extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO) is complicated. This study presents a novel IC method for this population and compares energy expenditure (EE) from IC with predictive equations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">IC was performed at the native lung using a Q-NRG+ indirect calorimeter. A CO<sub>2</sub> sensor connected to the ECMO oxygenator primary exhalation port collected FeCO<sub>2</sub> during IC studies. ECMO-VO<sub>2</sub> and ECMO-VCO<sub>2</sub> were calculated from sweep gas oxygen concentration, FeCO<sub>2</sub>, and sweep flow. EE was calculated from the combined readings. EE was compared with 25&#x2009;kcal/kg, 30&#x2009;kcal/kg, and Mifflin St Jeor. Subanalysis compared EE over time (ECMO days 1-3, 4-10, 11-21, and &gt;21) and between venoarterial and venovenous patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In total, 90 assessments in 52 patients were analyzed. The cohort was 67.3% male with a median age of 54 years, and median ECMO duration of 207&#x2009;h. EE was 1523&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;432&#x2009;kcal/day (18.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.9&#x2009;kcal/kg/day). Energy needs did not vary significantly over time (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.24); however, readings from days 11 to 21 were higher than days 1-3 (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0497). No significant differences between cannulation types were observed. EE was significantly lower than all predicted results (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Mean difference between EE and predicted energy ranged from 413 to 1099&#x2009;kcal/day. No equation was strongly correlated with EE (r<sub>s</sub>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.15-0.61) overall or after stratification by cannulation type.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study presents a viable method for incorporating IC in patients receiving ECMO. Using this method, EE in patients receiving ECMO was significantly lower than predicted. Using IC may help prevent overfeeding.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pelekhaty</LastName><ForeName>Stacy L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8060-5389</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Nutrition, University of Maryland Medical Center, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rector</LastName><ForeName>Raymond P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of ECMO, Department of Perioperative Services, University of Maryland Medical Center, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Zhongjun J</ForeName><Initials>ZJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grazioli</LastName><ForeName>Alison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plazak</LastName><ForeName>Michael E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Services, University of Maryland Medical Center, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Bradley S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Surgery, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Griffith</LastName><ForeName>Bartley P</ForeName><Initials>BP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Surgery, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Aakash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, University of Maryland Medical Center, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stein</LastName><ForeName>Deborah M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>R. Adams Cowley Shock Trauma Center, Program in Trauma, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scalea</LastName><ForeName>Thomas M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>R. Adams Cowley Shock Trauma Center, Program in Trauma, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rabin</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Clin Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8606733</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0884-5336</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ECMO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">indirect calorimetry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition assessment</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40483574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ncp.11330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>McClave SA, Taylor BE, Martindale RG, et al. Guidelines for the provision and assessment of nutrition support therapy in the adult critically ill patient: Society of Critical Care Medicine (SCCM) and American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (A.S.P.E.N.). JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2016;40(2):159&#x2010;211. doi:10.1177/0148607115621863</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer P, Blaser AR, Berger MM, et al. ESPEN practical and partially revised guideline: clinical nutrition in the intensive care unit. Clin Nutr. 2023;42(9):1671&#x2010;1689. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2023.07.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priem S, Jonckheer J, De Waele E, Stiens J. Indirect calorimetry in spontaneously breathing, mechanically ventilated and extracorporeally oxygenated patients: an engineering review. Sensors (Basel). 2023;23(8):4143. doi:10.3390/s23084143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordoza M, Chan LN, Bridges E, Thompson H. Methods for estimating energy expenditure in critically ill adults. AACN Adv Crit Care. 2020;31(3):254&#x2010;264. doi:10.4037/aacnacc2020110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zanten ARH, De Waele E, Wischmeyer PE. Nutrition therapy and critical illness: practical guidance for the ICU, post&#x2010;ICU, and long&#x2010;term convalescence phases. Crit Care. 2019;23(1):368. doi:10.1186/s13054-019-2657-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dresen E, Naidoo O, Hill A, et al. Medical nutrition therapy in patients receiving ECMO: evidence&#x2010;based guidance for clinical practice. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2023;47(2):220&#x2010;235. doi:10.1002/jpen.2467</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Waele E, Jonckheer J, Pen JJ, et al. Energy expenditure of patients on ECMO: a prospective pilot study. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2019;63(3):360&#x2010;364. doi:10.1111/aas.13287</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Waele E, van Zanten ARH. Routine use of indirect calorimetry in critically ill patients: pros and cons. Crit Care. 2022;26(1):123. doi:10.1186/s13054-022-04000-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wollersheim T, Frank S, M&#xfc;ller MC, et al. Measuring Energy Expenditure in extracorporeal lung support Patients (MEEP)&#x2014;protocol, feasibility and pilot trial. Clin Nutr. 2018;37(1):301&#x2010;307. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2017.01.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankenfield D, Hise M, Malone A, Russell M, Gradwell E, Compher C. Prediction of resting metabolic rate in critically ill adult patients: results of a systematic review of the evidence. J Am Diet Assoc. 2007;107(9):1552&#x2010;1561. doi:10.1016/j.jada.2007.06.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wooley JA, Sax HC. Indirect calorimetry: applications to practice. Nutr Clin Pract. 2003;18(5):434&#x2010;439. doi:10.1177/0115426503018005434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mifflin M, St Jeor S, Hill L, Scott B, Daugherty S, Koh Y. A new predictive equation for resting energy expenditure in healthy individuals. Am J Clin Nutr. 1990;51(2):241&#x2010;247. doi:10.1093/ajcn/51.2.241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankenfield D, Smith J, Cooney R. Validation of 2 approaches to predicting resting metabolic rate in critically ill patients. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2004;28(4):259&#x2010;264. doi:10.1177/0148607104028004259</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankenfield D. Validation of an equation for resting metabolic rate in older obese, critically ill patients. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2011;35(2):264&#x2010;269. doi:10.1177/0148607110377903</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez CL, Pelekhaty S, Massetti JM, et al. Validation of predictive equations to assess energy expenditure in acute spinal cord injury. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2018;85(5):984&#x2010;991. doi:10.1097/TA.0000000000001959</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cade JF, Jones DA, Bellomo R. Nutrition in the intensive care unit&#x2014;you must breathe what you eat. Crit Care Resusc. 2016;18(4):224&#x2010;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankenfield DC. Impact of feeding on resting metabolic rate and gas exchange in critically ill patients. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2019;43(2):226&#x2010;233. doi:10.1002/jpen.1420</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshima T, Berger MM, De Waele E, et al. Indirect calorimetry in nutritional therapy. A position paper by the ICALIC study group. Clin Nutr. 2017;36(3):651&#x2010;662. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2016.06.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reignier J, Plantefeve G, Mira JP, et al. Low versus standard calorie and protein feeding in ventilated adults with shock: a randomised, controlled, multicentre, open&#x2010;label, parallel&#x2010;group trial (NUTRIREA&#x2010;3). Lancet Respir Med. 2023;11(7):602&#x2010;612. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00092-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacGowan L, Smith E, Elliott&#x2010;Hammond C, et al. Adequacy of nutrition support during extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Clin Nutr. 2019;38(1):324&#x2010;331. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2018.01.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelekhaty S, Gessler J, Dante S, et al. Nutrition and outcomes in venovenous extracorporeal membrane oxygenation: an observational cohort study. Nutr Clin Pract. 2024;40(1):117&#x2010;124. doi:10.1002/ncp.11132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Heo E, Song IA, et al. Nutritional support and clinical outcomes in critically ill patients supported with veno&#x2010;arterial extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Clin Nutr. 2020;39(8):2617&#x2010;2623. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2019.11.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatucu&#x2010;Babet OA, Diehl A, Kratzing C, et al. Modified indirect calorimetry for patients on venoarterial extracorporeal membrane oxygenation: a pilot feasibility study. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2023;77(9):888&#x2010;894. doi:10.1038/s41430-023-01291-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatucu&#x2010;Babet OA, Nguo K, Lambell KJ, Romero L, Earthman CP, Ridley EJ. Doubly labelled water for determining total energy expenditure in adult critically ill and acute care hospitalized inpatients: a scoping review. Clin Nutr. 2022;41(2):424&#x2010;432. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2021.12.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller MC, Wilke SK, Dobbermann A, et al. Quantitative gas exchange in extracorporeal membrane oxygenation&#x2010;a new device: accuracy, approach&#x2010;based difficulties, and caloric targeting. ASAIO J. 2023;69(1):61&#x2010;68. doi:10.1097/MAT.0000000000001662</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>