<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41139072</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-6080</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Transplantation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Transplantation</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Extracorporeal Membrane Oxygenation Versus Off-pump Technique in Lung Transplantation: A Meta-analysis With Reconstructed Time-to-event Data.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/TP.0000000000005544</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO) is an important intraoperative support strategy in lung transplantation, particularly for high-risk patients. Although ECMO offers theoretical advantages such as controlled reperfusion and hemodynamic stabilization, its impact on postoperative outcomes compared with off-pump techniques remains debated. This study aimed to evaluate evidence comparing ECMO and off-pump approaches.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Three databases were assessed. The primary outcome was overall survival. Secondary outcomes included time until extubation, intensive care unit and hospital length of stay (LOS), primary graft dysfunction at postoperative day 3, and need for renal replacement therapy. Hazard ratio, odds ratio, and mean difference (MD) with 95% confidence interval (CI) were calculated. Time-to-event data reconstruction and sensitivity analyses were performed. A subgroup analysis compared planned versus unplanned ECMO to address treatment allocation bias.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Six retrospective studies with 1008 patients were included. ECMO was associated with lower overall survival (hazard ratio, 1.555; 95% CI, 1.13-2.15; P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.007). ECMO also resulted in longer time until extubation (MD, 1.24 d; 95% CI, 0.38-2.09; P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.005), intensive care unit LOS (MD, 2.40 d; 95% CI, 1.20-3.61; P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.001), hospital LOS (MD, 3.61 d; 95% CI, 0.81-6.40; P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.011), and higher primary graft dysfunction incidence at day 3 (odds ratio, 2.18; 95% CI, 1.34-3.53; P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.002). No significant difference was observed for renal replacement therapy (P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.054). Landmark analysis showed poorer survival for patients supported with ECMO during the first 6 mo but not beyond.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ECMO is associated with poorer early survival and adverse outcomes but remains crucial for high-risk patients, underscoring the need for optimized selection and standardized management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Passos</LastName><ForeName>Felipe S</ForeName><Initials>FS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, MaterDei Hospital, Salvador, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carvalho E Silva</LastName><ForeName>Maria Clara</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Est&#xe1;cio de S&#xe1; University, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodrigues</LastName><ForeName>Fabiano Taranto de O</ForeName><Initials>FTO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Est&#xe1;cio de S&#xe1; University, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Rachid Eduardo Noleto da Nobrega</ForeName><Initials>RENDN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, Barretos Cancer Hospital, Barretos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pessoa</LastName><ForeName>Bernardo M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, Hospital Santa Cruz, Rede D'Or, Curitiba, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Treml</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Perioperative and Pain Medicine, Stanford School of Medicine, Palo Alto, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heim</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac and Vascular Surgery, Klinikum Bayreuth, Medical Campus Oberfranken of Friedrich Alexander University, Bayreuth, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siemeni</LastName><ForeName>Thierry</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, Jena University Hospital, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kirov</LastName><ForeName>Hristo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, Jena University Hospital, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doenst</LastName><ForeName>Torsten</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, Jena University Hospital, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caldonazo</LastName><ForeName>Tulio</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, Jena University Hospital, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Transplantation</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0132144</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0041-1337</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41139072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TP.0000000000005544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00007890-990000000-01201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bos S, Vos R, Van Raemdonck DE, et al. Survival in adult lung transplantation: where are we in 2020? Curr Opin Organ Transplant. 2020;25:268&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartert M, Senbaklavaci O, Gohrbandt B, et al. Lung transplantation: A treatment option in end-stage lung disease. Dtsch Arzteblatt Int. 2014;111:107&#x2013;116&#x2009;+&#x2009;11-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fessler J, Finet M, Fischler M, et al. New aspects of lung transplantation: A narrative overview covering important aspects of perioperative management. Life (Basel, Switzerland). 2022;13:92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidi Y, Kovats Z, Bohacs A, et al. Lung transplant rehabilitation&#x2014;a review. Life (Basel, Switzerland). 2023;13:506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laskey D, Housman B, Dawodu G, et al. Intraoperative extracorporeal support during lung transplantation: not just for the high-risk patient. J Clin Med. 2024;13:192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fessler J, Sage E, Roux A, et al. Is Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation withdrawal a safe option after double-lung transplantation? Ann Thorac Surg. 2020;110:1167&#x2013;1174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weingarten N, Schraufnagel D, Plitt G, et al. Comparison of mechanical cardiopulmonary support strategies during lung transplantation. Expert Rev Med Devices. 2020;17:1075&#x2013;1093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Nobrega Oliveira REN, Passos FS, Pessoa BM. Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation vs cardiopulmonary bypass in lung transplantation: an updated meta-analysis. Gen Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2025;73:137&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan EG, Hyzny EJ, Furukawa M, et al. Intraoperative support for primary bilateral lung transplantation: a propensity-matched analysis. Ann Thorac Surg. 2023;115:743&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz S, Hoetzenecker K, Klepetko W. Procedural mechanical support for lung transplantation. Curr Opin Organ Transplant. 2021;26:309&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ. 2016;355:i4919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, et al. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Cochrane Editorial Unit, ed. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10:ED000142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y, Royston P. Reconstructing time-to-event data from published Kaplan-Meier curves. Stata J. 2017;17:786&#x2013;802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel M, Khanna P, Kishore J. Understanding survival analysis: Kaplan-Meier estimate. Int J Ayurveda Res. 2010;1:274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chacon&#x2010;Alberty L, Ye S, Elsenousi A, et al. Effect of intraoperative support mode on circulating inflammatory biomarkers after lung transplantation surgery. Artif Organs. 2023;47:749&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpern SE, Wright MC, Madsen G, et al. Textbook outcome in lung transplantation: Planned venoarterial extracorporeal membrane oxygenation versus off-pump support for patients without pulmonary hypertension. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2022;41:1628&#x2013;1637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettenuzzo T, Faggi G, Di Gregorio G, et al. Blood products transfusion and mid-term outcomes of lung transplanted patients under extracorporeal membrane oxygenation support. Prog transplant. 2018;28:314&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salman J, Bernhard BA, Ius F, et al. Intraoperative extracorporeal circulatory support in lung transplantation for pulmonary fibrosis. Ann Thorac Surg. 2021;111:1316&#x2013;1324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaravilli V, Morlacchi LC, Merrino A, et al. Intraoperative extracorporeal membrane oxygenation for lung transplantation in cystic fibrosis patients: Predictors and impact on outcome. J Cyst Fibros. 2020;19:659&#x2013;665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ius F, Sommer W, Tudorache I, et al. Five-year experience with intraoperative extracorporeal membrane oxygenation in lung transplantation: Indications and midterm results. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2016;35:49&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weill D, Benden C, Corris PA, et al. A consensus document for the selection of lung transplant candidates: 2014&#x2014;an update from the Pulmonary Transplantation Council of the International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2015;34:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pervaiz Butt S, Kakar V, Abdulaziz S, et al. Enhancing lung transplantation with ECMO: a comprehensive review of mechanisms, outcomes, and future considerations. J Extra Corpor Technol. 2024;56:191&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoetzenecker K, Benazzo A, Stork T, et al.; Vienna Lung Transplant Group. Bilateral lung transplantation on intraoperative extracorporeal membrane oxygenator: An observational study. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2020;160:320&#x2013;327.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartwig M, Van Berkel V, Bharat A, et al.; Expert Consensus Panel. The American Association for Thoracic Surgery (AATS) 2022 Expert Consensus Document: the use of mechanical circulatory support in lung transplantation. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2023;165:301&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becher PM, Go&#xdf;ling A, Schrage B, et al. Procedural volume and outcomes in patients undergoing VA-ECMO support. Crit Care. 2020;24:291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajkowski EF, Herrera G, Hatton L, et al. ELSO guidelines for adult and pediatric extracorporeal membrane oxygenation circuits. ASAIO J. 2022;68:133&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas J, Kostousov V, Teruya J. Bleeding and thrombotic complications in the use of extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. Semin Thromb Hemost. 2018;44:020&#x2013;029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loor G, Huddleston S, Hartwig M, et al. Effect of mode of intraoperative support on primary graft dysfunction after lung transplant. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2022;164:1351&#x2013;1361.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie JD, Carby M, Bag R, et al.; ISHLT Working Group on Primary Lung Graft Dysfunction. Report of the ISHLT Working Group on primary lung graft dysfunction part ii: definition. a consensus statement of the International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2005;24:1454&#x2013;1459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snell GI, Yusen RD, Weill D, et al. Report of the ISHLT Working Group on Primary Lung Graft Dysfunction, part I: definition and grading&#x2014;a 2016 consensus group statement of the International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2017;36:1097&#x2013;1103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosi&#x144;ski S, Darocha T, Jarosz A, et al. Difficulties in funding of VA-ECMO therapy for patients with severe accidental hypothermia. Anaesth intens therapy. 2017;49:106&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41137364</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2194-802X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diagnosis (Berlin, Germany)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diagnosis (Berl)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A framework for defining diagnostically challenging conditions identifiable through electronic algorithms.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/dx-2025-0034</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diagnostic delays and errors are serious and costly, affecting approximately 5&#x202f;% of US adults in the outpatient setting annually. Patients with difficult-to-diagnose conditions may spend months or years undergoing diagnostic evaluation in search of a correct diagnosis. Methods are needed to identify patients with diagnostically challenging conditions (DCCs) who are experiencing diagnostic odysseys and, as a result, potential missed opportunities in their diagnosis. Given the increasing availability of longitudinal EHR data to map a patient's journey, we propose a new framework to proactively identify patients with DCCs using electronic data. These patients are at risk for missed opportunities in diagnosis, and a timelier diagnosis can improve their outcomes. We propose criteria for identifying specific DCCs where the diagnostic process for that condition makes them amenable to detection using EHR-based algorithms. We discuss the application of the proposed framework to an exemplary case study of fibrotic interstitial lung disease and provide examples of algorithms that could be implemented in the future. This work can help identify patients earlier in their diagnostic journeys, resulting in adequate follow-up and fewer missed or delayed diagnoses. Our proposed framework can inform research and potential solutions that are more <i>real-time</i> to potentially mitigate and avoid delays in care and resulting harm.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Walter de Gruyter GmbH, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olson</LastName><ForeName>Andrew P J</ForeName><Initials>APJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7226-5783</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hospital Medicine, Department of Medicine; Division of Pediatric Hospital Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, University of Minnesota Medical School, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sloane</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Innovations in Quality, Effectiveness and Safety, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zimolzak</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Innovations in Quality, Effectiveness and Safety, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaul</LastName><ForeName>Bhavika</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Innovations in Quality, Effectiveness and Safety, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaghani</LastName><ForeName>Viralkumar</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Innovations in Quality, Effectiveness and Safety, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matin</LastName><ForeName>Roni</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Innovations in Quality, Effectiveness and Safety, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cholankeril</LastName><ForeName>Rosann T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Innovations in Quality, Effectiveness and Safety, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Hardeep</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Innovations in Quality, Effectiveness and Safety, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Diagnosis (Berl)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101654734</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2194-802X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic error</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electronic health records</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">missed and delayed diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient safety</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41137364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/dx-2025-0034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">dx-2025-0034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences . Engineering, and medicine and others, medicine. In: Improving diagnosis in health care . Washington, DC: National Academies Press; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, H, Meyer, AND, Thomas, EJ. The frequency of diagnostic errors in outpatient care: estimations from three large observational studies involving US adult populations. BMJ Qual Saf 2014;23:727&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjqs-2013-002627 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2013-002627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunderson, CG, Bilan, VP, Holleck, JL, Nickerson, P, Cherry, BM, Chui, P, et al.. Prevalence of harmful diagnostic errors in hospitalised adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Qual Saf 2020;29:1008&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjqs-2019-010822 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2019-010822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng, LN, Sum-Ping, O, Geng, YJ. Phases of the diagnostic journey: a framework. Int Arch Intern Med 2019;3:013. https://www.clinmedjournals.org/articles/iaim/international-archives-of-internal-medicine-iaim-3-013.php?jid=iaim .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachter, RM. Why diagnostic errors don&#x2019;t get any respect - and what can be done about them. Health Aff (Millwood) . 2010;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satterfield, K, Rubin, JC, Friedman, CP. Toward a learning ecosystem for diagnostic excellence [White paper]. University of Michigan 2018. Available from: https://deepblue.lib.umich.edu/bitstream/2027.42/145487/1/Toward a Learning Ecosystem for Diagnostic Excellence (2018) .pdf [Accessed 21 August 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorincz, CY, Drazen, E, Sokol, PE, Neerukonda, KV, Metzger, J, Toepp, MC, et al.. Research in ambulatory patient safety 2000-2010: a 10-year review . Chicago IL: American Medical Association; 2011:106 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sittig, DF, Singh, H. A new socio-technical model for studying health information technology in complex adaptive healthcare systems. Qual Saf Health Care 2010;19:i68&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1136/qshc.2010.042085 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/qshc.2010.042085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, M, Murphy, D, Laxmisan, A, Sittig, D, Reis, B, Esquivel, A, et al.. Developing software to &#x201c;Track and Catch&#x201d; missed Follow-up of abnormal test results in a complex sociotechnical environment. Appl Clin Inf 2013;04:359&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.4338/aci-2013-04-ra-0019 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4338/aci-2013-04-ra-0019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, H, Sittig, DF. Advancing the science of measurement of diagnostic errors in healthcare: the safer Dx framework. BMJ Qual Saf 2015;24:103&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjqs-2014-003675 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2014-003675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiff, GD, Hasan, O, Kim, S, Abrams, R, Cosby, K, Lambert, BL, et al.. Diagnostic error in medicine: analysis of 583 physician-reported errors. Arch Intern Med 2009;169:1881&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1001/archinternmed.2009.333 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2009.333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mutairi, A, Meyer, AN, Thomas, EJ, Etchegaray, JM, Roy, KM, Davalos, MC, et al.. Accuracy of the safer Dx instrument to identify diagnostic errors in primary care. J Gen Intern Med 2016;31:602&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11606-016-3601-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-016-3601-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, DR, Meyer, AN, Sittig, DF, Meeks, DW, Thomas, EJ, Singh, H. Application of electronic trigger tools to identify targets for improving diagnostic safety. BMJ Qual Saf 2019;28:151&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjqs-2018-008086 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2018-008086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Classen, DC, Resar, R, Griffin, F, Federico, F, Frankel, T, Kimmel, N, et al.. &#x2018;Global trigger tool&#x2019; shows that adverse events in hospitals may be ten times greater than previously measured. Health Aff (Millwood) 2011;30:581&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1377/hlthaff.2011.0190 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.2011.0190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, DR, Wu, L, Thomas, EJ, Forjuoh, SN, Meyer, AN, Singh, H. Electronic trigger-based intervention to reduce delays in diagnostic evaluation for cancer: a cluster randomized controlled trial. J Clin Oncol 2015;33:3560&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2015.61.1301 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2015.61.1301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, DR, Meyer, AND, Vaghani, V, Russo, E, Sittig, DF, Wei, L, et al.. Development and validation of trigger algorithms to identify delays in diagnostic evaluation of gastroenterological cancer. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2018;16:90&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cgh.2017.08.007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2017.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhise, V, Modi, V, Kalavar, A, Espadas, D, Hanser, L, Gould, M, et al.. Patient-reported attributions for missed colonoscopy appointments in two large healthcare systems. Dig Dis Sci 2016;61:1853&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10620-016-4096-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-016-4096-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer, AND, Murphy, DR, Al-Mutairi, A, Sittig, DF, Wei, L, Russo, E, et al.. Electronic detection of delayed test result Follow-Up in patients with hypothyroidism. J Gen Intern Med 2017;32:753&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11606-017-3988-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-017-3988-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson, APJ, Graber, ML, Singh, H. Tracking progress in improving diagnosis: a framework for defining undesirable diagnostic events. J Gen Intern Med 2018;33:1187&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11606-018-4304-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-018-4304-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyer, N, Prior, TS, Bendstrup, E, Shaker, SB. Diagnostic delay in IPF impacts progression-free survival, quality of life and hospitalisation rates. BMJ Open Respir Res 2022;9:e001276. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjresp-2022-001276 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjresp-2022-001276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamas, DJ, Kawut, SM, Bagiella, E, Philip, N, Arcasoy, SM, Lederer, DJ. Delayed access and survival in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: a cohort study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2011;184:842&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1164/rccm.201104-0668oc .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201104-0668oc</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiello, M, Bertorelli, G, Bocchino, M, Chetta, A, Fiore-Donati, A, Fois, A, et al.. The earlier, the better: impact of early diagnosis on clinical outcome in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Pulm Pharmacol Ther 2017;44:7&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pupt.2017.02.005 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pupt.2017.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove, GP, Bianchi, P, Danese, S, Lederer, DJ. Barriers to timely diagnosis of interstitial lung disease in the real world: the INTENSITY survey. BMC Pulm Med 2018;18:9. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12890-017-0560-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-017-0560-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyer, N, Prior, TS, Bendstrup, E, Wilcke, T, Shaker, SB. Risk factors for diagnostic delay in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respir Res 2019;20:103. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12931-019-1076-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-019-1076-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritchard, D, Adegunsoye, A, Lafond, E, Pugashetti, JV, DiGeronimo, R, Boctor, N, et al.. Diagnostic test interpretation and referral delay in patients with interstitial lung disease. Respir Res 2019;20:253. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12931-019-1228-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-019-1228-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onishchenko, D, Marlowe, RJ, Ngufor, CG, Faust, LJ, Limper, AH, Hunninghake, GM, et al.. Screening for idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis using comorbidity signatures in electronic health records. Nat Med 2022;28:2107&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-02010-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-02010-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egashira, R, Nishino, M. Quantitative texture analysis of interstitial lung abnormalities opens a new chapter for chest CT interpretation. Radiology 2023;307:e230469. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.230469 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.230469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiff, GD, Volodarskaya, M, Ruan, E, Lim, A, Wright, A, Singh, H, et al.. Characteristics of disease-specific and generic diagnostic pitfalls: a qualitative study. JAMA Netw Open 2022;5:e2144531. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.44531 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.44531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivers, E, Nguyen, B, Havstad, S, Ressler, J, Muzzin, A, Knoblich, B, et al.. Early goal-directed therapy in the treatment of severe sepsis and septic shock. N Engl J Med 2001;345:1368&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa010307 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejmoa010307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chartan, C, Singh, H, Krishnamurthy, P, Sur, M, Meyer, A, Lutfi, R, et al.. Isolating red flags to enhance diagnosis (I-RED): an experimental vignette study. Int J Qual Health Care 2019;31:G97&#x2013;102. https://doi.org/10.1093/intqhc/mzz082 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzz082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubio-Tapia, A, Hill, ID, Semrad, C, Kelly, CP, Greer, KB, Limketkai, BN, et al.. American college of gastroenterology guidelines update: diagnosis and management of celiac disease. Am J Gastroenterol 2023;118:59&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.14309/ajg.0000000000002075 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000002075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaul, B, Lee, JS, Zhang, N, Vittinghoff, E, Sarmiento, K, Collard, HR, et al.. Epidemiology of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis among U.S. veterans, 2010&#x2013;2019. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2022;19:196&#x2013;203. https://doi.org/10.1513/annalsats.202103-295oc .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/annalsats.202103-295oc</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijsenbeek, M, Cottin, V. Spectrum of fibrotic lung diseases. N Engl J Med 2020;383:958&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmra2005230 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejmra2005230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>As-Sanie, S, Mackenzie, SC, Morrison, L, Schrepf, A, Zondervan, KT, Horne, AW, et al.. Endometriosis: a review. JAMA 2025;334:64&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2025.2975 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2025.2975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, JL. Understanding the impact of delayed diagnosis and misdiagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). J Fam Med Prim Care 2024;13:4819&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc-1177-24 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc-1177-24</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz, FJ, Beauchamp-Perez, F, Manni, A, Chung, T, Goldenberg, D, Goyal, N. Analysis of time to diagnosis and outcomes among adults with primary hyperparathyroidism. JAMA Netw Open 2022;5:e2248332. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.48332 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.48332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwers, FP, de Boer, RA, van der Harst, P, Voors, AA, Gansevoort, RT, Bakker, SJ, et al.. Incidence and epidemiology of new onset heart failure with preserved vs. reduced ejection fraction in a community-based cohort: 11-Year follow-up of PREVEND. Eur Heart J 2013;34:1424&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/eht066 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/eht066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni, S, Macklin, EA, Lee, A, Murphy, A, Chang, J, Zipf, A, et al.. Diagnostic timelines and delays in diagnosing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2014;15:453&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2014.903974 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2014.903974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>