<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41504517</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1948-965X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of nursing research : JNR</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Nurs Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Postoperative Consequences of Fear and Anxiety in Open Heart Surgery: A Comparative Analysis of Two Patient Groups.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/jnr.0000000000000721</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patients undergoing open heart surgery may experience negative emotions such as anxiety, fear, panic, and anger in the preoperative period that may negatively affect their postoperative recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study was designed to compare the effects of preoperative fear and anxiety on postoperative pain and complications in a referral group and on a non-referral group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This descriptive study was conducted at a cardiovascular surgery hospital in Turkey from July 1, 2020, to December 31, 2020, on 96 patient participants. The referral group (n = 48) comprised patients who were diagnosed in another hospital and received cardiovascular surgery at our hospital, while the non-referral group (n = 48) comprised patients who received their angiography and cardiovascular surgery in our hospital. A Personal Information Form, Surgical Fear Questionnaire, and the Beck Anxiety Inventory were administered to all of the participants in the preoperative period. In the postoperative period, pain levels were determined using the Visual Analog Scale, and complications were recorded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">No statistically significant difference were found in the overall occurrence of complications between the two groups (p &gt; .05). However, those in the referral group who developed lung-related complications exhibited significantly higher levels of surgical fear (p &lt; .05). No statistically significant differences were observed between the groups in terms of length of stay in the intensive care unit, length of intubation, length of mobilization, length of hospitalization, pain levels, or mean anxiety and surgical fear scores (p &gt; .05). A significantly positive relationship was observed between anxiety and surgical fear levels in both groups (p &lt; .05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS/IMPLICATIONS FOR PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results indicate neither the timing of surgical treatment decision nor preoperative fear and anxiety are associated with postoperative pain and certain complications. However, a significant relationship was detected between preoperative anxiety and surgical fear. No relationship between the way patients are taken to surgery and levels of anxiety and surgical fear or postoperative complications was found. The literature should be further expanded by conducting different studies on this subject.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the Taiwan Nurses Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dizdar</LastName><ForeName>Ebru</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6216-3505</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Operating Theatre and Training Unit, Ahi Evren Chest, Heart and Vascular Surgery Training and Research Hospital, Trabzon, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kili&#xe7;</LastName><ForeName>A&#x15f;kin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Surgery Clinic, Samsun University Faculty of Medicine, Samsun, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alkan Kayhan</LastName><ForeName>Semiha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Operating Theatre and Training Unit, Ahi Evren Chest, Heart and Vascular Surgery Training and Research Hospital, Trabzon, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;ilingir</LastName><ForeName>Dilek</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Disease Nursing, Faculty of Health Science, Karadeniz Technical University, Trabzon, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babul Turhan</LastName><ForeName>&#x15e;eyda</ForeName><Initials>&#x15e;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic and Physical Therapy, Yavuz Selim Bone Diseases and Rehabilitation Hospital, Trabzon, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China (Republic : 1949- )</Country><MedlineTA>J Nurs Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101128757</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1682-3141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fear</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient care</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41504517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/jnr.0000000000000721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00134372-990000000-00181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abate S. M., Chekol Y. A., Basu B. 2020. Global prevalence and determinants of preoperative anxiety among surgical patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. International Journal of Surgery Open, 25, 6&#x2013;16. http://creativecommons.org/licenses/bync-nd/4.0/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arslan Isik N., Emir I. 2022. The effect of preoperative anxiety on postoperative symptoms in patients without a history of anxiety scheduled for coronary artery bypass grafting. Galician Medical Journal, 29(3), Article E202237. https://doi.org/10.21802/gmj.2022.3.7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21802/gmj.2022.3.7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avci M. G. 1995. Validity and reliability study of Beck Anxiety Scale [Unpublished master&#x2019;s thesis]. Faculty of Health Sciences, Ege University, &#x130;zmir. (Original work published in Turkish)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x11f;digen M., Karaman &#xd6;zl&#xfc; Z. 2018. Validation of the Turkish version of the Surgical Fear Questionnaire. Journal of PeriAnesthesia Nursing, 33(5), 708&#x2013;714. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jopan.2017.05.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jopan.2017.05.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck A. T., Epstein N., Brown G., Steer R. A. 1988. An inventory for measuring clinical anxiety: Psychometric properties. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 56, 893&#x2013;897. https://doi.org/10.1037//0022-006x.56.6.893</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0022-006x.56.6.893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhe Y. W., Melkie T. B., Lema G. F., Getnet M., Chekol W. B. 2022. The overlooked problem among surgical patients: Preoperative anxiety at Ethiopian University Hospital. Frontiers in Medicine, 9, Article 912743. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2022.912743</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.912743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsook D., George E., Kussman B., Becerra L. 2010. Anesthesia and perioperative stress: Consequences on neural networks and postoperative behaviors. Progress in Neurobiology, 92(4), 601&#x2013;612. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2010.08.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pneurobio.2010.08.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiarotto A., Maxwell L. J., Ostelo R. W., Boers M., Tugwell P., Terwee C. B. 2019. Measurement properties of Visual Analogue Scale, Numeric Rating Scale, and Pain Severity Subscale of the Brief Pain Inventory in patients with low back pain: A systematic review. The Journal of Pain, 20(3), 245&#x2013;263. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpain.2018.07.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpain.2018.07.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Findik &#xdc;. Y., Yildizeli Top&#xe7;u S. 2012. Effect of the way of surgery on preoperative anxiety. Hacettepe University Faculty of Health Sciences Nursing Journal, 19(2), 22&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Q., Mok H. P., Zhang H. Y., Qiu H. L., Liu J., Chen Z. R., Tenh Y., Li X. H., Cen Z. J., Chen J. M., Zhuang J. 2021. Inflammatory indicator levels in patients undergoing aortic valve replacement via median sternotomy with preoperative anxiety and postoperative complications: A prospective cohort study. Journal of International Medical Research, 49(2), Article 300060520977417. https://doi.org/10.1177/0300060520977417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0300060520977417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glare P., Aubrey K. R., Myles P. S. 2019. Transition from acute to chronic pain after surgery. The Lancet, 393(10180), 1537&#x2013;1546. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(19)30352-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(19)30352-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawker G. A., Mian S., Kendzerska T., French M. 2011. Measures of adult pain: Visual Analog Scale for Pain (VAS Pain), Numeric Rating Scale for Pain (NRS Pain), McGill Pain Questionnaire (MPQ), Short-Form McGill Pain Questionnaire Chiarotto et al (SF-MPQ), Chronic Pain Grade Scale (CPGS), Short Form-36 Bodily Pain Scale (SF-36 BPS), and Measure of Intermittent and Constant Osteoarthritis Pain (ICOAP). Arthritis Care and Research, 63(11), 240&#x2013;252. https://doi.org/10.1002/acr.20543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.20543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Palaz&#xf3;n J., Fuentes-Garc&#xed;a D., Falc&#xf3;n-Ara&#xf1;a L., Roca-Calvo M. J., Burguillos-L&#xf3;pez S., Dom&#xe9;nech-Asensi P., Jara-Rubio R. 2018. Assessment of preoperative anxiety in cardiac surgery patients lacking a history of anxiety: Contributing factors and postoperative morbidity. Journal of Cardiothoracic and Vascular Anesthesia, 32(1), 236&#x2013;244. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.jvca.2017.04.044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jvca.2017.04.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashif M., Hamid M., Raza A. 2022. Influence of preoperative anxiety level on postoperative pain after cardiac surgery. Cureus, 14(2), Article e22170. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.22170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.22170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalili N., Karvandian K., Ardebili H. E., Eftekhar N., Nabavian O. 2019. Predictive factors of preoperative anxiety in the anesthesia clinic: A survey of 231 surgical candidates. Archives of Anesthesiology and Critical Care, 5, 21&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.18502/aacc.v5i4.1452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/aacc.v5i4.1452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudgalkar N., Kandi V., Baviskar A., Kasturi R., Bandurapalli B. 2022. Preoperative anxiety among cardiac surgery patients and its impact on major adverse cardiac events and mortality&#x2014;A randomized, parallel-group study. Annals of Cardiac Anaesthesia, 25(3), 293&#x2013;296. https://doi.org/10.4103/aca.aca_80_21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/aca.aca_80_21</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulugeta H., Ayana M., Sintayehu M., Dessie G., Zewtu D. 2018. Preoperative anxiety and associated factors among adult surgical patients in Debre Markos and Felege Hiwot referral hospitals, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Anesthesiology, 18(1), Article 155. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871-018-0619-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12871-018-0619-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peker K., Polat R. 2021. The effects of preoperative reactions of emotional distress on headache and acute low back pain after spinal anesthesia: A prospective study. Journal of Psychosomatic Research, 144, Article 110416. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110416</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh C., Nayak B. S., Pai V. B., George A., George L. S., Devi E. S. 2017. Pre-operative anxiety in patients undergoing coronary artery bypass graft surgery&#x2014;A cross-sectional study. International Journal of Africa Nursing Sciences, 7, 31&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijans.2017.06.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijans.2017.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reisli R., Akkaya &#xd6;. T., Arican &#x15e;., Can &#xd6;. S., &#xc7;eting&#xf6;k H., G&#xfc;le&#xe7; M. S., Talu G. K. 2021. Pharmacological treatment of acute postoperative pain: Turkish Algology-Pain Society clinical practice guideline. Pain, 33(1), 1&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.14744/agri.2021.60243 (Original work published in Turkish)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14744/agri.2021.60243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riecke J., Zerth S. F., Schubert A-K., Wiesmann T., Dinges H. C., Wulf H., Volberg C. 2023. Risk factors and protective factors of acute postoperative pain: An observational study at a German university hospital with cross-sectional and longitudinal inpatient data. BMJ Open, 13, Article e069977. https://doi.org/10.1136/ bmjopen-2022-069977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-069977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues H. F., Furuya R. K., Dantas R. A. S., Morelato R. D. C., Dessotte C. A. M. 2020. Relationship between emotional states before cardiac valve surgeries with postoperative complications. Revista Ga&#xfa;cha Enfermagem, 41, Article e20190025. https://doi.org/10.1590/1983-1447.2020.20190025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1983-1447.2020.20190025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabine F., Stefanie R., Patrick M., Peter K. 2022. Preoperative anxiety. Current Opinion in Anaesthesiology, 35(6), 674&#x2013;678. https://doi.org/10.1097/ACO.0000000000001186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACO.0000000000001186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salzmann S., Salzmann-Djufri M., Wilhelm M., Euteneuer F. 2020. Psychological preparation for cardiac surgery. Current Cardiology Reports, 22(12), Article No. 172. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11886-020-01424-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11886-020-01424-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sameed M., Choi H., Auron M., Mireles-Cabodevila E. 2021. Preoperative pulmonary risk assessment. Respiratory Care, 66(7), 1150&#x2013;1166. https://doi.org/10.4187/respcare.09154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.09154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamenkovic D. M., Rancic N. K., Latas M. B., Neskovic V., Rondovic G. R., Wu J. D., Cattano D. 2018. Preoperative anxiety and implications on postoperative recovery: What can we do to change our history. Minerva Anestesiologica, 84(11), 1307&#x2013;1317. https://doi.org/10.23736/S0375-9393.18.12520-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0375-9393.18.12520-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse M., Ahmed S., Regassa T., Girma T., Hailu S., Mohammed A., Mohammed S. 2022. Effect of preoperative anxiety on postoperative pain on patients undergoing elective surgery: Prospective cohort study. Annals of Medicine and Surgery, 73, Article 103190. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amsu.2021.103190</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amsu.2021.103190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theunissen M., Peters M., Schouten E., Fiddelers A. A. A., Willemsen M. G. A., Pinto P. R., Gramke H. F., Marcus M. E. 2014. Validation of the surgical fear questionnaire in adult patients waiting for elective surgery. PLOS One, 9, 6&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0100225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0100225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wondmieneh A. 2020. Preoperative anxiety and associated factors among adult elective surgery patients in North Wollo Zone, Northeast Ethiopia. Open Access Journal of Surgery, 13, 85&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.2147/OAS.S285562</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OAS.S285562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaman &#xd6;., Aygin D. 2022. Relationship between patients&#x2019; anxiety levels before open heart surgery with postoperative symptoms. Journal of Sakarya University Holistic Health, 5(3), 251&#x2013;261. https://doi.org/10.54803/sauhsd.1103950 (Original work published in Turkish)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54803/sauhsd.1103950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41503935</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2191-0286</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of basic and clinical physiology and pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Basic Clin Physiol Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A study of pulmonary function in hypothyroid female patients of reproductive age group and its correlation with free T3, T4 and TSH.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/jbcpp-2024-0169</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Hypothyroidism is common among females of reproductive age group. The prevalence is 10.95&#x202f;% of which 3.47&#x202f;% are unaware of the condition and its effect on lung function. To study the pulmonary function among hypothyroid females of reproductive age group and to identify the respiratory disease pattern and also to correlate free T3, T4 and TSH Levels with pulmonary function test parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a case control study, comprised of 156 participants divided into two groups (n<sub>1</sub> and n<sub>2</sub>). Group 1 consisted of normal healthy female controls and group 2 consisted of hypothyroid female patients of age group 18-45&#x202f;years. After recording anthropometric variables, vital signs and BMI, spirometry was performed and following parameters, FVC, FEV1, FEV1/FVC, PEF, PIF and FEF<sub>25-75&#x202f;%</sub> were assessed and analyzed. Statistical analysis and correlation was&#xa0;done.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Hypothyroid patients showed a statistically significant decline in FEV1, FEV1/FVC%. Rho and Pearson's correlation showed a positive correlation between free T4 and FEV1, FEV1/FVC%, PIF, FEF<sub>25-75&#x202f;%</sub>, with FEF<sub>25-75&#x202f;%</sub> statistically significant. TSH showed a negative correlation with FVC, PEF and PIF with PEF statistically significant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study shows that patients with hypothyroidism are more prone to develop obstructive pattern of lung disease, with a decline in small airway and large airway function.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Walter de Gruyter GmbH, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sivakumar</LastName><ForeName>Sunandhinidevi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Dr. MGR Educational and Research Institute, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramakumar Latha</LastName><ForeName>Bhavya</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, ESIC Medical College and Hospital, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayyavoo</LastName><ForeName>Saravanan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, SRM Medical College Hospital and Research Center, Kattankulathur, Kancheepuram Dist., Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanagaraj</LastName><ForeName>Thamarai Selvi</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, SRM Medical College Hospital and Research Center, Kattankulathur, Kancheepuram Dist., Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krishnan</LastName><ForeName>Prabhavathi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, SRM Medical College Hospital and Research Center, Kattankulathur, Kancheepuram Dist., Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prem Sundar</LastName><ForeName>Kalyani Praba</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Melmaruvathur Adhiparasakthi Institute of Medical Sciences &amp; Research, Melmaruvathur, Chengalpattu District, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Basic Clin Physiol Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9101750</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0792-6855</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glycose amine glycans</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypothyroid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary function test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spirometry</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41503935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jbcpp-2024-0169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jbcpp-2024-0169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Unnikrishnan, AG, Kalra, S, Sahay, RK, Bantwal, G, John, M, Tewari, N. Prevalence of hypothyroidism in adults: an epidemiological study in eight cities of India. Indian J Endocrinol Metab 2013;17:647&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.4103/2230-8210.113755 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2230-8210.113755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krassas, GE. Thyroid disease and female reproduction. Fertil Steril 2000;74:1063&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0015-0282(00)01589-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0015-0282(00)01589-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln, R, Ke, RW, Kutteh, WH. Screening for hypothyroidism in infertile women. J&#xa0;Reprod Med 1999;44:455&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siafakas, NM, Salesiotou, V, Filaditaki, V, Tzanakis, N, Thalassinos, N, Bouros, D. Respiratory muscle strength in hypothyroidism. Chest 1992;102:189&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1378/chest.102.1.189 . PMID: 1623751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.102.1.189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosi, SKY, Kaur, J, Garla, VV. Subclinical hypothyroidism. In: StatPearls [Internet] . Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2024. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK536970 [Accessed 15 Feb 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dashe, JS, Cunningham, FG. Subclinical hypothyroidism. N&#xa0;Engl J Med 2001;345:1855. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM200112203452517 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM200112203452517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kek, PC, Ho, SC, Khoo, DH. Subclinical thyroid disease. Singap Med J 2003;44:595&#x2013;600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, JF, Peng, L, Hu, CM, Wu, TN. Impaired learning and memory performance in a subclinical hypothyroidism rat model induced by hemi-thyroid electrocauterization. J&#xa0;Neuroendocrinol 2012;24:953&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2826.2012.02297.x . PMID: 22324892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2826.2012.02297.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivaranjani, H, Chaitra, KR. The study of pulmonary function tests in patients with hypothyroidism. Int J Adv Med 2019. https://doi.org/10.18203/2349-3933.ijam20195225 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18203/2349-3933.ijam20195225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh, M, Sinha, B, Biswas, MK. Comparative study of pulmonary function by spirometric parameters between clinical and subclinical hypothyroidism patients in a tertiary health care institute catering village population. Int J Acad Med Pharm 2023;5:340&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman, R, Sasisekharan, V, Sasisekharan, R. Structural insights into biological roles of protein-glycosaminoglycan interactions. Chem Biol 2005;12:267&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chembiol.2004.11.020 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chembiol.2004.11.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, N, Hu, M, Khalil, RA. Biochemical and biological attributes of matrix metalloproteinases. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci 2017;147:1&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.pmbts.2017.02.005 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.pmbts.2017.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, TJ, Murata, Y, Horwitz, AL, Philipson, L, Refetoff, S. Regulation of glycosaminoglycan synthesis by thyroid hormone in&#xa0;vitro. J&#xa0;Clin Investig 1982;70:1066&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci110694 . PMID: 6813355; PMCID: PMC370319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci110694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterling, K. Thyroid hormone action at the cell level (second of two parts). N&#xa0;Engl J Med 1979;300:173&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejm197901253000405 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejm197901253000405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roel, S, Punyabati, O, Prasad, L, Salam, R, Ningshen, K, Shimray, AJ, et al.. Assessment of functional lung impairment in hypothyroidism. IOSR J Dent Med Sci 2014;13:4&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.9790/0853-13980407 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9790/0853-13980407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41499501</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Control of airway basal stem cell-mediated lung repair by TGF-&#x3b2; signaling.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eadz1519</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eadz1519</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eadz1519</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.adz1519</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Airway basal stem cells (BCs) are recognized as resident stem cells responsible for reconstituting epithelial barriers and differentiating into multiple epithelial cell types following severe lung injury. However, the mechanism that the injured lung microenvironment uses to modulate BC-mediated lung repair remains unclear. Here, we showed that the profibrotic transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; (TGF-&#x3b2;) gradient from the injured lung immune microenvironment can be sensed by BCs. Targeted degradation of Smad2/3 in human BCs via proteolysis targeting chimera (PROTAC) disrupted TGF-&#x3b2; signaling, causing cell hyperplasia and barrier function loss after being transplanted into the alveolar area. Genetic ablation of the TGF-&#x3b2; receptor or <i>Smad4</i> in mouse BCs impaired multilineage differentiation and suppressed migration to the alveolar injury site. These data indicated that TGF-&#x3b2; signaling is essential for BC-mediated lung repair. Moreover, we genetically engineered human BCs to release antifibrotic bone morphogenetic protein 7 (BMP7) in response to microenvironmental TGF-&#x3b2; stimulation. Transplantation of this iBMP7-BC enhanced lung repair and reduced fibrosis. Collectively, this study delineates how TGF-&#x3b2; governs BC behavior and provides a microenvironment-responsive cell therapeutic strategy for pulmonary fibrosis.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zou</LastName><ForeName>Tingting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-0897-3167</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Cardiology and Medical Innovation Center, Shanghai East Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Stem Cell Center, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shiyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-6306-8728</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Cardiology and Medical Innovation Center, Shanghai East Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Stem Cell Center, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Mingzhe</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-7577-4142</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Cardiology and Medical Innovation Center, Shanghai East Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Stem Cell Center, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Qiaoyu</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Cardiology and Medical Innovation Center, Shanghai East Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Stem Cell Center, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Siyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Cardiology and Medical Innovation Center, Shanghai East Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Stem Cell Center, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Lingyun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Cardiology and Medical Innovation Center, Shanghai East Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Stem Cell Center, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ye-Guang</ForeName><Initials>YG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6701-0065</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The MOE Basic Research and Innovation Center for the Targeted Therapeutics of Solid Tumors, Jiangxi Medical College, Nanchang University, Nanchang, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-2427-2476</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kiangnan Institute of Stem Cell, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Super Organ R&amp;D Center, Regend Therapeutics, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4460-0337</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Regenerative Medicine, State Key Laboratory of Cardiology and Medical Innovation Center, Shanghai East Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Stem Cell Center, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kiangnan Institute of Stem Cell, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Super Organ R&amp;D Center, Regend Therapeutics, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016212">Transforming Growth Factor beta</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D055419">Bone Morphogenetic Protein 7</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="Y">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016212" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transforming Growth Factor beta</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013234" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stem Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055419" MajorTopicYN="N">Bone Morphogenetic Protein 7</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002454" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Differentiation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Injury</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011658" MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Fibrosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41499501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adz1519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12778057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Raghu G., Remy-Jardin M., Richeldi L., Thomson C. C., Inoue Y., Johkoh T., Kreuter M., Lynch D. A., Maher T. M., Martinez F. J., Molina-Molina M., Myers J. L., Nicholson A. G., Ryerson C. J., Strek M. E., Troy L. K., Wijsenbeek M., Mammen M. J., Hossain T., Bissell B. D., Herman D. D., Hon S. M., Kheir F., Khor Y. H., Macrea M., Antoniou K. M., Bouros D., Buendia-Roldan I., Caro F., Crestani B., Ho L., Morisset J., Olson A. L., Podolanczuk A., Poletti V., Selman M., Ewing T., Jones S., Knight S. L., Ghazipura M., Wilson K. C., Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (an update) and progressive pulmonary fibrosis in adults: An official ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT clinical practice guideline. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 205, e18&#x2013;e47 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9851481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35486072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu G., Rochwerg B., Zhang Y., Garcia C. A., Azuma A., Behr J., Brozek J. L., Collard H. R., Cunningham W., Homma S., Johkoh T., Martinez F. J., Myers J., Protzko S. L., Richeldi L., Rind D., Selman M., Theodore A., Wells A. U., Hoogsteden H., Schunemann H. J., American Thoracic Society, European Respiratory Society, Japanese Respiratory Society, Latin American Thoracic Association , An official ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT clinical practice guideline: Treatment of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. An update of the 2011 clinical practice guideline. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 192, e3-19 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26177183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spagnolo P., Kropski J. A., Jones M. G., Lee J. S., Rossi G., Karampitsakos T., Maher T. M., Tzouvelekis A., Ryerson C. J., Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: Disease mechanisms and drug development. Pharmacol. Ther. 222, 107798 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8142468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alysandratos K. D., Herriges M. J., Kotton D. N., Epithelial stem and progenitor cells in lung repair and regeneration. Annu. Rev. Physiol. 83, 529&#x2013;550 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33074772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basil M. C., Katzen J., Engler A. E., Guo M., Herriges M. J., Kathiriya J. J., Windmueller R., Ysasi A. B., Zacharias W. J., Chapman H. A., Kotton D. N., Rock J. R., Snoeck H. W., Vunjak-Novakovic G., Whitsett J. A., Morrisey E. E., The cellular and physiological basis for lung repair and regeneration: Past, present, and future. Cell Stem Cell 26, 482&#x2013;502 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32243808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q., Ma Y., Dai X., Ren T., Fu Y., Liu W., Han Y., Wu Y., Cheng Y., Zhang T., Zuo W., 
Regeneration of functional alveoli by adult human SOX9<sup>+</sup> airway basal cell transplantation. Protein Cell
9, 
267&#x2013;282 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5829276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29344809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Dong M., Zhou Y., Li W., Gao Y., Han L., Chen M., Lin H., Zuo W., Jin F., Distal airway stem cells ameliorate bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis in mice. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 10, 161 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6547529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31159891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Zhao Y., Li D., Feng Y., Xie Y., Zhou Y., Zhou M., Wang Y., Qu J., Zuo W., Intrapulmonary distal airway stem cell transplantation repairs lung injury in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Cell Prolif. 54, e13046 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8168420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33960563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Meng Z., Liu M., Zhou Y., Chen D., Zhao Y., Zhang T., Zhong N., Dai X., Li S., Zuo W., 
Autologous transplantation of P63<sup>+</sup> lung progenitor cells for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease therapy. Sci. Transl. Med.
16, 
eadi3360 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38354225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J., Zhang W., Feng Y., Liu X., Niu L., Guo Y., Zhou L., Shi M., Di C., Zhang Q., Wang X., Zhou J., Dai R., Ni L., Bao Z., Yan T., Hu Y., Wang P., Zhang T., Zhou M., Zuo W., Qu J., 
Autologous transplantation of P63<sup>+</sup> lung progenitor cells in patients with bronchiectasis: A randomized, single-blind, controlled trial. Cell Rep. Med.
5, 
101819 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11604513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39566467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Zhou M., Shao C., Zhao Y., Liu M., Ni L., Bao Z., Zhang Q., Zhang T., Luo Q., Qu J., Xu Z., Zuo W., 
Autologous P63<sup>+</sup> lung progenitor cell transplantation in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: A phase 1 clinical trial. eLife
13, 
eadi3360 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11879106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40036154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Zhou Y., Zhang W., Liu M., Duan J., Zhang X., Ma Q., Wang Y., Zhang Y., Guo Z., Zhang T., Zuo W., Cloned airway basal progenitor cells to repair fibrotic lung through re-epithelialization. Nat. Commun. 16, 1303 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11790844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39900892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniely Y., Liao G., Dixon D., Linnoila R. I., Lori A., Randell S. H., Oren M., Jetten A. M., Critical role of p63 in the development of a normal esophageal and tracheobronchial epithelium. Am. J. Physiol. Cell Physiol. 287, C171&#x2013;C181 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15189821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boers J. E., Ambergen A. W., Thunnissen F. B., Number and proliferation of basal and parabasal cells in normal human airway epithelium. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 157, 2000&#x2013;2006 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9620938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rock J. R., Onaitis M. W., Rawlins E. L., Lu Y., Clark C. P., Xue Y., Randell S. H., Hogan B. L., Basal cells as stem cells of the mouse trachea and human airway epithelium. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 106, 12771&#x2013;12775 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoro D. T., Haber A. L., Biton M., Vinarsky V., Lin B., Birket S. E., Yuan F., Chen S., Leung H. M., Villoria J., Rogel N., Burgin G., Tsankov A. M., Waghray A., Slyper M., Waldman J., Nguyen L., Dionne D., Rozenblatt-Rosen O., Tata P. R., Mou H., Shivaraju M., Bihler H., Mense M., Tearney G. J., Rowe S. M., Engelhardt J. F., Regev A., Rajagopal J., A revised airway epithelial hierarchy includes CFTR-expressing ionocytes. Nature 560, 319&#x2013;324 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6295155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30069044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plantier L., Crestani B., Wert S. E., Dehoux M., Zweytick B., Guenther A., Whitsett J. A., Ectopic respiratory epithelial cell differentiation in bronchiolised distal airspaces in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Thorax 66, 651&#x2013;657 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21422041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smirnova N. F., Schamberger A. C., Nayakanti S., Hatz R., Behr J., Eickelberg O., Detection and quantification of epithelial progenitor cell populations in human healthy and IPF lungs. Respir. Res. 17, 83 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4947297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsdottir H. R., Arason A. J., Palsson R., Franzdottir S. R., Gudbjartsson T., Isaksson H. J., Gudmundsson G., Gudjonsson T., Magnusson M. K., Basal cells of the human airways acquire mesenchymal traits in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis and in culture. Lab. Invest. 95, 1418&#x2013;1428 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26390052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swatek A. M., Lynch T. J., Crooke A. K., Anderson P. J., Tyler S. R., Brooks L., Ivanovic M., Klesney-Tait J. A., Eberlein M., Pena T., Meyerholz D. K., Engelhardt J. F., Parekh K. R., 
Depletion of airway submucosal glands and TP63<sup>+</sup>KRT5<sup>+</sup> basal cells in obliterative bronchiolitis. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med.
197, 
1045&#x2013;1057 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5909161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29236513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rustam S., Hu Y., Mahjour S. B., Rendeiro A. F., Ravichandran H., Urso A., D&#x2019;Ovidio F., Martinez F. J., Altorki N. K., Richmond B., Polosukhin V., Kropski J. A., Blackwell T. S., Randell S. H., Elemento O., Shaykhiev R., A unique cellular organization of human distal airways and its disarray in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 207, 1171&#x2013;1182 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10161760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36796082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt R. J., Puttur F., Gaboriau D. C. A., Fercoq F., Fresquet M., Traves W. J., Yates L. L., Walker S. A., Molyneaux P. L., Kemp S. V., Nicholson A. G., Rice A., Roberts E., Lennon R., Carlin L. M., Byrne A. J., Maher T. M., Lloyd C. M., 
Lung extracellular matrix modulates KRT5<sup>+</sup> basal cell activity in pulmonary fibrosis. Nat. Commun.
14, 
6039 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10533905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37758700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng X. M., Nikolic-Paterson D. J., Lan H. Y., TGF-&#x3b2;: The master regulator of fibrosis. Nat. Rev. Nephrol. 12, 325&#x2013;338 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27108839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broekelmann T. J., Limper A. H., Colby T. V., McDonald J. A., Transforming growth factor beta 1 is present at sites of extracellular matrix gene expression in human pulmonary fibrosis. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 88, 6642&#x2013;6646 (1991).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC52144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1862087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil N., O&#x2019;Connor R. N., Unruh H. W., Warren P. W., Flanders K. C., Kemp A., Bereznay O. H., Greenberg A. H., Increased production and immunohistochemical localization of transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Am. J. Respir. Cell Mol. Biol. 5, 155&#x2013;162 (1991).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1892646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartram U., Speer C. P., The role of transforming growth factor &#x3b2; in lung development and disease. Chest 125, 754&#x2013;765 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanda D., Otoupalova E., Smith S. R., Volckaert T., De Langhe S. P., Thannickal V. J., Developmental pathways in the pathogenesis of lung fibrosis. Mol. Aspects Med. 65, 56&#x2013;69 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6374163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30130563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao J., Meng X. M., Huang X. R., Chung A. C., Feng Y. L., Hui D. S., Yu C. M., Sung J. J., Lan H. Y., miR-29 inhibits bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis in mice. Mol. Ther. 20, 1251&#x2013;1260 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3369297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22395530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter N. J., Pirfenidone: In idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Drugs 71, 1721&#x2013;1732 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21902295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horan G. S., Wood S., Ona V., Li D. J., Lukashev M. E., Weinreb P. H., Simon K. J., Hahm K., Allaire N. E., Rinaldi N. J., Goyal J., Feghali-Bostwick C. A., Matteson E. L., O&#x2019;Hara C., Lafyatis R., Davis G. S., Huang X., Sheppard D., Violette S. M., Partial inhibition of integrin &#x3b1;v&#x3b2;6 prevents pulmonary fibrosis without exacerbating inflammation. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 177, 56&#x2013;65 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17916809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puthawala K., Hadjiangelis N., Jacoby S. C., Bayongan E., Zhao Z., Yang Z., Devitt M. L., Horan G. S., Weinreb P. H., Lukashev M. E., Violette S. M., Grant K. S., Colarossi C., Formenti S. C., Munger J. S., Inhibition of integrin &#x3b1;v&#x3b2;6, an activator of latent transforming growth factor-&#x3b2;, prevents radiation-induced lung fibrosis. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 177, 82&#x2013;90 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2176115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17916808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao M., Guan Z., Zhang Z., Ai H., Peng X., Zhou H., Xu J., Gu Q., Atractylodinol prevents pulmonary fibrosis through inhibiting TGF-&#x3b2; receptor 1 recycling by stabilizing vimentin. Mol. Ther. 31, 3015&#x2013;3033 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10556230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37641404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H., Liu X., Zhang M., Bera H., Xu W., Jiang H., Zhao X., Wu L., Cun D., Yang M., Pulmonary fibroblast-specific delivery of siRNA exploiting exosomes-based nanoscaffolds for IPF treatment. Asian J. Pharm. Sci. 19, 100929 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11385781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39258001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Wang X. F., Wang Z. C., Lou D., Fang Q. Q., Hu Y. Y., Zhao W. Y., Zhang L. Y., Wu L. H., Tan W. Q., Current potential therapeutic strategies targeting the TGF-&#x3b2;/Smad signaling pathway to attenuate keloid and hypertrophic scar formation. Biomed. Pharmacother. 129, 110287 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32540643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiyokawa H., Yamaoka A., Matsuoka C., Tokuhara T., Abe T., Morimoto M., Airway basal stem cells reutilize the embryonic proliferation regulator, Tgf&#x3b2;-Id2 axis, for tissue regeneration. Dev. Cell 56, 1917&#x2013;1929.e9 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34129836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mou H., Vinarsky V., Tata P. R., Brazauskas K., Choi S. H., Crooke A. K., Zhang B., Solomon G. M., Turner B., Bihler H., Harrington J., Lapey A., Channick C., Keyes C., Freund A., Artandi S., Mense M., Rowe S., Engelhardt J. F., Hsu Y. C., Rajagopal J., Dual SMAD signaling inhibition enables long-term expansion of diverse epithelial basal cells. Cell Stem Cell 19, 217&#x2013;231 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4975684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27320041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaway D. A., Penkala I. J., Zhou S., Knowlton J. J., Cardenas-Diaz F., Babu A., Morley M. P., Lopes M., Garcia B. A., Morrisey E. E., TGF-&#x3b2; controls alveolar type 1 epithelial cell plasticity and alveolar matrisome gene transcription in mice. J. Clin. Invest. 134, e172095 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10947970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38488000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman M. B., Wood M., Lapey A., Mou H., SMAD signaling restricts mucous cell differentiation in human airway epithelium. Am. J. Respir. Cell Mol. Biol. 61, 322&#x2013;331 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6839926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30848657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil N., O&#x2019;Connor R. N., Flanders K. C., Shing W., Whitman C. I., Regulation of type II alveolar epithelial cell proliferation by TGF-&#x3b2; during bleomycin-induced lung injury in rats. Am. J. Physiol. 267, L498&#x2013;L507 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7526703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enomoto Y., Katsura H., Fujimura T., Ogata A., Baba S., Yamaoka A., Kihara M., Abe T., Nishimura O., Kadota M., Hazama D., Tanaka Y., Maniwa Y., Nagano T., Morimoto M., Autocrine TGF-&#x3b2;-positive feedback in profibrotic AT2-lineage cells plays a crucial role in non-inflammatory lung fibrogenesis. Nat. Commun. 14, 4956 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10471635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37653024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsukui T., Wolters P. J., Sheppard D., Alveolar fibroblast lineage orchestrates lung inflammation and fibrosis. Nature 631, 627&#x2013;634 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12088911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38987592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsukazaki T., Chiang T. A., Davison A. F., Attisano L., Wrana J. L., SARA, a FYVE domain protein that recruits Smad2 to the TGF&#x3b2; receptor. Cell 95, 779&#x2013;791 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9865696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G., Chen Y. G., Ozdamar B., Gyuricza C. A., Chong P. A., Wrana J. L., Massague J., Shi Y., Structural basis of Smad2 recognition by the Smad anchor for receptor activation. Science 287, 92&#x2013;97 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10615055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai A. C., Crews C. M., Induced protein degradation: An emerging drug discovery paradigm. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 16, 101&#x2013;114 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5684876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27885283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton D. C., Helms M. N., Koval M., Bao H. F., Jain L., The contribution of epithelial sodium channels to alveolar function in health and disease. Annu. Rev. Physiol. 71, 403&#x2013;423 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18831683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K. J., Malik A. B., Protein transport across the lung epithelial barrier. Am. J. Physiol. Lung Cell. Mol. Physiol. 284, L247&#x2013;L259 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta D., Bhattacharya J., Matthay M. A., Malik A. B., Integrated control of lung fluid balance. Am. J. Physiol. Lung Cell. Mol. Physiol. 287, L1081&#x2013;L1090 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15531757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell L. A., Overgaard C. E., Ward C., Margulies S. S., Koval M., Differential effects of claudin-3 and claudin-4 on alveolar epithelial barrier function. Am. J. Physiol. Lung Cell. Mol. Physiol. 301, L40&#x2013;L49 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3129905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21515662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito A., Horie M., Nagase T., TGF-&#x3b2; signaling in lung health and disease. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 19, 2460 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6121238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30127261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhurst R. J., Hata A., Targeting the TGF&#x3b2; signalling pathway in disease. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 11, 790&#x2013;811 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3520610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23000686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonn P., Moren A., Raja E., Dahl M., Moustakas A., Regulating the stability of TGF&#x3b2; receptors and Smads. Cell Res. 19, 21&#x2013;35 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19030025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derynck R., Zhang Y. E., Smad-dependent and Smad-independent pathways in TGF-&#x3b2; family signalling. Nature 425, 577&#x2013;584 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14534577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadokoro T., Gao X., Hong C. C., Hotten D., Hogan B. L., BMP signaling and cellular dynamics during regeneration of airway epithelium from basal progenitors. Development 143, 764&#x2013;773 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4813333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26811382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan A. E., Brumwell A. N., Xi Y., Gotts J. E., Brownfield D. G., Treutlein B., Tan K., Tan V., Liu F. C., Looney M. R., Matthay M. A., Rock J. R., Chapman H. A., Lineage-negative progenitors mobilize to regenerate lung epithelium after major injury. Nature 517, 621&#x2013;625 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25533958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo W., Zhang T., Wu D. Z., Guan S. P., Liew A. A., Yamamoto Y., Wang X., Lim S. J., Vincent M., Lessard M., Crum C. P., Xian W., McKeon F., 
p63<sup>+</sup>Krt5<sup>+</sup> distal airway stem cells are essential for lung regeneration. Nature
517, 
616&#x2013;620 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25383540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi Y., Kim T., Brumwell A. N., Driver I. H., Wei Y., Tan V., Jackson J. R., Xu J., Lee D. K., Gotts J. E., Matthay M. A., Shannon J. M., Chapman H. A., Vaughan A. E., Local lung hypoxia determines epithelial fate decisions during alveolar regeneration. Nat. Cell Biol. 19, 904&#x2013;914 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5600325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28737769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv Z., Liu Z., Liu K., Lin X., Pu W., Li Y., Zhao H., Xi Y., Sui P., Vaughan A. E., Gillich A., Zhou B., 
Alveolar regeneration by airway secretory-cell-derived p63<sup>+</sup> progenitors. Cell Stem Cell
31, 
1685&#x2013;1700.e6 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39232560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger B., Schupp J. C., Plappert L., Terwolbeck O., Artysh N., Kayser G., Engelhard P., Adams T. S., Zweigerdt R., Kempf H., Lienenklaus S., Garrels W., Nazarenko I., Jonigk D., Wygrecka M., Klatt D., Schambach A., Kaminski N., Prasse A., 
Airway basal cells show a dedifferentiated KRT17<sup>high</sup>Phenotype and promote fibrosis in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Nat. Commun.
13, 
5637 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9513076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36163190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeisberg E. M., Tarnavski O., Zeisberg M., Dorfman A. L., McMullen J. R., Gustafsson E., Chandraker A., Yuan X., Pu W. T., Roberts A. B., Neilson E. G., Sayegh M. H., Izumo S., Kalluri R., Endothelial-to-mesenchymal transition contributes to cardiac fibrosis. Nat. Med. 13, 952&#x2013;961 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17660828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu D., Sun Z., Wei J., Zhang Y., An W., Lin Y., Li X., BMP7-loaded human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cell-derived small extracellular vesicles ameliorate liver fibrosis by targeting activated hepatic stellate cells. Int. J. Nanomedicine 19, 3475&#x2013;3495 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11018131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38623080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y., Wang Y., Zhou Z., Pan C., Jiang L., Zhou Z., Meng Y., Charugundla S., Li T., Allayee H., Seldin M. M., Lusis A. J., Liver-heart cross-talk mediated by coagulation factor XI protects against heart failure. Science 377, 1399&#x2013;1406 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9639660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinoshita K., Iimuro Y., Otogawa K., Saika S., Inagaki Y., Nakajima Y., Kawada N., Fujimoto J., Friedman S. L., Ikeda K., Adenovirus-mediated expression of BMP-7 suppresses the development of liver fibrosis in rats. Gut 56, 706&#x2013;714 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1942155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17127702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midgley A. C., Wei Y., Zhu D., Gao F., Yan H., Khalique A., Luo W., Jiang H., Liu X., Guo J., Zhang C., Feng G., Wang K., Bai X., Ning W., Yang C., Zhao Q., Kong D., Multifunctional natural polymer nanoparticles as antifibrotic gene carriers for CKD therapy. J. Am. Soc. Nephrol. 31, 2292&#x2013;2311 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32769144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selman M., King T. E., Pardo A., American Thoracic Society, European Respiratory Society, American College of Chest Physicians , Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: Prevailing and evolving hypotheses about its pathogenesis and implications for therapy. Ann. Intern. Med. 134, 136&#x2013;151 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11177318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner L., Single A. B., Bhongir R. K. V., Heusel M., Mohanty T., Karlsson C. A. Q., Pan L., Clausson C. M., Bergwik J., Wang K., Andersson C. K., Oommen R. M., Erjefalt J. S., Malmstrom J., Wallner O., Boldogh I., Helleday T., Kalderen C., Egesten A., Small-molecule-mediated OGG1 inhibition attenuates pulmonary inflammation and lung fibrosis in a murine lung fibrosis model. Nat. Commun. 14, 643 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9902543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36746968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolters P. J., Collard H. R., Jones K. D., Pathogenesis of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Annu. Rev. Pathol. 9, 157&#x2013;179 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4116429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24050627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding H., Chen J., Qin J., Chen R., Yi Z., TGF-&#x3b2;-induced alpha-SMA expression is mediated by C/EBP&#x3b2; acetylation in human alveolar epithelial cells. Mol. Med. 27, 22 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7934236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33663392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M., Zhang X., Lin Y., Zeng Y., Roles of airway basal stem cells in lung homeostasis and regenerative medicine. Respir. Res. 23, 122 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9102684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35562719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volckaert T., Yuan T., Yuan J., Boateng E., Hopkins S., Zhang J. S., Thannickal V. J., Fassler R., De Langhe S. P., Hippo signaling promotes lung epithelial lineage commitment by curbing Fgf10 and &#x3b2;-catenin signaling. Development 146, dev166454 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30651296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas M., Gomez Vazquez J. L., Sun D. I., Tran H. T., Brislinger M., Tasca A., Shomroni O., Vleminckx K., Walentek P., DeltaN-Tp63 mediates Wnt/&#x3b2;-catenin-induced inhibition of differentiation in basal stem cells of mucociliary epithelia. Cell Rep. 28, 3338&#x2013;3352.e6 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6935018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31553905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori M., Mahoney J. E., Stupnikov M. R., Paez-Cortez J. R., Szymaniak A. D., Varelas X., Herrick D. B., Schwob J., Zhang H., Cardoso W. V., Notch3-Jagged signaling controls the pool of undifferentiated airway progenitors. Development 142, 258&#x2013;267 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4302835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25564622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange A. W., Sridharan A., Xu Y., Stripp B. R., Perl A. K., Whitsett J. A., Hippo/Yap signaling controls epithelial progenitor cell proliferation and differentiation in the embryonic and adult lung. J. Mol. Cell Biol. 7, 35&#x2013;47 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4400400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25480985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsao P. N., Vasconcelos M., Izvolsky K. I., Qian J., Lu J., Cardoso W. V., Notch signaling controls the balance of ciliated and secretory cell fates in developing airways. Development 136, 2297&#x2013;2307 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2729343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19502490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss D. J., Kolls J. K., Ortiz L. A., Panoskaltsis-Mortari A., Prockop D. J., Stem cells and cell therapies in lung biology and lung diseases. Proc. Am. Thorac. Soc. 5, 637&#x2013;667 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2645238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18625757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan C. Y., Wong J. X., Chan P. S., Tan H., Liao D., Chen W., Tan L. W., Ackers-Johnson M., Wakimoto H., Seidman J. G., Seidman C. E., Lunde I. G., Zhu F., Hu Q., Bian J., Wang J. W., Foo R. S., Jiang J., Yin Yang 1 suppresses dilated cardiomyopathy and cardiac fibrosis through regulation of Bmp7 and Ctgf. Circ. Res. 125, 834&#x2013;846 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7336364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31495264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang D., Wang Y., Zhu Z., Yang G., An G., Li X., Niu P., Chen L., Tian L., BMP-7 attenuated silica-induced pulmonary fibrosis through modulation of the balance between TGF-&#x3b2;/Smad and BMP-7/Smad signaling pathway. Chem. Biol. Interact. 243, 72&#x2013;81 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26585589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao W., Niroula S., Wang S., Vincent M., McKeon F., Xian W., Protocol for cloning epithelial stem cell variants from human lung. STAR Protoc. 1, 100063 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7529324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Li L., Zheng Y., Xue F., Yu M., Ma Y., Dong L., Shan Z., Feng D., Wang T., Wang X., Schistosoma japonicum peptide SJMHE1 suppresses airway inflammation of allergic asthma in mice. J. Cell. Mol. Med. 23, 7819&#x2013;7829 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31496071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L., Dong L., Li H., Liu Z., Luo Z., Duan G., Dai X., Lin Z., Ubiquitination-mediated degradation of SIRT1 by SMURF2 suppresses CRC cell proliferation and tumorigenesis. Oncogene 39, 4450&#x2013;4464 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32361710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao H., Li X., Zhao L., Wang Y., Wang X., Wu Y., Zhou X., Fu W., Liu L., Hu H. G., Chen Y. G., A PROTAC peptide induces durable beta-catenin degradation and suppresses Wnt-dependent intestinal cancer. Cell Discov. 6, 35 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7280531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32550000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller A. J., Hill D. R., Nagy M. S., Aoki Y., Dye B. R., Chin A. M., Huang S., Zhu F., White E. S., Lama V., Spence J. R., In vitro induction and in vivo engraftment of lung bud tip progenitor cells derived from human pluripotent stem cells. Stem Cell Rep. 10, 101&#x2013;119 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5770275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29249664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence J. R., Lange A. W., Lin S. C., Kaestner K. H., Lowy A. M., Kim I., Whitsett J. A., Wells J. M., Sox17 regulates organ lineage segregation of ventral foregut progenitor cells. Dev. Cell 17, 62&#x2013;74 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2734336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19619492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y. Q., An X. L., Jin F. Y., Bai Y. F., Li T., Yang X. Y., Liu S. P., Gao X. M., Mao N., Xu H., Cai W. C., Yang F., ISRIB inhibits the senescence of type II pulmonary epithelial cells to alleviate pulmonary fibrosis induced by silica in mice. Ecotoxicol. Environ. Saf. 264, 115410 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37647802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A., Liao S., Cheng M., Ma K., Wu L., Lai Y., Qiu X., Yang J., Xu J., Hao S., Wang X., Lu H., Chen X., Liu X., Huang X., Li Z., Hong Y., Jiang Y., Peng J., Liu S., Shen M., Liu C., Li Q., Yuan Y., Wei X., Zheng H., Feng W., Wang Z., Liu Y., Wang Z., Yang Y., Xiang H., Han L., Qin B., Guo P., Lai G., Munoz-Canoves P., Maxwell P. H., Thiery J. P., Wu Q. F., Zhao F., Chen B., Li M., Dai X., Wang S., Kuang H., Hui J., Wang L., Fei J. F., Wang O., Wei X., Lu H., Wang B., Liu S., Gu Y., Ni M., Zhang W., Mu F., Yin Y., Yang H., Lisby M., Cornall R. J., Mulder J., Uhlen M., Esteban M. A., Li Y., Liu L., Xu X., Wang J., Spatiotemporal transcriptomic atlas of mouse organogenesis using DNA nanoball-patterned arrays. Cell 185, 1777&#x2013;1792.e21 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35512705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobin A., Davis C. A., Schlesinger F., Drenkow J., Zaleski C., Jha S., Batut P., Chaisson M., Gingeras T. R., STAR: Ultrafast universal RNA-seq aligner. Bioinformatics 29, 15&#x2013;21 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3530905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>