<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41645520</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6971</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in pulmonary medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Improving lung cancer screening diagnostic efficiency.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCP.0000000000001250</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We discuss opportunities to improve lung cancer screening (LCS) diagnostic efficiency, which necessitates simultaneous focus on both diagnosis of early-stage lung cancer and reduction of diagnostic errors during diagnostic evaluation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Recent efforts have focused on three distinct targets for improving LCS diagnostic efficiency: Eligibility and uptake, Adherence to annual screening, and Diagnostic evaluation of concerning findings. There has been ongoing debate regarding who should be screened and how to consider lung cancer risk factors, even as LCS uptake remains suboptimal. LCS annual adherence has emerged as an important quality metric, as it is associated with increased early-stage lung cancer detection. Finally, optimization of the diagnostic pathway once concerning findings are identified via LCS is necessary to minimize exposing those without cancer to the harms of invasive diagnostic testing. Efforts to improve pulmonary nodule risk assessment, the nonmalignant resection rate, and lung cancer overdiagnosis will be crucial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Improving LCS diagnostic efficiency requires a careful balance between prioritizing lung cancer sensitivity (i.e., ability to diagnose early-stage lung cancers) and avoiding both false negatives (i.e., failure to diagnose an early-stage lung cancer) and false positives (i.e., unnecessary performance of invasive testing for benign lesions).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caruso</LastName><ForeName>Christopher R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary, Allergy, and Critical Care, Department of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Penn Center for Cancer Care Innovation, Abramson Cancer Center, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Roger Y</ForeName><Initials>RY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary, Allergy, and Critical Care, Department of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Penn Center for Cancer Care Innovation, Abramson Cancer Center, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pulm Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9503765</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1070-5287</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health services research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung cancer screening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41645520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCP.0000000000001250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00063198-990000000-00304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agha L, Skinner J, Chan D. Improving efficiency in medical diagnosis. JAMA 2022; 327:2189&#x2013;2190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Lung Screening Trial Research T, Aberle DR, Adams AM, Berg CD, et al. Reduced lung-cancer mortality with low-dose computed tomographic screening. N Engl J Med 2011; 365:395&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Koning HJ, van der Aalst CM, de Jong PA, et al. Reduced lung-cancer mortality with volume CT screening in a randomized trial. N Engl J Med 2020; 382:503&#x2013;513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzone PJ, White CS, Kazerooni EA, et al. Proposed quality metrics for lung cancer screening programs: a National Lung Cancer Roundtable Project. Chest 2021; 160:368&#x2013;378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzone PJ, Silvestri GA, Souter LH, et al. Screening for lung cancer: CHEST Guideline and Expert Panel Report. Chest 2021; 160:e427&#x2013;e494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barta JA, Arenberg D, Backhus L, et al. Components necessary for high-quality lung cancer screening: a 10-year update. Chest 2025; 168:1257&#x2013;1270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Force USPST, Krist AH, Davidson KW, Mangione CM, et al. Screening for lung cancer: US Preventive Services Task Force Recommendation Statement. JAMA 2021; 325:962&#x2013;970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldrich MC, Mercaldo SF, Sandler KL, et al. Evaluation of USPSTF Lung Cancer Screening Guidelines Among African American Adult Smokers. JAMA Oncol 2019; 5:1318&#x2013;1324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonas DE, Reuland DS, Reddy SM, et al. Screening for lung cancer with low-dose computed tomography: updated evidence report and systematic review for the US Preventive Services Task Force. JAMA 2021; 325:971&#x2013;987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katki HA, Kovalchik SA, Berg CD, et al. Development and validation of risk models to select ever-smokers for CT lung cancer screening. JAMA 2016; 315:2300&#x2013;2311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X, Goodley P, Alcala K, et al. Evaluation of risk prediction models to select lung cancer screening participants in Europe: a prospective cohort consortium analysis. Lancet Digit Health 2024; 6:e614&#x2013;e624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tammemagi MC, Katki HA, Hocking WG, et al. Selection criteria for lung-cancer screening. N Engl J Med 2013; 368:728&#x2013;736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu CY, Lusk CM, Neslund-Dudas C, et al. Comparison between the 2021 USPSTF Lung Cancer Screening Criteria and other lung cancer screening criteria for racial disparity in eligibility. JAMA Oncol 2022; 8:374&#x2013;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tammemagi MC, Ruparel M, Tremblay A, et al. USPSTF2013 versus PLCOm2012 lung cancer screening eligibility criteria (International Lung Screening Trial): interim analysis of a prospective cohort study. Lancet Oncol 2022; 23:138&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. Standard protocol prepared for the Targeted Lung Health Checks Programme. URL: NHS England &#xbb; Standard protocol and quality assurance standards for the Lung Cancer Screening Programme. [Accessed 14 May 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Government. Report on the Lung Cancer Screening Enquiry. URL: https://www.canceraustralia.gov.au/publications-and-resources/cancer-australia-publications/report-lung-cancer-screening-enquiry. [Accessed 14 May 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Haaf K, Bastani M, Cao P, et al. A comparative modeling analysis of risk-based lung cancer screening strategies. J Natl Cancer Inst 2020; 112:466&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung LC, Berg CD, Castle PE, et al. Life-gained-based versus risk-based selection of smokers for lung cancer screening. Ann Intern Med 2019; 171:623&#x2013;632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel N, Miller DP Jr, Snavely AC, et al. A comparison of smoking history in the electronic health record with self-report. Am J Prev Med 2020; 58:591&#x2013;595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter AL, Xu NN, Senthil P, et al. Pack-year smoking history: an inadequate and biased measure to determine lung cancer screening eligibility. J Clin Oncol 2024; 42:2026&#x2013;2037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landy R, Cheung LC, Young CD, et al. Absolute lung cancer risk increases among individuals with &gt;15 quit-years: analyses to inform the update of the American Cancer Society lung cancer screening guidelines. Cancer 2024; 130:201&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Cancer Society. Lung Cancer Screening Guidelines. URL:Lung Cancer Screening Guidelines | American Cancer Society. [Accessed 14 May 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvestri GA, Young RP, Tanner NT, Mazzone P. Screening low-risk individuals for lung cancer: the need may be present, but the evidence of benefit is not. J Thorac Oncol 2024; 19:1155&#x2013;1163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson LM, Su IH, Rivera MP, et al. Prevalence of lung cancer screening in the US, 2022. JAMA Netw Open 2024; 7:e243190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jemal A, Fedewa SA. Lung cancer screening with low-dose computed tomography in the United States-2010 to 2015. JAMA Oncol 2017; 3:1278&#x2013;1281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedewa SA, Kazerooni EA, Studts JL, et al. State variation in low-dose CT scanning for lung cancer screening in the United States. J Natl Cancer Inst 2021; 113:1044&#x2013;1052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnett-Hartman AN, Carroll NM, Croswell JM, et al. Percentage up to date with chest computed tomography among those eligible for lung cancer screening. Am J Prev Med 2023; 65:126&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neslund-Dudas C, Tang A, Alleman E, et al. Uptake of lung cancer screening CT after a provider order for screening in the PROSPR-Lung Consortium. J Gen Intern Med 2024; 39:186&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezenwankwo E, Yell N, Eberth JM. Lung cancer screening in the United States 2024 a National Health Interview Survey Analysis. Chest 2025; S0012-3692:05818-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolle LD, Olazagasti C, Lopes G, et al. USPSTF Lung Cancer Screening Guidelines and Disparities in Screening Adherence. JAMA Oncol 2025; 11:784&#x2013;786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukhareva PV, Caverly TJ, Li H, et al. Inaccuracies in electronic health records smoking data and a potential approach to address resulting underestimation in determining lung cancer screening eligibility. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2022; 29:779&#x2013;788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modin HE, Fathi JT, Gilbert CR, et al. Pack-year cigarette smoking history for determination of lung cancer screening eligibility. Comparison of the electronic medical record versus a shared decision-making conversation. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2017; 14:1320&#x2013;1325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson E, Harris K, Farjah F, et al. Improving smoking history documentation in the electronic health record for lung cancer risk assessment and screening in primary care: a case study. Healthc (Amst) 2021; 9:100578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rendle KA, Steltz JP, Cohen S, et al. Estimating pack-year eligibility for lung cancer screening using 2 yes or no questions. JAMA Netw Open 2023; 6:e2327363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnett-Hartman AN, Powers JD, Hixon BP, et al. Development of an electronic health record-based algorithm for predicting lung cancer screening eligibility in the population-based research to optimize the screening process Lung Research Consortium. JCO Clin Cancer Inform 2023; 7:e2300063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen J, Prosper AE, Wu CC, et al. ACR Lung-RADS v2022: assessment categories and management recommendations. J Am Coll Radiol 2024; 21:473&#x2013;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim RY, Rendle KA, Mitra N, et al. Adherence to annual lung cancer screening and rates of cancer diagnosis. JAMA Netw Open 2025; 8:e250942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Olivo MA, Maki KG, Choi NJ, et al. Patient adherence to screening for lung cancer in the US: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open 2020; 3:e2025102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Fu M, Ding R, et al. Patient adherence to lung CT screening reporting &amp; data system-recommended screening intervals in the United States: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Thorac Oncol 2022; 17:38&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvestri GA, Goldman L, Tanner NT, et al. Outcomes from more than 1 million people screened for lung cancer with low-dose CT imaging. Chest 2023; 164:241&#x2013;251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim RY, Rendle KA, Mitra N, et al. Racial disparities in adherence to annual lung cancer screening and recommended follow-up care: a multicenter cohort study. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2022; 19:1561&#x2013;1569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezenwankwo E, Jones C, Nguyen DT, Eberth JM. Lung cancer screening adherence in centralized versus decentralized screening programs a meta-analysis of U.S. cohort studies among individuals with negative baseline results. Chest 2025; 168:797&#x2013;809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunez ER, Triplette M. Addressing lung cancer screening disparities: what does it mean to be centralized? Ann Am Thorac Soc 2022; 19:1457&#x2013;1458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunitomo Y, Bade B, Gunderson CG, et al. Racial differences in adherence to lung cancer screening follow-up: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Chest 2021; 161:266&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lake M, Shusted CS, Juon HS, et al. Black patients referred to a lung cancer screening program experience lower rates of screening and longer time to follow-up. BMC Cancer 2020; 20:561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapoor S, Deppen SA, Paulson AB, et al. Education level predicts appropriate follow-up of incidental findings from lung cancer screening. J Am Coll Radiol 2020; 17:613&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tailor TD, Tong BC, Gao J, et al. A geospatial analysis of factors affecting access to CT facilities: implications for lung cancer screening. J Am Coll Radiol 2019; 16:1663&#x2013;1668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin D, Fishman MDC, Ngo M, et al. The impact of social determinants of health on lung cancer screening utilization. J Am Coll Radiol 2022; 19:122&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim RY, Rendle KA, Mitra N, et al. Socioeconomic status as a mediator of racial disparity in annual lung cancer screening adherence. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2023; 207:777&#x2013;780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner NT, Brasher PB, Wojciechowski B, et al. Screening adherence in the Veterans Administration Lung Cancer Screening Demonstration Project. Chest 2020; 158:1742&#x2013;1752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakoda LC, Henderson LM, Rivera MP. Adherence to lung cancer screening: what exactly are we talking about? Ann Am Thorac Soc 2021; 18:1951&#x2013;1952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakoda LC, Rivera MP, Zhang J, et al. Patterns and factors associated with adherence to lung cancer screening in diverse practice settings. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4:e218559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunez ER, Caverly TJ, Zhang S, et al. Adherence to follow-up testing recommendations in US Veterans Screened for Lung Cancer, 2015-2019. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4:e2116233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triplette M, Thayer JH, Kross EK, et al. The impact of smoking and screening results on adherence to follow-up in an academic multisite lung cancer screening program. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2020; 18:545&#x2013;547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith-Bindman R, Miglioretti DL, Johnson E, et al. Use of diagnostic imaging studies and associated radiation exposure for patients enrolled in large integrated healthcare systems, 1996&#x2013;2010. JAMA 2012; 307:2400&#x2013;2409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith-Bindman R, Chu PW, Azman Firdaus H, et al. Projected lifetime cancer risks from current computed tomography imaging. JAMA Intern Med 2025; 185:710&#x2013;719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson LM, Durham DD, Long J, et al. Communication of positive lung cancer screening findings and receipt of recommended follow-up care. JAMA Netw Open 2023; 6:e2320409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkmen CP, Dako F, Moore R, et al. Adherence to annual lung cancer screening with low-dose CT scan in a diverse population. Cancer Causes Control 2021; 32:291&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzone PJ, Lam L. Evaluating the patient with a pulmonary nodule: a review. JAMA 2022; 327:264&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould MK, Donington J, Lynch WR, et al. Evaluation of individuals with pulmonary nodules: when is it lung cancer? Diagnosis and management of lung cancer, 3rd ed: American College of Chest Physicians evidence-based clinical practice guidelines. Chest 2013; 143:e93S&#x2013;e120S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ost DE, Gould MK. Decision making in patients with pulmonary nodules. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2012; 185:363&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi HK, Ghobrial M, Mazzone PJ. Models to estimate the probability of malignancy in patients with pulmonary nodules. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2018; 15:1117&#x2013;1126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balekian AA, Silvestri GA, Simkovich SM, et al. Accuracy of clinicians and models for estimating the probability that a pulmonary nodule is malignant. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2013; 10:629&#x2013;635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner NT, Porter A, Gould MK, et al. Physician assessment of pretest probability of malignancy and adherence with guidelines for pulmonary nodule evaluation. Chest 2017; 152:263&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paez R, Kammer MN, Tanner NT, et al. Update on biomarkers for the stratification of indeterminate pulmonary nodules. Chest 2023; 164:1028&#x2013;1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim RY, Sears CR, Pastis NJ. POINT: liquid markers for risk stratification of pulmonary nodules, ready for prime time? Yes!. CHEST Pulmon 2024; 2:100071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim RY. Radiomics and artificial intelligence for risk stratification of pulmonary nodules: ready for primetime? Cancer Biomark 2025; 42:CBM230360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of a Radiomics-based Computer-Aided Diagnosis Tool for Pulmonary nodulES (ARCADES). ClinicalTrials.gov. URL: https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05968898. [Accessed 4 March 2024].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biomarker Platform (Virtual Nodule Clinic) for the Management of Indeterminate Pulmonary Nodules. ClinicalTrials.gov. URL: https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT06638398. [Accessed 2 June 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodify XL2 Classifier Clinical Utility Study in Low to Moderate Risk Lung Nodules (ALTITUDE). ClinicalTrials.gov. URL: https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04171492. [Accessed 20 February 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Utility of Management of Patients With Pulmonary Nodules Using the Percepta Nasal Swab Classifier (NIGHTINGALE). ClinicalTrials.gov. URL: https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT06426628. [Accessed 2 June 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Kim AW, Hsin M, et al. The 2023 American Association for Thoracic Surgery (AATS) Expert Consensus Document: management of subsolid lung nodules. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg 2024; 168:631&#x2013;647. e611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera MP, Mehta AC, Wahidi MM. Establishing the diagnosis of lung cancer: diagnosis and management of lung cancer, 3rd ed: American College of Chest Physicians evidence-based clinical practice guidelines. Chest 2013; 143:e142S&#x2013;e165S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacMahon H, Naidich DP, Goo JM, et al. Guidelines for management of incidental pulmonary nodules detected on CT images: from the Fleischner Society. Radiology 2017; 284:228&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Comprehensive Cancer Network. NCCN Guidelines Version 2.2026 Nonsmall Cell Lung Cancer. National Comprehensive Cancer Network; 2026. URL: https://www.nccn.org/professionals/physician_gls/pdf/nscl.pdf. [Accessed 9 December 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lentz RJ, Frederick-Dyer K, Planz VB, et al. Navigational bronchoscopy or transthoracic needle biopsy for lung nodules. N Engl J Med 2025; 392:2100&#x2013;2112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaddha U, Agrawal A, Ghori U, et al. Safety and sample adequacy for comprehensive biomarker testing of bronchoscopic biopsies: an American Association of Bronchology and Interventional Pulmonology (AABIP) and International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer (IASLC) Clinical Practice Guideline. J Thorac Oncol 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navani N, Nankivell M, Lawrence DR, et al. Lung cancer diagnosis and staging with endobronchial ultrasound-guided transbronchial needle aspiration compared with conventional approaches: an open-label, pragmatic, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respir Med 2015; 3:282&#x2013;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskin AS, Velotta JB. ASO Author Reflections: preoperative mediastinal lymph node staging for nonsmall cell lung cancer: where do we go from here? Ann Surg Oncol 2025; 32:3187&#x2013;3188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guinde J, Bourdages-Pageau E, Collin-Castonguay MM, et al. Endobronchial ultrasound for staging of the radiologically normal mediastinum: should we individualize our approach? Ann Am Thorac Soc 2020; 17:1493&#x2013;1496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan KA, Farrokhyar F, Patel YS, et al. Preoperative mediastinal staging in early-stage lung cancer: targeted nodal sampling is not inferior to systematic nodal sampling. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg 2024; 168:391&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forde PM, Spicer J, Lu S, et al. Neoadjuvant nivolumab plus chemotherapy in resectable lung cancer. N Engl J Med 2022; 386:1973&#x2013;1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuboi M, Weder W, Escriu C, et al. Neoadjuvant osimertinib with/without chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone for EGFR-mutated resectable nonsmall-cell lung cancer: NeoADAURA. Future Oncol 2021; 17:4045&#x2013;4055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altorki NK, Wang X, Wigle D, et al. Perioperative mortality and morbidity after sublobar versus lobar resection for early-stage nonsmall-cell lung cancer: posthoc analysis of an international, randomised, phase 3 trial (CALGB/Alliance 140503). Lancet Respir Med 2018; 6:915&#x2013;924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo E, Bharat A, Bontumasi N, et al. Impact of video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery on benign resections for solitary pulmonary nodules. Ann Thorac Surg 2012; 93:266&#x2013;272. discussion 272&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhamani A, Creamer A, Verghese P, et al. Low-dose CT for lung cancer screening in a high-risk population (SUMMIT): a prospective, longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Oncol 2025; 26:609&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso CR, Vachani A, Kim RY. Monitoring the harms of lung cancer screening: why the nonmalignant resection rate is our best bet. J Am Coll Radiol 2025; 22:1569&#x2013;1571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer JM, Mendoza DP, Hung YP, et al. Surgical resection of benign nodules in lung cancer screening: incidence and features. JTO Clin Res Rep 2023; 4:100605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho H, Williamson C, Regis SM, et al. Surgery and invasive diagnostic procedures for benign disease are rare in a large low-dose computed tomography lung cancer screening program. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg 2021; 161:790&#x2013;802. e792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Alam R, Byrne SC, Hammer MM. Rate of benign nodule resection in a lung cancer screening program. Clin Imaging 2023; 104:109984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso CR, Kim RY, Rendle KA, Vachani A. Evaluating the nonmalignancy rate in the National Lung Screening Trial: addressing surgical misclassification. Chest 2025; 168:1271&#x2013;1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin D, Callister M, Akram A, et al. British Thoracic Society quality standards for the investigation and management of pulmonary nodules. BMJ Open Respir Res 2018; 5:e000273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodard GA, Udelsman BV, Prince SR, et al. Brief report: increasing prevalence of ground-glass nodules and semisolid lung lesions on outpatient chest computed tomography scans. JTO Clin Res Rep 2023; 4:100583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yankelevitz DF, Yip R, Smith JP, et al. CT screening for lung cancer: nonsolid nodules in baseline and annual repeat rounds. Radiology 2015; 277:555&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henschke CI, Yip R, Smith JP, et al. CT screening for lung cancer: part-solid nodules in baseline and annual repeat rounds. AJR Am J Roentgenol 2016; 207:1176&#x2013;1184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callister MEJ, Sasieni P, Robbins HA. Overdiagnosis in lung cancer screening. Lancet Respir Med 2021; 9:7&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Succony L, Rassl DM, Barker AP, et al. Adenocarcinoma spectrum lesions of the lung: detection, pathology and treatment strategies. Cancer Treat Rev 2021; 99:102237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Silvestri GA, Kim YW, et al. Screening for lung cancer, overdiagnosis, and healthcare utilization: a nationwide population-based study. J Thorac Oncol 2024; 20:577&#x2013;588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YW, Joo DH, Kim SY, et al. Gender disparities and lung cancer screening outcomes among individuals who have never smoked. JAMA Netw Open 2025; 8:e2454057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim RY. Insights into opportunistic lung cancer screening for individuals who have never smoked. JAMA Netw Open 2025; 8:e2454009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerpel-Fronius A, Tammemagi M, Cavic M, et al. Screening for lung cancer in individuals who never smoked: an International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer Early Detection and Screening Committee Report. J Thorac Oncol 2022; 17:56&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gareen IF, Gutman R, Sicks J, et al. Significant incidental findings in the National Lung Screening Trial. JAMA Intern Med 2023; 183:677&#x2013;684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen K, Schertz K, Rubin N, Begnaud A. Incidental findings in a decentralized lung cancer screening program. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2019; 16:1198&#x2013;1201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan L, Choi H, Reid M, et al. Frequency of incidental findings and subsequent evaluation in low-dose computed tomographic scans for lung cancer screening. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2017; 14:1450&#x2013;1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munden RF, Black WC, Hartman TE, et al. Managing incidental findings on thoracic CT: lung findings. A White Paper of the ACR Incidental Findings Committee. J Am Coll Radiol 2021; 18:1267&#x2013;1279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanoue LT, Sather P, Cortopassi I, et al. Standardizing the reporting of incidental, non-lung cancer (Category S) findings identified on lung cancer screening low-dose CT imaging. Chest 2022; 161:1697&#x2013;1706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson LM, Kim RY, Tanner NT, et al. Lung cancer screening and incidental findings: a research agenda: an official American Thoracic Society Research Statement. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2025; 211:436&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>