<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41695725</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2218-5836</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of orthopedics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Risk factors for thoracic-osteoporotic thoracic vertebral compression fractures during the normalized prevention and control period of COVID-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>114984</StartPage><MedlinePgn>114984</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">114984</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5312/wjo.v17.i2.114984</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Some scholars believe that there is a certain correlation between coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection and the occurrence of osteoporotic vertebral compression fractures (OVCF), but no relevant domestic research reports have been published yet. This study retrospectively analyzed the clinical data of patients admitted for OVCF and treated with percutaneous vertebroplasty during the normalized prevention and control period of COVID-19 in Shanghai (after June 1, 2022), aiming to explore the individual differences of OVCF patients during this special period and analyze the risk factors for OVCF.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore risk factors for senile OVCF during COVID-19 normalization.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Retrospective analysis of 230 OVCF patients (June 2022 to June 2023, percutaneous vertebroplasty, observation group) and 236 controls (June 2020 to June 2021, OVCF surgery). Observation group was split into nucleic acid-positive (<i>n</i> = 85) and negative (<i>n</i> = 145) subgroups. Fracture location/cause, visual analogue scale, activity scores were compared; risk factors identified.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Observation group had 42.2% thoracic fractures and 38.2% cough-induced fractures (both higher than controls, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). No significant differences in post-op visual analogue scale (1 day, 1 month) or activity scores (<i>P</i> &gt; 0.05). Nucleic acid results, fracture cause/location correlated (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05; cause-location <i>r</i> = 0.827). Logistic regression showed fracture cause, nucleic acid result, body mass index, bone mineral density as high-risk factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">During COVID-19 normalization, cough is the top OVCF cause; thoracic fractures rise. The four factors above are independent risks. For elderly COVID-positive patients with recurrent cough, lung disease treatment, anti-osteoporosis therapy, and thoracic braces prevent thoracic OVCF.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2026. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Fan</ForeName><Initials>YF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Tong Ren Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200336, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Chen-Qiong</ForeName><Initials>CQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine, Shanghai General Hospital (Shanghai First People's Hospital), Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuxi School of Medicine, Jiangnan University, Wuxi 214122, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Qi-Feng</ForeName><Initials>QF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine, Shanghai General Hospital (Shanghai First People's Hospital), Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine, Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jian-Jie</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Medicine, Ganzhou Hospital-Nanfang Hospital, Southern Medical University, Ganzhou 341000, Jiangxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiang-Yang</ForeName><Initials>XY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Tong Ren Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200336, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhi-Kun</ForeName><Initials>ZK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine, Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200080, China. lizhikun@shsmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576349</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2218-5836</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cough</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Normalized prevention and control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoporotic vertebral compression fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factor</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41695725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12898869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5312/wjo.v17.i2.114984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Drake TM, Riad AM, Fairfield CJ, Egan C, Knight SR, Pius R, Hardwick HE, Norman L, Shaw CA, McLean KA, Thompson AAR, Ho A, Swann OV, Sullivan M, Soares F, Holden KA, Merson L, Plotkin D, Sigfrid L, de Silva TI, Girvan M, Jackson C, Russell CD, Dunning J, Solomon T, Carson G, Olliaro P, Nguyen-Van-Tam JS, Turtle L, Docherty AB, Openshaw PJ, Baillie JK, Harrison EM, Semple MG ISARIC4C investigators. Characterisation of in-hospital complications associated with COVID-19 using the ISARIC WHO Clinical Characterisation Protocol UK: a prospective, multicentre cohort study. Lancet. 2021;398:223&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8285118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34274064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Lancet. China's response to COVID-19: a chance for collaboration. Lancet. 2021;397:1325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8032252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33838746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song DW, Niu JJ, Meng B, Liu T, Huang LX, Zou J, Yang HL. [Diagnosis and treatment of osteoporotic vertebral compression fracture during epidemic prevention and control of coronavirus disease 2019] Zhonghua Gu Yu Guanjie Waike Zazhi. 2020;13:183&#x2013;189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burki T. China's successful control of COVID-19. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020;20:1240&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7544475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Filippo L, Formenti AM, Doga M, Pedone E, Rovere-Querini P, Giustina A. Radiological Thoracic Vertebral Fractures are Highly Prevalent in COVID-19 and Predict Disease Outcomes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106:e602&#x2013;e614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7797741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33159451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creecy A, Awosanya OD, Harris A, Qiao X, Ozanne M, Toepp AJ, Kacena MA, McCune T. COVID-19 and Bone Loss: A Review of Risk Factors, Mechanisms, and Future Directions. Curr Osteoporos Rep. 2024;22:122&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10912142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38221578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu EW, Tsourdi E, Clarke BL, Bauer DC, Drake MT. Osteoporosis Management in the Era of COVID-19. J Bone Miner Res. 2020;35:1009&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7273005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32406536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao W, Lau HE, Xie H, Poon VK, Chan CC, Chu H, Yuan S, Yuen TT, Chik KK, Tsang JO, Chan CC, Cai JP, Luo C, Yuen KY, Cheung KM, Chan JF, Yeung KW. SARS-CoV-2 infection induces inflammatory bone loss in golden Syrian hamsters. Nat Commun. 2022;13:2539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9085785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35534483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil V, Reddy AD, Kale A, Vadlamudi A, Kishore JVS, Jani C. Incidental Identification of Vertebral Fragility Fractures by Chest CT in COVID-19-Infected Individuals. Cureus. 2022;14:e24867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9184180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35698715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma CH, Yang HL, Huang YT, Wu ZX, Cheng HC, Chou WC, Hung CH, Tsai KL. Effects of percutaneous vertebroplasty on respiratory parameters in patients with osteoporotic vertebral compression fractures. Ann Med. 2022;54:1320&#x2013;1327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9090413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35506757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Wang S, Chen C, Li Y, Ji Y, Zhu X, Li Z. Correlation analysis between the magnetic resonance imaging characteristics of osteoporotic vertebral compression fractures and the efficacy of percutaneous vertebroplasty: a prospective cohort study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2018;19:114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5898070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29650014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf N, Abou Shaar B, Taha RM, Arabi TZ, Sabbah BN, Alkodaymi MS, Omrani OA, Makhzoum T, Almahfoudh NE, Al-Hammad QA, Hejazi W, Obeidat Y, Osman N, Al-Kattan KM, Berbari EF, Tleyjeh IM. A systematic review of trials currently investigating therapeutic modalities for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome and registered on WHO International Clinical Trials Platform. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2023;29:570&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9837206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36642173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuggle NR, Singer A, Gill C, Patel A, Medeiros A, Mlotek AS, Pierroz DD, Halbout P, Harvey NC, Reginster JY, Cooper C, Greenspan SL. How has COVID-19 affected the treatment of osteoporosis? An IOF-NOF-ESCEO global survey. Osteoporos Int. 2021;32:611&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7869913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33558957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, McCorkell L, Vogel JM, Topol EJ. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2023;21:133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu SH, Dong RC, Liu Z, Liu H, Liu YT, Tang SJ. Impact of Sacroiliac Interosseous Ligament Tension and Laxity on the Biomechanics of the Lumbar Spine: A Finite Element Study. World Neurosurg. 2024;185:e431&#x2013;e441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38360209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo AJ, Liao JC, Chen LH, Lai PL. High viscosity bone cement vertebroplasty versus low viscosity bone cement vertebroplasty in the treatment of mid-high thoracic vertebral compression fractures. Spine J. 2022;22:524&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34958934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu SC, Luo AJ, Liao JC. Cement augmentation for treatment of high to mid-thoracic osteoporotic compression fractures, high-viscosity cement percutaneous vertebroplasty versus balloon kyphoplasty. Sci Rep. 2022;12:19404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9653425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36371412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maupin JJ, Steinmetz RG, Hickerson LE. A Percutaneous Threaded Wire as a Clamp Technique for Avoiding Wedge Deformity While Nailing Intertrochanteric Femur Fractures. J Orthop Trauma. 2019;33:e276&#x2013;e279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30844955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamauchi K, Adachi A, Kameyama M, Murakami M, Sato Y, Kato C, Kato T. A risk factor associated with subsequent new vertebral compression fracture after conservative therapy for patients with vertebral compression fracture: a retrospective observational study. Arch Osteoporos. 2020;15:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31897621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jian Y, Zhu D, Zhou D, Li N, Du H, Dong X, Fu X, Tao D, Han B. ARIMA model for predicting chronic kidney disease and estimating its economic burden in China. BMC Public Health. 2022;22:2456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9801144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36585665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirwan R, McCullough D, Butler T, Perez de Heredia F, Davies IG, Stewart C. Sarcopenia during COVID-19 lockdown restrictions: long-term health effects of short-term muscle loss. Geroscience. 2020;42:1547&#x2013;1578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33001410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41633605</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1671-167X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Beijing da xue xue bao. Yi xue ban = Journal of Peking University. Health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Beijing Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Clinical features and virulence gene distribution of <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> multi-site infection in patients with hospital-acquired pneumonia].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>201</StartPage><EndPage>207</EndPage><MedlinePgn>201-207</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To analyze the clinical features and virulence gene characteristics of <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> multi-site infections in patients with hospital-acquired pneumonia, as well as the risk factors for death within 30 days in patients with multi-site infections, in order to provide help for clinical anti-infective treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The case data of hospital-acquired pneumonia patients with <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> isolated in sputum culture from March 2018 to June 2023 in Peking University Third Hospital were selected for retrospective analysis, and a total of 128 consecutive patients were enrolled, of whom 35 were in the multi-site infection group and 93 were in the lung infection group, and the clinical data, strain sequence typing, and virulence-related genes of the patients in the two groups were analyzed and compared.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The differences in age, gender, proportion of the patients with length of hospital stay &#x2265;30 days, antibiotic exposure rate within 90 days and 30-day mortality rate between the two groups were statistically significant (all <i>P</i> &lt; 0.05); the differences in the proportions of combined interstitial lung disease, myocardial infarction, peripheral vascular disease, peptic ulcer, diabetes mellitus and hemiplegia between the two groups were statistically significant (all <i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). The proportions of patients with Glasgow coma scale (GCS) scores &lt; 8 points, the proportion of the patients who underwent peripherally inserted central catheter (PICC) and gastric tube invasive operation, the proportion of the presence of pleural effusion and infectious shock in the multi-site infection group were significantly higher than those of the pulmonary infection group (all <i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). The blood procalcitonin (PCT) level in the multi-site infection group was significantly higher than that of the pulmonary infection group (<i>P</i>=0.004), and the red blood cell count and hemoglobin level were significantly lower than those of the pulmonary infection group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001). The proportion of ST11 and the detection rates of virulence genes <i>iroB</i>, <i>ybtA</i>, <i>irp1</i> and <i>fyuA</i> in <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> strains in the multi-site infection group were significantly higher than those in the pulmonary infection group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). According to the occurrence of death within 30 days, the patients in the multi-site infection group were further divided into the multi-site infection survival group (<i>n</i>=21) and the non-survival group (<i>n</i>=14). Multivariate analysis showed that septic shock was an independent risk factor for death within 30 days of multi-site infection (<i>P</i>=0.045, <i>OR</i>=38.510).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> multi-site infection were mainly found in patients with advanced age, female, more comorbidities, performing invasive operation and having history of antimicrobial drug exposure within 90 days. They had lower erythrocyte counts, hemoglobin levels and higher PCT levels, and were prone to pleural effusion, infectious shock. Infectious shock was an independent risk factor for death within 30 days in patients with <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> multi-site infection. ST11 type was the most prevalent type of multi-site infectious strains, and the virulence genes <i>iroB</i>, <i>ybtA</i>, <i>irp1</i>, <i>fyuA</i> were more prevalent.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geng</LastName><ForeName>Y</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>P</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>N</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DU</LastName><ForeName>Y</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>chi</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Beijing Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101125284</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1671-167X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D037521">Virulence Factors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007711" MajorTopicYN="Y">Klebsiella pneumoniae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007710" MajorTopicYN="Y">Klebsiella Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003428" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cross Infection</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014774" MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077299" MajorTopicYN="Y">Healthcare-Associated Pneumonia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D037521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virulence Factors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="chi"><AbstractText Label="&#x76ee;&#x7684;">&#x5206;&#x6790;&#x533b;&#x9662;&#x83b7;&#x5f97;&#x6027;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;(<i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i>)&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7684;&#x4e34;&#x5e8a;&#x7279;&#x5f81;&#x548c;&#x6bd2;&#x529b;&#x57fa;&#x56e0;&#x7279;&#x5f81;, &#x4ee5;&#x53ca;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x60a3;&#x8005;30 d&#x5185;&#x6b7b;&#x4ea1;&#x7684;&#x5371;&#x9669;&#x56e0;&#x7d20;, &#x4e3a;&#x4e34;&#x5e8a;&#x6297;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x6cbb;&#x7597;&#x63d0;&#x4f9b;&#x5e2e;&#x52a9;&#x3002;</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="&#x65b9;&#x6cd5;">&#x9009;&#x62e9;&#x5317;&#x4eac;&#x5927;&#x5b66;&#x7b2c;&#x4e09;&#x533b;&#x9662;2018&#x5e74;3&#x6708;&#x81f3;2023&#x5e74;6&#x6708;&#x75f0;&#x57f9;&#x517b;&#x4e2d;&#x5206;&#x79bb;&#x51fa;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;&#x7684;&#x533b;&#x9662;&#x83b7;&#x5f97;&#x6027;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x7684;&#x75c5;&#x4f8b;&#x8d44;&#x6599;&#x8fdb;&#x884c;&#x56de;&#x987e;&#x6027;&#x5206;&#x6790;, &#x5171;&#x8fde;&#x7eed;&#x7eb3;&#x5165;&#x60a3;&#x8005;128&#x4f8b;, &#x5176;&#x4e2d;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7ec4;35&#x4f8b;, &#x5355;&#x7eaf;&#x80ba;&#x90e8;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7ec4;93&#x4f8b;, &#x5206;&#x6790;&#x5e76;&#x6bd4;&#x8f83;&#x4e24;&#x7ec4;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x7684;&#x4e34;&#x5e8a;&#x8d44;&#x6599;&#x3001;&#x83cc;&#x682a;&#x5e8f;&#x5217;&#x5206;&#x578b;&#x53ca;&#x6bd2;&#x529b;&#x76f8;&#x5173;&#x57fa;&#x56e0;&#x3002;</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="&#x7ed3;&#x679c;">&#x4e24;&#x7ec4;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x5e74;&#x9f84;&#x3001;&#x6027;&#x522b;&#x3001;&#x4f4f;&#x9662;&#x65f6;&#x957f;&#x2265;30 d&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x6bd4;&#x4f8b;&#x3001;90 d&#x5185;&#x6297;&#x83cc;&#x836f;&#x7269;&#x66b4;&#x9732;&#x7387;&#x3001;30 d&#x6b7b;&#x4ea1;&#x7387;&#x5dee;&#x5f02;&#x5747;&#x6709;&#x7edf;&#x8ba1;&#x5b66;&#x610f;&#x4e49;(<i>P</i>&#x5747;&#xff1c;0.05), &#x4e24;&#x7ec4;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x5408;&#x5e76;&#x95f4;&#x8d28;&#x6027;&#x80ba;&#x75c5;&#x3001;&#x5fc3;&#x808c;&#x6897;&#x6b7b;&#x3001;&#x5468;&#x56f4;&#x8840;&#x7ba1;&#x75c5;&#x3001;&#x6d88;&#x5316;&#x6027;&#x6e83;&#x75a1;&#x3001;&#x7cd6;&#x5c3f;&#x75c5;&#x3001;&#x504f;&#x762b;&#x6bd4;&#x4f8b;&#x5dee;&#x5f02;&#x4ea6;&#x6709;&#x7edf;&#x8ba1;&#x5b66;&#x610f;&#x4e49;(<i>P</i>&#x5747;&#xff1c;0.05)&#x3002;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7ec4;&#x683c;&#x62c9;&#x65af;&#x54e5;&#x660f;&#x8ff7;&#x8bc4;&#x5206;(Glasgow coma scale, GCS)&#xff1c;8&#x5206;&#x3001;&#x884c;&#x5916;&#x5468;&#x9759;&#x8109;&#x7f6e;&#x5165;&#x4e2d;&#x5fc3;&#x9759;&#x8109;&#x5bfc;&#x7ba1;(peripherally inserted central catheter, PICC)&#x53ca;&#x80c3;&#x7ba1;&#x4fb5;&#x5165;&#x64cd;&#x4f5c;&#x3001;&#x51fa;&#x73b0;&#x80f8;&#x8154;&#x79ef;&#x6db2;&#x548c;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x6027;&#x4f11;&#x514b;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x6bd4;&#x4f8b;&#x5747;&#x663e;&#x8457;&#x9ad8;&#x4e8e;&#x5355;&#x7eaf;&#x80ba;&#x90e8;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7ec4;(<i>P</i>&#xff1c;0.05);&#x8840;&#x6db2;&#x964d;&#x9499;&#x7d20;&#x539f;(procalcitonin, PCT)&#x6c34;&#x5e73;&#x663e;&#x8457;&#x9ad8;&#x4e8e;&#x5355;&#x7eaf;&#x80ba;&#x90e8;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7ec4;(<i>P</i>=0.004), &#x8840;&#x7ea2;&#x7ec6;&#x80de;&#x8ba1;&#x6570;&#x3001;&#x8840;&#x7ea2;&#x86cb;&#x767d;&#x6c34;&#x5e73;&#x663e;&#x8457;&#x4f4e;&#x4e8e;&#x5355;&#x7eaf;&#x80ba;&#x90e8;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7ec4;(<i>P</i>&#xff1c;0.001);&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;&#x83cc;&#x682a;&#x4e2d;ST11&#x578b;&#x5360;&#x6bd4;&#x53ca;<i>iroB</i>&#x3001;<i>ybtA</i>&#x3001;<i>irp1</i>&#x3001;<i>fyuA</i>&#x6bd2;&#x529b;&#x57fa;&#x56e0;&#x68c0;&#x51fa;&#x7387;&#x5747;&#x663e;&#x8457;&#x9ad8;&#x4e8e;&#x5355;&#x7eaf;&#x80ba;&#x90e8;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7ec4;(<i>P</i>&#xff1c;0.05)&#x3002;&#x6839;&#x636e;&#x662f;&#x5426;&#x51fa;&#x73b0;30 d&#x5185;&#x6b7b;&#x4ea1;&#x5c06;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7ec4;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x8fdb;&#x4e00;&#x6b65;&#x5206;&#x4e3a;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x751f;&#x5b58;&#x7ec4;(<i>n</i>=21)&#x548c;&#x6b7b;&#x4ea1;&#x7ec4;(<i>n</i>=14), &#x591a;&#x56e0;&#x7d20;&#x5206;&#x6790;&#x8868;&#x660e;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x6027;&#x4f11;&#x514b;&#x662f;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;30 d&#x5185;&#x6b7b;&#x4ea1;&#x7684;&#x72ec;&#x7acb;&#x5371;&#x9669;&#x56e0;&#x7d20;(<i>P</i>=0.045, <i>OR</i>=38.510)&#x3002;</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="&#x7ed3;&#x8bba;">&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7684;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x591a;&#x89c1;&#x4e8e;&#x9ad8;&#x9f84;&#x3001;&#x5973;&#x6027;, &#x591a;&#x6709;&#x57fa;&#x7840;&#x75be;&#x75c5;&#x53f2;&#x3001;&#x4fb5;&#x5165;&#x6027;&#x64cd;&#x4f5c;&#x53f2;&#x53ca;90 d&#x5185;&#x6297;&#x83cc;&#x836f;&#x7269;&#x66b4;&#x9732;&#x53f2;, &#x4e14;&#x5177;&#x6709;&#x66f4;&#x4f4e;&#x7684;&#x7ea2;&#x7ec6;&#x80de;&#x8ba1;&#x6570;&#x3001;&#x8840;&#x7ea2;&#x86cb;&#x767d;&#x6c34;&#x5e73;&#x53ca;&#x66f4;&#x9ad8;&#x7684;PCT&#x6c34;&#x5e73;, &#x6613;&#x51fa;&#x73b0;&#x80f8;&#x8154;&#x79ef;&#x6db2;&#x3001;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x6027;&#x4f11;&#x514b;; &#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x6027;&#x4f11;&#x514b;&#x662f;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x60a3;&#x8005;30 d&#x5185;&#x6b7b;&#x4ea1;&#x7684;&#x72ec;&#x7acb;&#x5371;&#x9669;&#x56e0;&#x7d20;; &#x81f4;&#x591a;&#x90e8;&#x4f4d;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x7684;&#x83cc;&#x682a;&#x4e2d;&#x4ee5;ST11&#x578b;&#x4e3a;&#x4e3b;, <i>iroB</i>&#x3001;<i>ybtA</i>&#x3001;<i>irp1</i>&#x3001;<i>fyuA</i>&#x57fa;&#x56e0;&#x643a;&#x5e26;&#x7387;&#x66f4;&#x9ad8;&#x3002;</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial genes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hospital-acquired pneumonia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Klebsiella pneumoniae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multi-site infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>&#x5229;&#x76ca;&#x51b2;&#x7a81;</b>&#xa0;&#xa0;&#x6240;&#x6709;&#x4f5c;&#x8005;&#x5747;&#x58f0;&#x660e;&#x4e0d;&#x5b58;&#x5728;&#x5229;&#x76ca;&#x51b2;&#x7a81;&#x3002;</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41633605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12872307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19723/j.issn.1671-167X.2026.01.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wyres KL, Lam MMC, Holt KE. Population genomics of Klebsiella pneumoniae. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2020;18(6):344&#x2013;359. doi: 10.1038/s41579-019-0315-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-019-0315-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32055025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x9648; &#x5f66;&#x6b23;, &#x5f90; &#x71d5;&#x840d;, &#x6731; &#x8fce;&#x94a2;, et al. &#x8010;&#x591a;&#x9ecf;&#x83cc;&#x7d20;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;&#x7684;&#x8bca;&#x6cbb;&#x8fdb;&#x5c55;. &#x4e2d;&#x534e;&#x7ed3;&#x6838;&#x548c;&#x547c;&#x5438;&#x6742;&#x5fd7;. 2023;46(8):813&#x2013;818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x674e; &#x661f;&#x5b87;, &#x7533; &#x5ddd;, &#x738b; &#x4e9a;&#x4e1c;, et al. &#x9ad8;&#x6bd2;&#x529b;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;&#x809d;&#x8113;&#x80bf;&#x7684;&#x8bca;&#x6cbb;&#x8fdb;&#x5c55;. &#x4e2d;&#x534e;&#x4f20;&#x67d3;&#x75c5;&#x6742;&#x5fd7;. 2021;39(2):116&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matono T, Morita M, Nakao N, et al. Genomic insights into virulence factors affecting tissue-invasive Klebsiella pneumoniae infection. Ann Clin Microbiol Antimicrob. 2022;21(1):2. doi: 10.1186/s12941-022-00494-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12941-022-00494-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8817621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu KL, Sun HY, Fang CT. Liver abscess and metastatic endophthalmitis secondary to Klebsiella pneumoniae K1. Am J Gastroenterol. 2017;112(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28050045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon JH, Kim YJ, Jun YH, et al. Liver abscess due to Klebsiella pneumoniae: Risk factors for metastatic infection. Scand J Infect Dis. 2014;46(1):21&#x2013;26. doi: 10.3109/00365548.2013.851414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00365548.2013.851414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24228822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SJ, Chu ST, Lee KS, et al. Metastatic endophthalmitis and thyroid abscess complicating Klebsiella pneumoniae liver abscess. Clin Mol Hepatol. 2018;24(1):88&#x2013;91. doi: 10.3350/cmh.2016.0066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3350/cmh.2016.0066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5875196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28656747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x4e2d;&#x534e;&#x533b;&#x5b66;&#x4f1a;&#x547c;&#x5438;&#x75c5;&#x5b66;&#x5206;&#x4f1a;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x5b66;&#x7ec4; &#x4e2d;&#x56fd;&#x6210;&#x4eba;&#x533b;&#x9662;&#x83b7;&#x5f97;&#x6027;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x4e0e;&#x547c;&#x5438;&#x673a;&#x76f8;&#x5173;&#x6027;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x8bca;&#x65ad;&#x548c;&#x6cbb;&#x7597;&#x6307;&#x5357;(2018&#x5e74;&#x7248;) &#x4e2d;&#x534e;&#x7ed3;&#x6838;&#x548c;&#x547c;&#x5438;&#x6742;&#x5fd7;. 2018;41(4):255&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Li D, Zhou H, et al. Bacteremia and other body site infection caused by hypervirulent and classic Klebsiella pneumoniae. Microb Pathog. 2017;104:254&#x2013;262. doi: 10.1016/j.micpath.2017.01.049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.micpath.2017.01.049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28132768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x9ea6; &#x4e1c;&#x5a9a;, &#x949f; &#x5609;&#x57ce;, &#x8c2d; &#x4fca;&#x9752;. 1 852&#x682a;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;&#x7684;&#x4e34;&#x5e8a;&#x5206;&#x5e03;&#x548c;&#x8010;&#x836f;&#x53ca;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x5f71;&#x54cd;&#x56e0;&#x7d20;&#x7814;&#x7a76;. &#x56fd;&#x9645;&#x533b;&#x836f;&#x536b;&#x751f;&#x5bfc;&#x62a5;. 2023;29(15):2110&#x2013;2116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x5218; &#x79c0;&#x51e4;, &#x8096; &#x5fd7;&#x519b;, &#x5510; &#x7fa4;&#x529b;, et al. &#x8001;&#x5e74;&#x4f4f;&#x9662;&#x60a3;&#x8005;&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x80ba;&#x708e;&#x514b;&#x96f7;&#x4f2f;&#x83cc;&#x7684;&#x4e34;&#x5e8a;&#x7279;&#x70b9;&#x53ca;&#x8010;&#x836f;&#x6027;&#x5206;&#x6790;. &#x8001;&#x5e74;&#x533b;&#x5b66;&#x4e0e;&#x4fdd;&#x5065;. 2023;29(1):43&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SS, Chen YS, Tsai HC, et al. Predictors of septic metastatic infection and mortality among patients with Klebsiella pneumoniae liver abscess. Clin Infect Dis. 2008;47(5):642&#x2013;650. doi: 10.1086/590932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/590932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18643760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JC, Siu LK, Fung CP, et al. Impaired phagocytosis of capsular serotypes K1 or K2 Klebsiella pneumoniae in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients with poor glycemic control. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91(8):3084&#x2013;3087. doi: 10.1210/jc.2005-2749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2005-2749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16720670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x9a6c; &#x6d77;&#x8273;, &#x5218; &#x5b66;&#x6587;, &#x9a6c; &#x6587;&#x4e1c;, et al. &#x8001;&#x5e74;&#x60a3;&#x8005;CRKP&#x4e0e;CSKP&#x611f;&#x67d3;&#x4e34;&#x5e8a;&#x7279;&#x70b9;&#x4ee5;&#x53ca;&#x6bd2;&#x529b;&#x76f8;&#x5173;&#x57fa;&#x56e0;&#x5206;&#x5e03;&#x5dee;&#x5f02;. &#x4f20;&#x67d3;&#x75c5;&#x4fe1;&#x606f;. 2023;36(4):325&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>