<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41678817</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2047-2986</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of global health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Glob Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Training in lung ultrasound for the diagnosis of lower respiratory tract infections in children under five years of age in rural healthcare facilities in Guatemala.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>04046</StartPage><MedlinePgn>04046</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7189/jogh.16.04046</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Lower respiratory tract infections (LRTI) in children under five years of age remain a leading cause of mortality, especially in low- and middle-income countries (LMIC). Although many of these deaths are preventable, accurate diagnosis of bacterial pneumonia is essential to ensure appropriate treatment and to reduce unnecessary antibiotic use. Imaging technologies are essential for improving the specificity of diagnoses; however, chest x-rays are often unavailable in rural LMIC settings. In this context, point-of-care lung ultrasound (POCLUS) offers a promising alternative, but the limited training remains a significant barrier to its widespread adoption and long-term sustainability. This study proposes and evaluates a training methodology to address this challenge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We conducted a pre-post observational study without a control group across 10 rural health districts in Alta Verapaz, Guatemala. We divided the training programme into four progressive phases: training in technical skills and basic image acquisition (phase 0); assessment of image acquisition skills (phase 1); evaluation of the ability to identify pathological findings (phase 2); and training in a diagnostic algorithm and evaluation in the clinical context (phase 3). In each phase, two specialists independently evaluated images, and a third resolved disagreements. We combined in-person and remote training activities and implemented them between April 2021 and December 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 23 healthcare professionals (six physicians, 15 nurses, and two nursing assistants) participated in the training. Of these, 19 successfully completed phase 1, 18 completed phase 2, and 13 completed phase 3. Eight participants discontinued the programme, primarily due to changes in professional roles or location.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The blended learning model proposed in this study enabled physician and non-physician healthcare providers to use POCLUS to diagnose LRTI in children under five years of age in a rural primary care setting in a low-income country.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the Journal of Global Health. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Rodr&#xed;guez</LastName><ForeName>Clara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics and Neonatology, Hospital Universitario del Tajo, Aranjuez, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Porras-L&#xf3;pez</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics and Neonatology, Hospital Universitario Fundaci&#xf3;n Alcorc&#xf3;n, Alcorc&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bueno-Campa&#xf1;a</LastName><ForeName>Mercedes</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics and Neonatology, Hospital Universitario Fundaci&#xf3;n Alcorc&#xf3;n, Alcorc&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IdiPAZ Research Institute, Translational Research Network for Paediatric Infectious Diseases (RITIP) Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Biomedical Research in Infectious Diseases (CIBERINFEC), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Montbel</LastName><ForeName>Fleur</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fundaci&#xf3;n EHAS, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lobos Medina</LastName><ForeName>Isabel Cristina</ForeName><Initials>IC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Asociaci&#xf3;n TulaSalud, ONG, Cob&#xe1;n, Guatemala.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Winter</LastName><ForeName>Ingris</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Asociaci&#xf3;n TulaSalud, ONG, Cob&#xe1;n, Guatemala.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prieto-Egido</LastName><ForeName>Ignacio</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fundaci&#xf3;n EHAS, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Signal Theory and Communications, Telematic Systems and Computing Department, Rey Juan Carlos University, Fuenlabrada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Scotland</Country><MedlineTA>J Glob Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101578780</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2047-2978</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006166" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Guatemala</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012141" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Tract Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019035" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rural Health Services</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019095" MajorTopicYN="N">Point-of-Care Systems</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Personnel</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Disclosure of interest: All the authors completed the ICMJE Disclosure of Interest Form (available upon request from the corresponding author) and disclose no relevant interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41678817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7189/jogh.16.04046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41678743</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-453X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of clinical oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a Family-centered Early Palliative Care Intervention on the Mental Health and Quality of Life in Patients With Advanced Cancer and Their Caregivers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/COC.0000000000001301</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study explored the effectiveness of family-centered early palliative care on emotional well-being and quality of life for Chinese advanced cancer (AC) and their caregivers (CGs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Involving 104 AC (including lung, breast, and colon) and CGs, a remote randomized controlled trial was undertaken. Patients and CGs randomly assigned in pairs to either an intervention group (IG) (n=52) or a control group (n=52). While both groups underwent 4 weeks of health education, the IG also received 4 weeks of early palliative care. Various scales, including the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale, Connor Davidson Resilience Scale, Benefit Discovery Rating Scale, Caregiver Positive Feelings Scale, Functional Evaluation of Cancer Therapy Scale, and Caregiver Quality of Life (QoL) Scale, were applied to assess anxiety, depression, resilience, benefit discovery, and QoL at baseline (T1), immediately after the intervention (T2), and one month following the intervention (T3) for patients and CGs, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At T2 and T3, the patients in the IG exhibited significantly higher resilience, benefit discovery, QoL, and lower anxiety and depression compared to the control group (P&lt;0.01). Analysis using a linear mixed model revealed a substantial interaction among group, time, and role regarding anxiety, depression, and resilience (P&lt;0.01), highlighting distinct differences in resilience and improvements in anxiety and depression between patients and CGs (P&lt;0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study demonstrated that family-centered early palliative care interventions effectively enhanced the mental well-being and QoL for AC and CGs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bu</LastName><ForeName>Congming</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiotherapy Department, Xuzhou Medical University Affiliated Hospital, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Xuzhou Medical University Affiliated Hospital, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Xuzhou Medical University Affiliated Hospital, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiotherapy Department, Xuzhou Medical University Affiliated Hospital, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Dianjiao</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiotherapy Department, Xuzhou Medical University Affiliated Hospital, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiotherapy Department, Xuzhou Medical University Affiliated Hospital, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 81972845</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2021SJA1091</GrantID><Agency>the General Project of Philosophy and Social Science Research in Jiangsu Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2022ZH05</GrantID><Agency>the Faculty Research Project of Affiliated Hospital of Xuzhou Medical University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8207754</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-3732</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">advanced cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caregiver</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">early palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41678743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/COC.0000000000001301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000421-990000000-00380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jokhadze N, Das A, Dizon DS. Global cancer statistics: a healthy population relies on population health. CA Cancer J Clin. 2024;74:224&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferlay J, Ervik M, Lam F. Global Cancer Observatory: Cancer Today (Version 10). International Agency for Research on Cancer; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Laversanne M, Sung H, et al. Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2024;74:229&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broeckaert B, Nu&#xf1;ez OJ. Sedation in palliative care. Facts and concepts. Have HT, Clark D. The Ethics of Palliative Care European Perspectives. Buckingham: Open University Press; 2002:166&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H, Ran X, An L, et al. Disparities in stage at diagnosis for five common cancers in China: a multicentre, hospital-based, observational study. Lancet Public health. 2021;6:e877&#x2013;e887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajwah S, Oluyase AO, Yi D, et al. The effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of hospital-based specialist palliative care for adults with advanced illness and their caregivers. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;9:Cd012780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinha-Costa B, Reis-Pina P. Home hospitalization in palliative care for advanced cancer and dementia: a systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2025;69:289&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthys O, De Vleminck A, Dierickx S, et al. Effectiveness of a nurse-delivered (FOCUS+) and a web-based (iFOCUS) psychoeducational intervention for people with advanced cancer and their family caregivers (DIAdIC): study protocol for an international randomized controlled trial. BMC Palliat Care. 2021;20:193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito E, Tadaka E. Effectiveness of the Online Daily Diary (ONDIARY) program on family caregivers of advanced cancer patients: a home-based palliative care trial. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2022;46:101508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrell BR, Kravitz K. Cancer care: supporting underserved and financially burdened family caregivers. J Adv Pract Oncol. 2017;8:494&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ate&#x15f; G, Ebenau AF, Busa C, et al. Never at ease&#x201d; - family carers within integrated palliative care: a multinational, mixed method study. BMC Palliat Care. 2018;17:39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi M, Irajpour A, Taleghani F. Caregivers needing care: the unmet needs of the family caregivers of end-of-life cancer patients. Support Care Cancer. 2018;26:759&#x2013;766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Heymann A, Finsted E, Guldin MB, et al. Effects of home-based specialized palliative care and dyadic psychological intervention on caregiver burden: results from a randomized controlled trial. Acta Oncol. 2023;62:803&#x2013;807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Given B, Sherwood PR. Family care for the older person with cancer. Semin Oncol Nurs. 2006;22:43&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingley CE, Clayton M, Lai D, et al. Caregiver activation and home hospice nurse communication in advanced cancer care. Cancer Nurs. 2017;40:E38&#x2013;e50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakitas M, Lyons KD, Hegel MT, et al. Effects of a palliative care intervention on clinical outcomes in patients with advanced cancer: the Project ENABLE II randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2009;302:741&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dionne-Odom JN, Azuero A, Lyons KD, et al. Family caregiver depressive symptom and grief outcomes from the ENABLE III randomized controlled trial. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2016;52:378&#x2013;385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dionne-Odom JN, Azuero A, Lyons KD, et al. Benefits of early versus delayed palliative care to informal family caregivers of patients with advanced cancer: outcomes from the ENABLE III randomized controlled trial. J Clin Oncol. 2015;33:1446&#x2013;1452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corn BW, Feldman DB, Hull JG, et al. Dispositional hope as a potential outcome parameter among patients with advanced malignancy: an analysis of the ENABLE database. Cancer. 2022;128:401&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn S, Romo RD, Campbell CL. A systematic review of interventions for family caregivers who care for patients with advanced cancer at home. Patient Educ Couns. 2020;103:1518&#x2013;1530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo I, Krishnan A, Lee GL. Psychosocial interventions for advanced cancer patients: a systematic review. Psychooncology. 2019;28:1394&#x2013;1407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Liu T, Li F. Association between dyadic interventions and outcomes in cancer patients: a meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer. 2019;27:745&#x2013;761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang QL, Xu N, Huang ST, et al. WeChat-assisted preoperative health education reduces burden of care on parents of children with simple congenital heart disease: a prospective randomized controlled study. Braz J Cardiovasc Surg. 2021;36:663&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grapp M, Rosenberger F, Hemlein E, et al. Acceptability and feasibility of a guided biopsychosocial online intervention for cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. J Cancer Educ. 2022;37:102&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen BZJ, Wang L, Qian H. Effect of positive psychological guidance on the stigma and resilience of postoperative breast cancer patients. Shanxi Health Vocat Coll. 2020;30:91&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner EH. Chronic disease management: what will it take to improve care for chronic illness? Eff Clin Pract. 1998;1:2&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner EH, Austin BT, Davis C, et al. Improving chronic illness care: translating evidence into action. Health Aff (Millwood). 2001;20:64&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, Cailu BJ. The positive role of early palliative treatment in the treatment of lung cancer. Modern Oncol Med. 2019;27:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X, Zhang J. Factor analysis and psychometric evaluation of the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC) with Chinese people. Soc Behav Pers Int J. 2007;35:19&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Cui Y, Dong J, Wang X. Reliability and validity of the Chinese version of the Breast Cancer Perceived Benefit Assessment Scale. Chin J Nurs. 2015;50:1400&#x2013;1403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Li Z. Reliability and validity of the Chinese version of the Caregiver Positive Feeling Scale. Chin J Nurse. 2007;42:1068&#x2013;1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan C, Zhang D, Tang X. Introduction of fact-B Chinese version of quality of Life Measurement scale for breast cancer patients. China Cancer. 2002;11(6):318&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Gan X, Tang W, Li X. Application of QOL Scale for Family in quality of life evaluation of caregivers of patients with laryngeal cancer. Chin Gen Pract. 2009;12:726&#x2013;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang LLW, Wu Y, Ou D, et al. Effect of family adaptability on fear of recurrence of breast cancer patients: suppressing effect of psychological resilience. Mil Nurse. 2022;39:34&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Yin X, Zhou L, et al. Study on correlation between psychological resilience and coping styles of colorectal cancer patients' caregivers. Chin Nurs Res. 2014;28:288&#x2013;290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi Guo, Wang Jie TX, Yan Wan, et al. Analysis of the impact of early intervention palliative treatment on pain and anxiety in patients with hepatitis related liver cancer. J Kunming Med Univ. 2022;43:93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou H, Gu Z, Chen L, Jiang J. Application of family empowerment theory and life hope plan in perioperative functional exercise for gastric cancer patients. J Logist Univ CAPF. 2020;29(12):43&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang M, Su Z, He Y, et al. Physical symptoms and anxiety and depression in older patients with advanced cancer in China: a network analysis. BMC Geriatr. 2024;24:185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang S, Liu C, et al. Caregiver burden among family caregivers of patients with advanced cancer in a palliative context: a mixed-method study. J Clin Nurs. 2023;32(21-22):7751&#x2013;7764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao M, Na N, Xing N, et al. The impact of social support on benefit finding among patients with advanced lung cancer and their caregivers: based on actor-partner interdependence mediation model. Support Care Cancer. 2024;32:287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Tian X, Fan Y, et al. Psychometric properties of the Chinese version of the Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy - Palliative Care (FACIT-Pal) in patients with advanced cancer. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2024;67:e8&#x2013;e15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang GM, Dionne-Odom JN, Foo YH, et al. Adapting ENABLE for patients with advanced cancer and their family caregivers in Singapore: a qualitative formative evaluation. BMC Palliat Care. 2021;20:86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin F, Wei T, Zhao X, et al. Relationship between family resilience and dyadic coping in colorectal cancer patients and their spouses, based on the actor-partner interdependence model. Eur J Oncol Nurs. 2024;70:102622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;hle N, Drossaert CHC, Ten Klooster PM, et al. Web-based self-help intervention for partners of cancer patients based on acceptance and commitment therapy and self-compassion training: a randomized controlled trial with automated versus personal feedback. Support Care Cancer. 2021;29:5115&#x2013;5125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan SP, Lengacher CA, Rodriguez CS. Caregiver burden in caregivers of patients with advanced stage cancer: A concept analysis. Eur J Oncol Nurs. 2022;60:102152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigi S, Ganfi V, Borelli E, et al. Perceptions of death among patients with advanced cancer receiving early palliative care and their caregivers: results from a mixed-method analysis. Oncologist. 2023;28:e54&#x2013;e62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S, Douglas SL, Boveington-Molter B, et al. Aggressive end-of-life care and caregiver satisfaction for patients with advanced cancer. West J Nurs Res. 2024;46:19&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dionne-Odom JN, Azuero A, Taylor RA, et al. A lay navigator-led, early palliative care intervention for African American and rural family caregivers of individuals with advanced cancer (Project Cornerstone): results of a pilot randomized trial. Cancer. 2022;128:1321&#x2013;1330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ser&#xe7;e &#xd6;, G&#xfc;n&#xfc;&#x15f;en NP. The interaction between hematological cancer patients and family caregivers and their life changes: a qualitative dyadic approach. Cancer Nurs. 2021;44:E201&#x2013;e208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer KM, Turner KL, Siwik C, et al. Digital health and telehealth in cancer care: a scoping review of reviews. Lancet Digit Health. 2023;5:e316&#x2013;e327.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41678593</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-4571</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>138</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Circulation research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Circ Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Gut-Heart Axis in Myocardial Repair: Mechanisms, Cross-Organ Networks, and Therapeutic Opportunities.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e326978</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e326978</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326978</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiovascular diseases remain the leading global cause of morbidity and mortality, placing an escalating burden on health care systems and economies. While the gut microbiota is well recognized in atherosclerosis and cardiometabolic disorders, its influence on myocardial injury, repair, and regeneration is only beginning to emerge. Growing evidence reveals that gut microbes and their metabolites regulate myocardial health through intricate cross-organ networks, including the gut-brain-heart, gut-liver-heart, and gut-lung-heart axes. These findings suggest that the heart plays a key role in systemic host-microbe communication. Advances in metagenomics, metabolomics, and single-cell transcriptomics are now defining the molecular and cellular pathways by which microbial metabolites modulate immune tone, endothelial integrity, metabolic resilience, and cardiomyocyte survival. Studies in gnotobiotic models have established causal links between specific microbial taxa and myocardial outcomes while illuminating their roles in fibrosis resolution, angiogenesis, and regeneration. In this review, we synthesize current knowledge on the bidirectional gut-heart dialogue, emphasizing immunometabolic signaling, cross-organ integration, and regenerative mechanisms. We propose that coupling high-resolution multiomics with mechanistic modeling in controlled microbial systems will be pivotal for next-generation, microbiota-informed diagnostics, and therapeutics. We explore the emerging role of the gut-myocardium axis as both a driver of disease and as a promising modifiable therapeutic target and highlight a new frontier in precision cardiovascular medicine, with the potential to transform strategies for prevention, repair, and tissue regeneration.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hung-Chih</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2579-9723</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Academia Sinica, Taipei 115, Taiwan (H.-C.C., T.W.H.T., S.N.N.P., P.C.H.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Tony W H</ForeName><Initials>TWH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Academia Sinica, Taipei 115, Taiwan (H.-C.C., T.W.H.T., S.N.N.P., P.C.H.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasaribu</LastName><ForeName>Sumi Nani Novita</ForeName><Initials>SNN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-4363-5095</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Academia Sinica, Taipei 115, Taiwan (H.-C.C., T.W.H.T., S.N.N.P., P.C.H.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Deng-Chyang</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan (D.C.W.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan (D.C.W., P.C.H.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rey</LastName><ForeName>Federico E</ForeName><Initials>FE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0239-7780</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bacteriology and Department of Medical Microbiology and Immunology, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53706 (F.E.R.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Patrick C H</ForeName><Initials>PCH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8910-3596</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Academia Sinica, Taipei 115, Taiwan (H.-C.C., T.W.H.T., S.N.N.P., P.C.H.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Genomics and Proteomics and Institute of Clinical Medicine, National Taiwan University College of Medicine, Taipei 115, Taiwan (P.C.H.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan (D.C.W., P.C.H.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Circ Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0047103</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0009-7330</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069196" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Microbiome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009206" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myocardium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012038" MajorTopicYN="Y">Regeneration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006321" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastrointestinal microbiome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke volume</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41678593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>