<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41529159</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-751X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiopulmonary rehabilitation and prevention</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Efficacy of Pulmonary Rehabilitation in Patients With COPD, ILD, and Long COVID: PHYSICAL AND PSYCHOSOCIAL OUTCOMES.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000997</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The benefits of pulmonary rehabilitation (PR) for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) are well-established, but data on the relative efficacy of PR in patients with interstitial lung disease (ILD) and prolonged symptoms from coronavirus disease-2019 (Long COVID) remain limited. With the increasing prevalence of Long COVID, understanding the role of PR in this group is essential.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Records of patients enrolled in PR between September 1, 2020, to November 30, 2022, at an academic health system were analyzed. Patients were categorized into COPD, ILD, and Long COVID groups based on primary referral diagnosis. Outcome measures included 6-minute walk test distance, COPD Assessment Tool, Modified Medical Research Council Questionnaire, and psychosocial assessments. Mixed-linear modeling for repeated measures compared pre- and post-PR outcomes within and across groups by referral diagnosis while adjusting for baseline covariates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 316 patients enrolled in PR, 192 completed PR. Demographics were similar across groups, though patients with Long COVID were younger, more likely to be Hispanic, and have higher body mass index than patients referred for COPD. Significant improvements were observed in functional capacity, dyspnea, quality of life, depression, anxiety, and stress in all 3 groups following PR without significant between-group differences in PR outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This single-center analysis suggests that PR was associated with significantly improved physical and psychosocial well-being in patients with COPD, ILD, and Long COVID with comparable outcomes across all groups. Future randomized-controlled trials are needed to confirm the benefits of PR for patients with Long COVID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berkowitz</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Cardiac Fitness, Miriam Hospital, Cardiovascular Institute, Brown University Health (Dr Berkowitz, Mrs DeAngelis, and Dr Wu).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Warren Alpert Medical School, Providence, Rhode Island (Dr Berkowitz, Dr Lu, and Dr Wu).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Frederick</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Warren Alpert Medical School, Providence, Rhode Island (Dr Berkowitz, Dr Lu, and Dr Wu).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DeAngelis</LastName><ForeName>Julianne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Cardiac Fitness, Miriam Hospital, Cardiovascular Institute, Brown University Health (Dr Berkowitz, Mrs DeAngelis, and Dr Wu).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simmons</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, and Sleep Medicine, The Miriam Hospital Pulmonary Rehabilitation Program, Warren Alpert Medical School of Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island (Dr Simmons).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Chih</ForeName><Initials>WC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Cardiac Fitness, Miriam Hospital, Cardiovascular Institute, Brown University Health (Dr Berkowitz, Mrs DeAngelis, and Dr Wu).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Warren Alpert Medical School, Providence, Rhode Island (Dr Berkowitz, Dr Lu, and Dr Wu).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Brown University School of Public Health, Providence, Rhode Island (Dr Wu).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101291247</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-7501</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COPD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interstitial lung disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical functional performance pulmonary</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no funding and conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41529159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01273116-990000000-00248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adjaye-Gbewonyo D, Vahratian A, Perrine CG, Bertolli J. Long COVID in adults: United States, 2022. NCHS Data Briefs number 480. Updated September 26, 2023. 8. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/products/databriefs/db480.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F; Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent symptoms in patients after acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;324(6):603-605. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.12603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi OL, Hughes SE, Turner G, et al.; TLC Study Group. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J R Soc Med. 2021;114(9):428-442. doi: 10.1177/01410768211032850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01410768211032850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Sehgal K, Gupta A, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat Med. 2021;27(4):601-615. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01283-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong SJ. Long COVID or post-COVID-19 syndrome: putative pathophysiology, risk factors, and treatments. Infect Dis (London). 2021;53(10):737-754. doi: 10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23744235.2021.1924397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zawilska JB, Kuczy&#x144;ska K. Psychiatric and neurological complications of long COVID. J Psychiatr Res. 2022;156:349-360. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychires.2022.10.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2022.10.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nici L, ZuWallack RL. Pulmonary rehabilitation: definition, concept, and history. Clin Chest Med. 2014;35(2):279-282. doi: 10.1016/j.ccm.2014.02.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccm.2014.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agust&#xed; A, Celli BR, Criner GJ, et al. Global initiative for chronic obstructive lung disease 2023 report: GOLD executive summary. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;207(7):819-837. doi: 10.1164/rccm.202301-0106PP</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202301-0106PP</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy B, Casey D, Devane D, Murphy K, Murphy E, Lacasse Y. Pulmonary rehabilitation for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015(4). doi: 10.1002/14651858.cd003793.pub3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.cd003793.pub3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochester CL, Alison JA, Carlin B, et al. Pulmonary rehabilitation for adults with chronic respiratory disease: an official American Thoracic Society Clinical Practice Guideline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;208(4):e7-e26. doi: 10.1164/rccm.202306-1066ST</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202306-1066ST</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowman L, Hill CJ, May A, Holland AE. Pulmonary rehabilitation for interstitial lung disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;2(2):CD006322. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD006322.pub4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006322.pub4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland AE, Wadell K, Spruit MA. How to adapt the pulmonary rehabilitation programme to patients with chronic respiratory disease other than COPD. Eur Respir Rev. 2013;22(130):577-586. doi: 10.1183/09059180.00005613</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09059180.00005613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochester CL, Vogiatzis I, Holland AE, et al.; ATS/ERS Task Force on Policy in Pulmonary Rehabilitation. An official American Thoracic Society/European Respiratory Society Policy Statement: enhancing implementation, use, and delivery of pulmonary rehabilitation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2015;192(11):1373-1386. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201510-1966ST</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201510-1966ST</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu G, Collard HR, Egan JJ, et al.; ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT Committee on Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis. An official ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT statement: idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: evidence-based guidelines for diagnosis and management. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011;183(6):788-824. doi: 10.1164/rccm.2009-040GL</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.2009-040GL</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aljazeeri J, Almusally R, Wert Y, et al. Pulmonary rehabilitation for post-COVID-19. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2023;43(6):438-443. doi: 10.1097/HCR.0000000000000813</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugazzaro S, Contri A, Esseroukh O, et al.; Reggio Emilia COVID-19 Working Group. Rehabilitation interventions for post-acute COVID-19 syndrome: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(9):5185. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19095185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19095185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopp S, Moik F, Klok FA, et al. Outpatient pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with long COVID improves exercise capacity, functional status, dyspnea, fatigue, and quality of life. Respiration. 2022;101(6):593-601. doi: 10.1159/000522118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000522118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley ML, Wycoff AM, Mahoney K, Pierce JF, Simmons J, Adami A. Improvements in dyspnea following traditional pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with long COVID. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2024;44(2):141-143. doi: 10.1097/HCR.0000000000000862</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Association of Cardiovascular &amp; Pulmonary Rehabilitation (AACVPR). Guidelines for Cardiac Rehabilitation Programs. 6th ed. Human Kinetics; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polkey MI, Spruit MA, Edwards LD, et al.; Evaluation of COPD Longitudinally to Identify Predictive Surrogate Endpoints (ECLIPSE) Study Investigators. Six-minute-walk test in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: minimal clinically important difference for death or hospitalization. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2013;187(4):382-386. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201209-1596OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201209-1596OC</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW, Crouch R. Minimal clinically important difference for change in 6&#x2010;minute walk test distance of adults with pathology: a systematic review. J Eval Clin Pract. 2017;23(2):377-381. doi: 10.1111/jep.12629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.12629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta N, Pinto LM, Morogan A, Bourbeau J. The COPD assessment test: a systematic review. Eur Respir J. 2014;44(4):873-884. doi: 10.1183/09031936.00025214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00025214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon SSC, Canavan JL, Jones SE, et al. Minimum clinically important difference for the COPD assessment test: a prospective analysis. Lancet Respir Med. 2014;2(3):195-203. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(14)70001-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(14)70001-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bestall JC, Paul EA, Garrod R, Garnham R, Jones PW, Wedzicha JA. Usefulness of the Medical Research Council (MRC) dyspnoea scale as a measure of disability in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Thorax. 1999;54(7):581-586. doi: 10.1136/thx.54.7.581</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.54.7.581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajala K, Lehto JT, Sutinen E, Kautiainen H, Myll&#xe4;rniemi M, Saarto T. mMRC dyspnoea scale indicates impaired quality of life and increased pain in patients with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. ERJ Open Res. 2017;3(4):00084-02017. doi: 10.1183/23120541.00084-2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00084-2017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Seo JB, Lee SM, et al. Pharmacological treatment response according to the severity of symptoms in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. J Thorac Dis. 2015;7(10):1765-1773. doi: 10.3978/j.issn.2072-1439.2015.10.27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3978/j.issn.2072-1439.2015.10.27</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K. Enhancing the clinical utility of depression screening. CMAJ. 2012;184(3):281-282. doi: 10.1503/cmaj.112004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.112004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JBW. The PHQ-9. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16(9):606-613. doi: 10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toussaint A, H&#xfc;sing P, Gumz A, et al. Sensitivity to change and minimal clinically important difference of the 7-item Generalized Anxiety Disorder Questionnaire (GAD-7). J Affect Disord. 2020;265:395-401. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2020.01.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2020.01.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JBW, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(10):1092-1097. doi: 10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter S, Greenberg J, Funes CJ, Macklin EA, Vranceanu AM. Effects of a mind-body program on symptoms of depression and perceived stress among adults with neurofibromatosis type 2 who are deaf: a live-video randomized controlled trial. Complement Ther Med. 2021;56:102581. doi: 10.1016/j.ctim.2020.102581</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2020.102581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EH. Review of the psychometric evidence of the perceived stress scale. Asian Nurs Res. 2012;6(4):121-127. doi: 10.1016/j.anr.2012.08.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anr.2012.08.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaglio J, Conard M, Poston WS, et al. Testing the performance of the ENRICHD Social Support Instrument in cardiac patients. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2004;2:24. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-2-24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-2-24</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>StataCorp. Stata Statistical Software: Release 16. StataCorp, LLC; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowman LM, McDonald CF, Hill CJ, et al. The evidence of benefits of exercise training in interstitial lung disease: a randomised controlled trial. Thorax. 2017;72(7):610-619. doi: 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2016-208638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2016-208638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina-Guti&#xe9;rrez S, Torres-Costoso A, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez de Arenas-Arroyo S, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez R, Pozuelo-Carrascosa DP. Effectiveness of pulmonary rehabilitation in interstitial lung disease, including coronavirus diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102(10):1989-1997.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2021.03.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2021.03.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vainshelboim B, Oliveira J, Yehoshua L, et al. Exercise training-based pulmonary rehabilitation program is clinically beneficial for idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respiration. 2014;88(5):378-388. doi: 10.1159/000367899</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000367899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed I, Mustafaoglu R, Yeldan I, Yasaci Z, Erhan B. Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation approaches on dyspnea, exercise capacity, fatigue, lung functions, and quality of life in patients with COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;103(10):2051-2062. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2022.06.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2022.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besnier F, B&#xe9;rub&#xe9; B, Malo J, et al. Cardiopulmonary rehabilitation in long-COVID-19 patients with persistent breathlessness and fatigue: the COVID-Rehab Study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(7):4133. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19074133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19074133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang J, Li Y, Chen Y. Respiratory rehabilitation in elderly patients with COVID-19: a randomized controlled study. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39:101166. doi: 10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabit R, Griffiths TL, Watkins AJ, et al. Predictors of poor attendance at an outpatient pulmonary rehabilitation programme. Respir Med. 2008;102(6):819-824. doi: 10.1016/j.rmed.2008.01.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2008.01.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathews L, Brewer LC. A review of disparities in cardiac rehabilitation: EVIDENCE, DRIVERS, AND SOLUTIONS. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2021;41(6):375-382. doi: 10.1097/HCR.0000000000000659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41247873</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1528-1175</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Anesthesiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anesthesiology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Individualized Flow-controlled versus Pressure-controlled Ventilation in Cardiac Surgery: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ALN.0000000000005851</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patients undergoing on-pump cardiac surgery are at high risk for perioperative lung injury and a hyperinflammatory state associated with postoperative complications. The authors investigated the hypothesis that flow-controlled ventilation (FCV) reduces the inflammatory stimulus compared to conventional pressure-controlled ventilation (PCV) in this patient cohort. FCV has the unique feature of controlling airway flows during inspiration and expiration and the potential to reduce mechanical power of invasive ventilation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this single-center randomized controlled trial, 140 adult patients undergoing cardiac surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass were allocated 1:1 to FCV or PCV from August 10, 2020, to November 16, 2022. Participants received perioperatively either individualized FCV with a compliance-guided positive end-expiratory pressure (PEEP) and a compliance-guided driving pressure (&#x394;P) or PCV with a compliance-guided PEEP and &#x394;P for tidal volumes of 6 to 8&#x2009;ml/kg predicted body weight. Postoperative plasmatic interleukin 8 (IL-8) levels 6&#x2009;h after cardiopulmonary bypass were defined as the primary endpoint. Explorative secondary outcomes included incidences of postoperative pulmonary and extrapulmonary complications and hospital length of stay.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Median postoperative IL-8 levels did not differ significantly between FCV and PCV (FCV, 3.08 vs . PCV, 3.60; &#x3b2;, 0.08 pg/ml; 95% CI, -0.17 to 0.33; P = 0.573). &#x394;P values and tidal volumes were higher in the FCV group but FCV yielded lower respiratory rates and minute volumes required for normocapnia. As a result, the FCV approach reduced the perioperatively applied mechanical power by 55%. After FCV, incidences of single postoperative pulmonary complications ( e.g. , confirmed pneumonia, moderate and severe hypoxemia) and any postoperative extrapulmonary complication were lower and the hospital stay shorter.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">FCV did not reduce plasmatic IL-8 levels at the predefined timepoint 6&#x2009;h after cardiopulmonary bypass. However, the reduction of mechanical power during individualized FCV application and the findings of the explorative secondary study outcomes justify future trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc., on behalf of the American Society of Anesthesiologists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Becker</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurz</LastName><ForeName>Christian T</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany; Department of Cardiac Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, German Heart Centre at Charit&#xe9;, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schnitzler</LastName><ForeName>Romina</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geppert</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wichelhaus</LastName><ForeName>Lisa-Marie</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Denz</LastName><ForeName>Robin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Informatics, Biometry and Epidemiology, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poepping</LastName><ForeName>Jonas</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rembecki</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berres</LastName><ForeName>Dinah Maria</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strauch</LastName><ForeName>Justus T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bates</LastName><ForeName>Declan G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering, University of Warwick, Coventry, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erdoes</LastName><ForeName>Gabor</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Pain Medicine, Inselspital, University Hospital Bern, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timmesfeld</LastName><ForeName>Nina</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Informatics, Biometry and Epidemiology, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zahn</LastName><ForeName>Peter K</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, BG University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Anesthesiology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1300217</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0003-3022</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41247873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000005851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000542-990000000-00814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>den Hengst WA, Gielis JF, Lin JY, Van Schil PE, De Windt LJ, Moens AL: Lung ischemia-reperfusion injury: A molecular and clinical view on a complex pathophysiological process. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 2010; 299:H1283&#x2013;99. doi:10.1152/ajpheart.00251.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00251.2010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis Miranda D, Gommers D, Struijs A, et al.: Ventilation according to the open lung concept attenuates pulmonary inflammatory response in cardiac surgery. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg 2005; 28:889&#x2013;95. doi:10.1016/j.ejcts.2005.10.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejcts.2005.10.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zupancich E, Paparella D, Turani F, et al.: Mechanical ventilation affects inflammatory mediators in patients undergoing cardiopulmonary bypass for cardiac surgery: A randomized clinical trial. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg 2005; 130:378&#x2013;83. doi:10.1016/j.jtcvs.2004.11.061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtcvs.2004.11.061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagier D, Fischer F, Fornier W, et al.; PROVECS Study Group: Effect of open-lung vs conventional perioperative ventilation strategies on postoperative pulmonary complications after on-pump cardiac surgery: The PROVECS randomized clinical trial. Intensive Care Med 2019; 45:1401&#x2013;12. doi:10.1007/s00134-019-05741-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-019-05741-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes T, van Asseldonk D, Enk D: Minimisation of dissipated energy in the airways during mechanical ventilation by using constant inspiratory and expiratory flows - Flow-controlled ventilation (FCV). Med Hypotheses 2018; 121:167&#x2013;76. doi:10.1016/j.mehy.2018.09.038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2018.09.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spraider P, Martini J, Abram J, et al.: Individualized flow-controlled ventilation compared to best clinical practice pressure-controlled ventilation: A prospective randomized porcine study. Crit Care 2020; 24:662. doi:10.1186/s13054-020-03325-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-020-03325-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spraider P, Abram J, Martini J, et al.: Flow-controlled versus pressure-controlled ventilation in cardiac surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass - A single-center, prospective, randomized, controlled trial. J Clin Anesth 2023; 91:111279. doi:10.1016/j.jclinane.2023.111279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinane.2023.111279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Oosten JP, Francovich JE, Somhorst P, et al.: Flow-controlled ventilation decreases mechanical power in postoperative ICU patients. Intensive Care Med Exp 2024; 12:30. doi:10.1186/s40635-024-00616-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40635-024-00616-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattinoni L, Tonetti T, Cressoni M, et al.: Ventilator-related causes of lung injury: The mechanical power. Intensive Care Med 2016; 42:1567&#x2013;75. doi:10.1007/s00134-016-4505-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-016-4505-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiumello D, Gotti M, Guanziroli M, et al.: Bedside calculation of mechanical power during volume- and pressure-controlled mechanical ventilation. Crit Care 2020; 24:417. doi:10.1186/s13054-020-03116-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-020-03116-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santer P, Wachtendorf LJ, Suleiman A, et al.: Mechanical power during general anesthesia and postoperative respiratory failure: A multicenter retrospective cohort study. A nesthesiology 2022; 137:41&#x2013;54. doi:10.1097/ALN.0000000000004256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000004256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon S, Nam JS, Blank RS, et al.: Association of mechanical energy and power with postoperative pulmonary complications in lung resection surgery: A post hoc analysis of randomized clinical trial data. A nesthesiology 2024; 140:920&#x2013;34. doi:10.1097/ALN.0000000000004879</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000004879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Wedel D, Redaelli S, Suleiman A, et al.: Adjustments of ventilator parameters during operating room-to-ICU transition and 28-day mortality. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2024; 209:553&#x2013;62. doi:10.1164/rccm.202307-1168OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202307-1168OC</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urner M, J&#xfc;ni P, Hansen B, Wettstein MS, Ferguson ND, Fan E: Time-varying intensity of mechanical ventilation and mortality in patients with acute respiratory failure: A registry-based, prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med 2020; 8:905&#x2013;13. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30325-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30325-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker S, Schnitzler R, Rembecki M, et al.: Individualized flow-controlled versus conventional pressure-controlled ventilation in on-pump heart surgery (FLOWVENTIN HEARTSURG): Study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials 2023; 24:195. doi:10.1186/s13063-023-07201-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-023-07201-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubin JH, Colt JS, Camann D, et al.: Epidemiologic evaluation of measurement data in the presence of detection limits. Environ Health Perspect 2004; 112:1691&#x2013;6. doi:10.1289/ehp.7199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/ehp.7199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemmes SN, Gama de Abreu M, Pelosi P, Schultz MJ; PROVE Network Investigators for the Clinical Trial Network of the European Society of Anaesthesiology: High versus low positive end-expiratory pressure during general anaesthesia for open abdominal surgery (PROVHILO trial): A multicentre randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2014; 384:495&#x2013;503. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(14)60416-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(14)60416-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bluth T, Serpa Neto A, Schultz MJ, et al.; Writing Committee for the PROBESE Collaborative Group of the PROtective VEntilation Network (PROVEnet) for the Clinical Trial Network of the European Society of Anaesthesiology: Effect of intraoperative high positive end-expiratory pressure (PEEP) with recruitment maneuvers vs low PEEP on postoperative pulmonary complications in obese patients: A randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2019; 321:2292&#x2013;305. doi:10.1001/jama.2019.7505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2019.7505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrando C, Carrami&#xf1;ana A, Pi&#xf1;eiro P, et al.; iPROVE-OLV Research Network Group: Individualised, perioperative open-lung ventilation strategy during one-lung ventilation (iPROVE-OLV): A multicentre, randomised, controlled clinical trial. Lancet Respir Med 2024; 12:195&#x2013;206. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00346-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00346-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amato MB, Meade MO, Slutsky AS, et al.: Driving pressure and survival in the acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med 2015; 372:747&#x2013;55. doi:10.1056/NEJMsa1410639</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMsa1410639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neto AS, Hemmes SN, Barbas CS, et al.; PROVE Network Investigators: Association between driving pressure and development of postoperative pulmonary complications in patients undergoing mechanical ventilation for general anaesthesia: A meta-analysis of individual patient data. Lancet Respir Med 2016; 4:272&#x2013;80. doi:10.1016/S2213-2600(16)00057-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(16)00057-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enk D, Spraider P, Abram J, Barnes T: Pressure measurements in flow-controlled ventilation. Crit Care Med 2020; 48:e1359&#x2013;60. doi:10.1097/CCM.0000000000004561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000004561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turan A, Esa WAS, Rivas E, et al.; Ventilation-PEEP Trial Group: Tidal volume and positive end-expiratory pressure and postoperative hypoxemia during general anesthesia: A single-center multiple crossover factorial cluster trial. A nesthesiology 2022; 137:406&#x2013;17. doi:10.1097/ALN.0000000000004342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000004342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karalapillai D, Weinberg L, Peyton P, et al.: Effect of intraoperative low tidal volume vs conventional tidal volume on postoperative pulmonary complications in patients undergoing major surgery: A randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2020; 324:848&#x2013;58. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.12866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundar S, Novack V, Jervis K, et al.: Influence of low tidal volume ventilation on time to extubation in cardiac surgical patients. A nesthesiology 2011; 114:1102&#x2013;10. doi:10.1097/ALN.0b013e318215e254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0b013e318215e254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buiteman-Kruizinga LA, van Meenen DMP, Serpa Neto A, et al.; NEBULAE: Association of ventilation volumes, pressures and rates with the mechanical power of ventilation in patients without acute respiratory distress syndrome: Exploring the impact of rate reduction. Anaesthesia 2025; 80:533&#x2013;42. doi:10.1111/anae.16537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.16537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt J, Wenzel C, Spassov S, et al.: Flow-controlled ventilation attenuates lung injury in a porcine model of acute respiratory distress syndrome: A preclinical randomized controlled study. Crit Care Med 2020; 48:e241&#x2013;8. doi:10.1097/CCM.0000000000004209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000004209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spassov SG, Streicher L, Bohe E, et al.: Flow-controlled expiration reduces lung injury during assisted ventilation in pigs with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2025; 211:272&#x2013;6. doi:10.1164/rccm.202404-0869RL</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202404-0869RL</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busana M, Zinnato C, Romitti F, et al.: Energy dissipation during expiration and ventilator-induced lung injury: An experimental animal study. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2022; 133:1212&#x2013;9. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.00426.2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00426.2022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ClinicalTrials.gov: U.S. National Library of Medicine. Available at: https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT06703814 . Accessed July 1, 2025.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>